<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Datica Company Blog</title>
  <id>https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/</id>
  <subtitle>Thoughts from the team behind Healthcare's trusted cloud</subtitle>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/" type="text/html"/>
  <link rel="self" href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/feed.xml" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <author>
    <name>Datica Health, Inc.</name>
  </author>
  <icon>https://images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/32chySeS5qMcCWeAwEyCQM/cf6c8d516896bc66f0c67d142869360a/datica-icon-256.png?w=48</icon>
  <logo>https://images.contentful.com/189dvqdsjh46/4SwayIJ5AcCe4iCU820mQs/504b8e57eacc0d81032d01ace96bc622/datica_logo__black.png?w=150</logo>
  <updated>2020-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <entry>
    <title>Top 50 Health IT Conferences to Attend in 2020, Part 2</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/top-health-it-conferences-part-2"/>
    <id>https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/top-health-it-conferences-part-2</id>
    <published>2020-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dave Levin, MD</name>
    </author>
    <summary>To make it easier for you to plan your conference attendance schedule for 2020, we’ve compiled our picks for the 50 must-attend health IT conferences. These events are designed to connect healthcare professionals working in a variety of unique disciplines, touching on hot-button topics for...</summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/2qylsn7PJMEb1ALdtRx2pP/b72b8413e6cb75aa5bf244470a219e7a/clement-m-sNyFgVJ72is-unsplash.jpg?fit=crop&w=840&h=420&fm=jpg&q=40" width="420" alt="Top 50 Health IT Conferences to Attend in 2020, Part 2"><p><strong>Find Part 1 of our Top Health It Conferences list, <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/top-health-it-conferences/">here</a>.</strong></p>

<p>As global technology continues to evolve, so does the healthcare  industry’s appetite for heightened connectivity and interoperability,  which empower healthcare organizations to streamline patient care  delivery and provide more efficient, better-quality care. According to data compiled by <a href="https://dashboard.healthit.gov/quickstats/quickstats.php"><em>Health IT Dashboard</em></a>, 96 percent of all non-federal acute care hospitals possessed certified health IT in 2017. But widespread health IT adoption aside, facilities must not rest on their initial investments to see them through the next decade – or potentially even the next few years. In order to compete in this ever-evolving landscape, the healthcare industry must be willing to collaborate and take an active role in its IT implementation.</p>
<p>To support this mission, we’ve compiled a list of the 50 best health  IT conferences to attend in 2020. These events are designed to connect  healthcare professionals working in a variety of unique disciplines,  touching on hot-button topics for today’s healthcare organizations, from connectivity to interoperability, <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/designing-safe-and-effective-digital-health-applications/">digital health apps</a>, cybersecurity, the rise of blockchain (and its potential to impact the healthcare industry), <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/innovation/automating-healthcare-with-artificial-intelligence/">Artificial Intelligence</a>, and other health IT trends and innovations.</p>

<h2 id="rd-quarter-health-it-conferences">3rd Quarter Health IT Conferences</h2>

<h2 id="aha-leadership-summithttpswwwahaorgeducation-and-eventsleadership-summit">33. <a href="https://www.aha.org/education-and-events/leadership-summit">AHA Leadership Summit</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/ahahospitals">@ahahospitals</a></p>

<p>July 19 – 21, 2020 
<strong>San Diego, CA</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/163TDGBd4BRbnc6BMpn1UO/2eb606359f9d13e4352df278b0caa5bd/33.__AHA_Leadership_Summit_.png" alt="33. AHA Leadership Summit" /></p>

<p>The 2020 AHA Leadership Summit, July 19-21, promotes a revolution in thinking among health care leaders that reflects a steady wave of disruptive strategies and unexpected solutions for future success. Focusing on transformational strategies and approaches for achieving financial sustainability while delivering greater value through operational excellence, creative partnerships, and redefined delivery models, the Summit convenes the field’s leading thinkers and doers – as well as those innovators who are shifting traditional business models.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong> Contact for attendance cost</p>

<h2 id="shsmd-connections-2020httpsannualshsmdorgindexcfm">34. <a href="https://annual.shsmd.org/index.cfm">SHSMD Connections 2020</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/shsmdaha">@shsmdaha</a></p>

<p>September 13 – 16, 2020<br />
<strong>Chicago, IL</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/5WPNOZ7ndQUrWm71RRnWqM/ba23265d2b56ac5d4e9923ff0f58213c/34.__SHSMD_Connections_2020.png" alt="34. SHSMD Connections 2020" /></p>

<p>The Society for Healthcare Strategy and Market Development of the American Hospital Association is hosting SHSMD Connections 2020, an annual event that will be held in the early fall at in Chicago. The conference acts as a gathering ground for some of the best and brightest thought leaders working in HIT and patient experience today. Organizers are currently working on this year’s schedule. Check the conference website for more information on the agenda, as well as the venue.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Member: $995</li>
  <li>Non-member: $1,195</li>
  <li>Groups of 8 or more: 10% off</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="chief-nursing-officer-summit-2020httpsopalgroupnetconferencechief-nursing-officer-summit-2020">35. <a href="https://opalgroup.net/conference/chief-nursing-officer-summit-2020/">Chief Nursing Officer Summit 2020</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/opal_group">@opal_group</a></p>

<p>September 14, 2020
<strong>Orlando, FL</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/6m98xUDugpPA82Cu7zhsQ1/5ab52ec36fb0a9f4c2f1c107ef9896d2/35.__Chief_Nursing_Officer_Summit_2020_.png" alt="35. Chief Nursing Officer Summit 2020" /></p>

<p>Nursing leaders have consistently gone through a significant amount of challenges due to a variety of influences both internal and external. Through these challenges, nursing leaders are tasked with providing quality care, reducing costs while improving patient experiences– a challenge that requires strong leaders at the helm of their organizations. Nursing administrators know this cannot be done alone, but with partners and peers to develop novel approaches and strategies to overcome these challenges.</p>

<p>The Chief Nursing Officer Summit brings together senior nursing executives from hospitals, healthcare systems, long-term health facilities and outpatient clinics to collaborate and strategize ideas with other administrators from around the country. The peer-driven content allows thought leaders to share best practices, have open and candid conversations while exploring novel approaches to work in a more efficient and productive manner.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong> Contact for attendance cost</p>

<h2 id="himss-health-20httpswwwh2fallconcomsanta-clara2019utmsourcehealth2conutmmediumpartnerutmcampaignregutmcontentnavigation">36. <a href="https://www.h2fallcon.com/santa-clara/2019?utm_source=health2con&amp;utm_medium=partner&amp;utm_campaign=reg&amp;utm_content=navigation">HIMSS Health 2.0</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/health2con">@health2con</a></p>

<p>September 16-18, 2020
<strong>San Francisco, CA</strong></p>

<p>HiMSS Health 2.0 Con showcases cutting-edge innovation that’s transforming the healthcare system. Health 2.0 brings together the best minds, compelling panels, discussions and product demonstrations that you won’t find anywhere else.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong> <a href="https://www.h2fallcon.com/santa-clara/2019/get-updates">Sign up</a> to receive updates as registration information is announced.</p>

<h2 id="expohealthhttpswwwexpohealth">37. <a href="https://www.expo.health">EXPO.health</a></h2>

<p>September 29 – October 1, 2020 
<strong>Las Vegas, NV</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/4GnK9ciagmFBc6RqQvDdj2/43f3645f14bddd92f511bc9474230a76/37.__EXPO.health.png" alt="37. EXPO.health" /></p>

<p>EXPO.health, is a healthcare IT conference that brings a down-to-earth approach to the seminar world, offering “practical innovation” to the mass health market. The three-day event offers educational and collaborative opportunities on a range of topics, including healthcare IT analytics, healthcare security, patient engagement, EHR optimization, and more. Each day is filled with conference programs and focus groups, followed by networking events in the evening hours. EXPO.health is organized by Healthcare Scene, a community of leading healthcare IT professionals.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Healthcare Provider, Non-profit and Government Pricing: Super Early Bird: $295 (Ends 4/17/20); Early Bird: $445 (Ends 6/19/20), Regular: $595 (Ends 8/28/20)</li>
  <li>Health IT Vendor Pricing: Super Early Bird: $695 (Ends 4/17/20), Early Bird: $995 (Ends 6/19/20), Regular: $1195 (Ends 8/28/20)</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="advamed-the-medtech-conferencehttpsthemedtechconferencecom">38. <a href="https://themedtechconference.com">AdvaMed: The MedTech Conference</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/avamedupdate">@avamedupdate</a></p>

<p>October 5 – 7, 2020 
<strong>Toronto, ON</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/6ALYBZpk2pv4M3G25etVq9/9528f1a85967530b4cf5b6e3373c1327/38.__AdvaMed-_The_MedTech_Conference_.png" alt="38. AdvaMed- The MedTech Conference" /></p>

<p>Featuring world‑class plenary speakers, cross‑cutting educational programming, valuable networking and business development opportunities, The MedTech Conference is a must‑attend event for the industry’s prominent and most promising companies.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong> Contact for attendance cost</p>

<h2 id="the-medtech-conferencehttpsthemedtechconferencecom">39. <a href="https://themedtechconference.com">The MedTech Conference</a></h2>

<p>October 5 – 7, 2020<br />
<strong>Toronto, ON</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/4BmPuejYKH8SdPcNiPZzRx/3e95ff34dd9699a2a0b68d292c70c6d5/39._The_MedTech_Conference__.png" alt="39. The MedTech Conference" /></p>

<p>Featuring world‑class plenary speakers, cross‑cutting educational programming, valuable networking and business development opportunities, The MedTech Conference is a must‑attend event for the industry’s prominent and most promising companies.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong> Contact for attendance cost</p>

<h2 id="hlthhttpshlthcom">40. <a href="https://hlth.com">HLTH</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/HLTHEVENT">@HLTHEVENT</a></p>

<p>October 11 – 14, 2020
<strong>Las Vegas, NV</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/7sQujfn6egS2ixEwYvOeGx/436c6970b0f54e577ee2168b8eefe697/40.__HLTH_.png" alt="40. HLTH" /></p>

<p>HLTH (pronounced “health”) is a one-of-a-kind ecosystem event for the health industry, and we’re on a mission to bring together 7,000+ senior leaders to solve the most pressing problems facing healthcare today and actualize the most promising opportunities to improve health.</p>

<p>We bring together senior leaders from across payers, providers, employers, investors, fast-growing startups, pharma, policymakers and innovation centers to ask one question: how do we create the future of health?</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong> Contact for attendance cost</p>

<h2 id="beckers-6th-annual-health-it--revenue-cycle-conferencehttpswwwbeckershospitalreviewcomhealth-it-revenue-cycle-conference">41. <a href="https://www.beckershospitalreview.com/health-it-revenue-cycle-conference/">Becker’s 6th Annual Health IT + Revenue Cycle Conference</a></h2>

<p>October 13-16, 2020
<strong>Chicago, IL</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/11DlOnXt8XMzjlz35q2LJo/320ed6d020bca36222d24fb5e7d43cf2/41._Becker_s_6th_Annual_Health_IT___Revenue_Cycle_Conference.png" alt="41. Becker's 6th Annual Health IT + Revenue Cycle Conference" /></p>

<p>Join the brightest minds in Health IT and the Revenue Cycle - great networking - learn more in 48 hours than you can all year! This exclusive conference brings together hospital and health system CIO and IT executives to discuss the Role of the CIO, Social Media, Data Analytics, Mobile Health, EMR Issues and Health IT Issues.
Come listen and network with Hospital Executives as our speakers discuss their biggest concerns and how they are addressing them.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>First attendee: $900</li>
  <li>Second attendee: $850</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="ahima-convention-and-exhibithttpwwwahimaorgconference">42. <a href="http://www.ahima.org/conference">AHIMA Convention and Exhibit</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/AHIMAResources">@AHIMAResources</a></p>

<p>October 14-17, 2020
<strong>Atlanta, GA</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/4WQKZsgmitC3mtr64pXY7z/4bbe9308fefa1f53bbd7391d79022d98/42.__AHIMA_Convention_and_Exhibit_.png" alt="42. AHIMA Convention and Exhibit" /></p>

<p>The 2020 AHIMA Convention and Exhibit is an event that brings together thousands working in HIT and HIM. While an agenda has yet to be made available for this conference, organizers have announced that the five-day event will be filled with plenty of educational and collaborative opportunities that will prove helpful to individuals working in a variety of sectors.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong> Contact for attendance cost</p>

<h2 id="th-quarter-healthcare-it-conferences">4th Quarter Healthcare IT Conferences</h2>

<h2 id="digital-healthcare-innovation-summit-dhishttpsdhisnet">43. <a href="https://dhis.net">Digital Healthcare Innovation Summit (DHIS)</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/dhisummit">@dhisummit</a></p>

<p>Dates TBA 
<strong>Location TBA</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/1gIJAF3HXV04U0UlyFJB3r/d14fce73094df8e2cc7fd4d78ca3f0cb/43.__Digital_Healthcare_Innovation_Summit__DHIS__.png" alt="43. Digital Healthcare Innovation Summit (DHIS)" /></p>

<p>DHIS, the Digital Healthcare Information Summit, gathers together the world’s most important innovators, investors, payers, providers, and policymakers currently shaping the digital health spectrum. 2018 speakers included a healthy range of care providers, venture capitalists, CEOs, and healthcare consultants.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong> Contact for attendance cost</p>

<h2 id="connected-health-conferencehttpswwwconnectedhealthconforgboston2019">44. <a href="https://www.connectedhealthconf.org/boston/2019">Connected Health Conference</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/pchalliance">@pchalliance</a></p>

<p>October 16-18, 2019<br />
<strong>Boston, MA</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/6yKuRbbJHqhXZNkUyX8pVM/038528f652437980cdac29a57e89354c/44.__Connected_Health_Conference_.png" alt="44. Connected Health Conference" /></p>

<p>The Connected Health Conference is an event that is famous for “balancing technology and the human element.” This conference attracts a range of professionals and elite sponsors representing powerful global organizations, like the National Institute of Health, Intel, Partners Healthcare, and HP. Attendees can expect to mingle with 3,000+ of their peers hailing from 50+ countries. Connected Health Conference will be held in Boston. Check the event’s website for venue details as they are made available.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong> Contact for attendance cost</p>

<h2 id="chime-fall-cio-forumhttpschimecentralorgforum2019-chime-fall-cio-forum">45. <a href="https://chimecentral.org/forum/2019-chime-fall-cio-forum/">CHIME Fall CIO Forum</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/CIOCHIME">@CIOCHIME</a></p>

<p>Dates TBA 
<strong>Location TBA</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/3Oa2RSX1U5bnRt9A736OeD/2c531576dcf2bde175fa72f1630299b9/45.__CHIME_Fall_CIO_Forum.png" alt="45. CHIME Fall CIO Forum" /></p>

<p>The CHIME Fall CIO Forum is a four-day event that is organized by the College of Healthcare Information Management Executives. It will be held at the JW Marriott Phoenix Desert Ridge Resort and Spa in the fall. Organizers are currently hard at work developing an agenda. Check the event’s website for more details as they emerge.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong> Contact for attendance cost</p>

<h2 id="exponential-medicinehttpsexponentialsingularityuorgmedicine">46. <a href="https://exponential.singularityu.org/medicine/">Exponential Medicine</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/ExponentialMed">@ExponentialMed</a></p>

<p>Dates TBA 
<strong>Location TBA</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/5tJFiK3vXIgy62gexKDVMn/2652a0a5100003aabfd97f296beaa1ee/46.__Exponential_Medicine.png" alt="46. Exponential Medicine" /></p>

<p>Exponential Medicine, an event hosted by Singularity University, is a four-day conference that “gathers world-class faculty, innovators and organizations from across the biomedical and technology spectrum to explore and leverage the convergence of fast-moving technologies in the reinvention of health and medicine.” To get a taste of the Exponential experience, be sure to watch its 2018 event videos. Exponential Medicine will be held at the Hotel del Coronado in San Diego.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong> Contact for attendance cost</p>

<h2 id="forbes-healthcare-summithttpswwwforbescomforbes-liveevent2019-healthcare-summit">47. <a href="https://www.forbes.com/forbes-live/event/2019-healthcare-summit/">Forbes Healthcare Summit</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/forbes">@forbes</a></p>

<p>Dates TBA 
<strong>Location TBA</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/6ME1bYJtVNr5XMoLxzTXmY/498b7e5e56fd89203f12e83619b69111/47.__Forbes_Healthcare_Summit_.png" alt="47. Forbes Healthcare Summit" /></p>

<p>Forbes Live hosts the Forbes Healthcare Summit, a gathering that is billed as being the “world’s most influential healthcare event.” Though details have yet to be made available about the 2020 event, we do know that last year’s conference focused heavily on the ever-evolving world of HIT, and the ways in which heightened connectivity makes it stronger.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Standard: $1,950</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="rsna-annual-meetinghttpswwwrsnaorgannual-meeting">48.<a href="https://www.rsna.org/annual-meeting">RSNA Annual Meeting</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/rsna">@rsna</a></p>

<p>November 29 – December 2, 2020
<strong>Chicago, IL</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/2B40iMryNS3thYc1VJA1yd/6d880843b89c2176793625956ee0c75f/48.__RSNA_Annual_Meeting_.png" alt="48. RSNA Annual Meeting" /></p>

<p>The 106th Scientific Assembly and Annual Meeting of the Radiological Society of North America, RSNA 2020 will be held in Chicago, Illinois between 29 November - 04 December 2020. We are dedicated to building the future of our profession, whether that’s through our Research &amp; Education Foundation, which has funded $60 million in grants since its inception, our solutions to support standards development or educational outreach to low-resource nations.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong> Contact for attendance cost</p>

<h2 id="aws-reinventhttpsreinventawseventscom">49. <a href="https://reinvent.awsevents.com">AWS re:Invent</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/awsreinvent">@awsreinvent</a></p>

<p>November 30 – December 4, 2020 
<strong>Las Vegas, NV</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/FnsOIiBm8B7q5q70XDhXq/05348894bb429a0faa4d87607d3f899f/49._AWS_re-Invent_.png" alt="49. AWS re-Invent" /></p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong> Contact for attendance cost</p>

<h2 id="healthcare-informatics-health-it-summit-serieshttpswwwhealthcare-informaticscompage2health-it-summit-series-calendar-events">50. <a href="https://www.healthcare-informatics.com/page2/health-it-summit-series-calendar-events">Healthcare Informatics Health IT Summit Series</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/HCInformatics">@HCInformatics</a></p>

<p>Multiple Dates<br />
<strong>Multiple Locations</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/1TxX8UdUkSWGM7gxzfICEK/9a463727fba933b89a7cdf5a7591f1eb/50.__Healthcare_Informatics_Health_IT_Summit_Series_.png" alt="50. Healthcare Informatics Health IT Summit Series" /></p>

<p>The Healthcare IT Summit Series, organized by Healthcare Informatics, includes ten events over nine states: the Midwest Health IT Summit, the Texas Health IT Summit, the Florida Health IT Summit, the Southeast Health IT Summit, the Rocky Mountain Health IT Summit, the Mid-Atlantic Health IT Summit, the California Health IT Summit, and more. Each of these series aims to provide education and healthy debate in regards to the future of HIT. 2020’s topics include value-based care, population health, cybersecurity, AI, data analytics, clinical workflow, and telehealth.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong> Contact for attendance cost</p>
<p><a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/top-health-it-conferences-part-2"> Continue reading, &quot;Top 50 Health IT Conferences to Attend in 2020, Part 2&quot;</a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Top 50 Health IT Conferences to Attend in 2020</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/top-health-it-conferences"/>
    <id>https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/top-health-it-conferences</id>
    <published>2020-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dave Levin, MD</name>
    </author>
    <summary>To make it easier for you to plan your conference attendance schedule for 2020, we’ve compiled our picks for the 50 must-attend health IT conferences. These events are designed to connect healthcare professionals working in a variety of unique disciplines, touching on hot-button topics for...</summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/2qylsn7PJMEb1ALdtRx2pP/b72b8413e6cb75aa5bf244470a219e7a/clement-m-sNyFgVJ72is-unsplash.jpg?fit=crop&w=840&h=420&fm=jpg&q=40" width="420" alt="Top 50 Health IT Conferences to Attend in 2020"><p>As global technology continues to evolve, so does the healthcare  industry’s appetite for heightened connectivity and interoperability,  which empower healthcare organizations to streamline patient care  delivery and provide more efficient, better-quality care. According to data compiled by <a href="https://dashboard.healthit.gov/quickstats/quickstats.php"><em>Health IT Dashboard</em></a>, 96 percent of all non-federal acute care hospitals possessed certified health IT in 2017. But widespread health IT adoption aside, facilities must not rest on their initial investments to see them through the next decade – or potentially even the next few years. In order to compete in this ever-evolving landscape, the healthcare industry must be willing to collaborate and take an active role in its IT implementation.</p>
<p>To support this mission, we’ve compiled a list of the 50 best health  IT conferences to attend in 2020. These events are designed to connect  healthcare professionals working in a variety of unique disciplines,  touching on hot-button topics for today’s healthcare organizations, from connectivity to interoperability, <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/designing-safe-and-effective-digital-health-applications/">digital health apps</a>, cybersecurity, the rise of blockchain (and its potential to impact the healthcare industry), <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/innovation/automating-healthcare-with-artificial-intelligence/">Artificial Intelligence</a>, and other health IT trends and innovations.</p>

<p>Below you’ll find the list of conferences taking place in Q1 and Q2. Click <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/top-health-it-conferences-part-2/">here</a> for a list of conferences in Q3 and Q4.</p>

<h2 id="clinical-data-disclosure-and-transparencyhttpsinformaconnectcomclinical-data-disclosure-and-transparency">1. <a href="https://informaconnect.com/clinical-data-disclosure-and-transparency/">Clinical Data Disclosure and Transparency</a></h2>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/CBI_Conferences">@CBI_Conferences</a></p>

<p>January 22 – 24, 2020<br />
<strong>Coral Gables, FL</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/PG0fqR3ba5qGCnCTdQOmP/acdc435ac79f1c739340f4258a64bcd8/1.png" alt="1" /></p>

<p>Join CBI’s 7th Annual Clinical Data Disclosure, Transparency &amp; Dissemination to discuss and disseminate the latest information during a time of industry reform. The clinical data transparency landscape is shifting as U.S. and global regulations are continuing to evolve. At this conference, gain insight from an expert speaking faculty, navigate regulatory changes, develop strategies for data and document anonymization, achieve meaningful patient engagement and spend your time with a laser focus on data sharing.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Standard: $2,299</li>
  <li>Onsite: $2,399</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="connected-health-rpm-and-telehealth-summithttps10timescomleadership-summit-on-telehealth">2. <a href="https://10times.com/leadership-summit-on-telehealth">Connected Health: RPM and Telehealth Summit</a></h2>

<p>January 29 – 31, 2020
<strong>Atlanta, GA</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/5lyJkgNxKHZhs2GJaGActp/660f75790e2f151882732e1d0eb33248/2._Connected_Health-_RPM_and_Telehealth_Summit.png" alt="2. Connected Health- RPM and Telehealth Summit" /></p>

<p>The Connected Health: RPM and Telehealth Summit outline operational best practices for connected health programs, explore case studies in digital health, identify critical quality metrics to define success, and uncover greater ROI for applications of emerging technologies.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong> Contact for attendance cost</p>

<h2 id="health-datapaloozahttpswwwacademyhealthorgevents2020-022020-health-datapalooza">3. <a href="https://www.academyhealth.org/events/2020-02/2020-health-datapalooza">Health Datapalooza</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/academyhealth">@academyhealth</a></p>

<p>February 10 – 11, 2020
<strong>Washington, D.C.</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/4MkrqsYsqrc6kX6dCbS8xS/ea3168f2b0b10eea74e51dca8ef1f395/3._Health_Datapalooza.png" alt="3. Health Datapalooza" /></p>

<p>For the first time, the Health Datapalooza will take place in February and be co-located with the AcademyHealth National Health Policy Conference (NHPC) in Washington, D.C. The 2020 Health Datapalooza will feature the same great plenaries, breakouts, awards, and unconference sessions.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong> Contact for attendance cost</p>

<h2 id="scope-summithttpswwwscopesummitcom">4. <a href="https://www.scopesummit.com/">SCOPE Summit</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/SCOPEsummit/">@SCOPESummit</a></p>

<p>February 18 – 21, 2020 
<strong>Orlando, FL</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/7FCuypDGGoPFK7KxKC2vtT/7af772a125a49a92f6751b37dcf11b65/4._SCOPE_Summit.png" alt="4. SCOPE Summit" /></p>

<p>Celebrating its 11th successful year, SCOPE Summit 2020 takes place February 18-21 in Orlando, FL. Over the course of four stimulating days of in-depth discussions in 20 different conferences, 3 plenary keynote sessions, the annual Participant Engagement Awards, and the ever-popular interactive breakout discussions, the programming focuses on advances and innovative solutions in all aspects of clinical trial planning, management and operations.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Commercial: $3,099</li>
  <li>Academic, Government, Hospital Affiliated: $1,399</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="gartner-cio-forum--httpswwwgartnercomenconferencesnacio-us-west">5. <a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/conferences/na/cio-us-west">Gartner CIO Forum  </a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/Gartner_inc">@Gartner_inc</a></p>

<p>February 23 – 25, 2020
<strong>Phoenix, AZ</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/kMrYxLuwVpphfVl1Bpgsi/d4e43816ea02cce3d605623b0de664a4/5._Gartner_CIO_Forum__.png" alt="5. Gartner CIO Forum" /></p>

<p>Join an exclusive community of CIOs to make connections and generate insights in a trusted and collaborative environment</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Standard: $3,800</li>
  <li>Public Sector: $3,125</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="digital-health--care-annual-conference--awardshttpdigitalhealthholyroodcom">6. <a href="http://digitalhealth.holyrood.com/">Digital Health &amp; Care: Annual Conference &amp; Awards</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/DigitalHealth18">@DigitalHealth18</a></p>

<p>February 25 – 26, 2020<br />
<strong>Edinburgh, Scotland</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/3kPVCHbpOmx91HSh6ben3B/7c3830a1d22ba80c119ee60524aeff73/6._Digital_Health___Care-_Annual_Conference___Awards.png" alt="6. Digital Health &amp; Care- Annual Conference &amp; Awards" /></p>

<p>Since 2011, Digital Health &amp; Care Scotland has been the premier gathering of senior eHealth professionals from across the Scottish health and social care sector. In 2018, its status was cemented with the launch of the first Digital Health &amp; Care Awards in Scotland – so get ready for our biggest conference yet in 2020. Throughout the course of the two days, delegates will hear a number of interactive presentations that showcase examples of success.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong> Contact for attendance cost</p>

<h2 id="chime-himss-cio-forumhttpschimecentralorgchime-himss-cio-forum">7. <a href="https://chimecentral.org/chime-himss-cio-forum/">CHIME HiMSS CIO Forum</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/CIOCHIME">@CIOCHIME</a></p>

<p>March 8 – 9, 2020<br />
<strong>Orlando, FL</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/2HRzZ4y1mnzKj2CYlH3Srm/9e763cdc05c65a9b220cc4d777e1ba00/7._CHIME_HiMSS_CIO_Forum.png" alt="7. CHIME HiMSS CIO Forum" /></p>

<p>The CHIME HIMSS CIO Forum provides valuable education programming, tailored specifically to meet the needs of CIOs and other healthcare IT executives, as well as face-to-face time with colleagues to collaborate, exchange best practices, address professional development needs and strengthen partnerships with industry associations, government agencies and service firms who share a professional interest in improving the quality, safety and cost-effectiveness of healthcare.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong> (must be a CHIME member to attend)</p>

<ul>
  <li>Advance (ends 2/10): $500</li>
  <li>Onsite (starts 2/11): $550</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="himss20httpswwwhimssconferenceorg">8. <a href="https://www.himssconference.org/">HIMSS20</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/HIMSS">@HIMSS</a></p>

<p>March 9 – 13, 2020 
<strong>Orlando, FL</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/3E2laRyGJ3gqifw8myhLge/ec83db64c60b99ce9ed3388f0f8942c6/8._HIMSS20.png" alt="8. HIMSS20" /></p>

<p>The 2020 HIMSS Global Health Conference &amp; Exhibition, March 9–13, 2020 in Orlando, is the can’t-miss health information and technology event of the year, where professionals throughout the global health ecosystem connect for the education, innovation and collaboration they need to reimagine health and wellness for everyone, everywhere. In a time of unprecedented healthcare disruption, HIMSS20 calls health information and technology professionals around the world to one essential, simple, bold action: Be the change.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>HIMSS Member: $975</li>
  <li>Non-Member: $1,185</li>
  <li>Collaborator: $975</li>
  <li>Government: $875</li>
  <li>Student: $185
*Cost will increase after 2/10/2020</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="sxsw-health--medtech-expohttpswwwsxswcomconferencehealth-and-medtech">9.<a href="https://www.sxsw.com/conference/health-and-medtech/"> SXSW Health &amp; MedTech Expo</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/sxsw">@sxsw</a></p>

<p>March 13 – 17, 2020 
<strong>Austin, TX</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/6gw6eAAwlKv5R6V88FlFmn/46426499a952af08219ace3c03ecff33/9._SXSW_Health___MedTech_Expo.png" alt="9. SXSW Health &amp; MedTech Expo" /></p>

<p>Perhaps one of the most high-profile additions to our list is the SXSW Health and MedTech Expo, a sub-event of the famed SXSW music, interactive, and film festival. The Health &amp; MedTech track focuses on the new advances and approaches being applied to medicine and well-being, including a deep dive into how the ecosystem of patients, providers, and payers interfaces with technology to improve outcomes in the communities where we live, work, and play.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Platinum Badge: $1,475</li>
  <li>Interactive Badge: $1,145</li>
  <li>Film Badge: $1,145</li>
  <li>SXSW Edu Badge: $485</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="rise-nashvillehttpswwwrise-nashvillecom">10. <a href="https://www.rise-nashville.com/">RISE Nashville</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/RISEhlth">@RISEhlth</a></p>

<p>March 15 – 17, 2020 
<strong>Nashville, TN</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/1Wuu45RnSKwcpWykhXWINq/95dedcd3730991230ae6e21cea5f690d/10._RISE_Nashville.png" alt="10. RISE Nashville" /></p>

<p>As the #1 trusted source for risk adjustment, quality, Stars, and beyond, RISE Nashville is back for its fourteenth consecutive year as the must-attend mega-conference for professionals of all levels in the Medicare Advantage and ACA market. Join other health plans and physician groups and network with key stakeholders in the health care industry. Learn best practices from peers and partners to re-energize and push your organization forward, including what’s to come in government health care reform. The 14th Annual RISE Nashville Summit will be held at Music City Center.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Government and Community Service: $1,195 (Early) $1,395 (Standard) $1,595 (Onsite)</li>
  <li>Health Plans and Providers: $1,895 (Early) $2,095 (Standard) $2,295 (Onsite)</li>
  <li>Solutions Partners and Consultants: : $2,695 (Early) $2,895 (Standard), $3,095 (Onsite)</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="aonlhttpswwwaonlorg">11. <a href="https://www.aonl.org/">AONL</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/tweetAONE">@tweetAONE</a></p>

<p>March 18-21, 2020<br />
<strong>Nashville, TN</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/6VjIrJiCU44j7ixDNqiwRo/e51f0d551435fd162d2bc7d208ffcad2/11._AONL_.png" alt="11. AONL" /></p>

<p>Further your career in a think tank environment at AONL 2020. Learn new innovative strategies that can help ready your team for the future of health care.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Full Conference AONL Member Registration: $1,150 (ends March 17), $1,350 (Onsite)</li>
  <li>Full Conference AONL Non-Member Registration: $1,250 (ends March 17), $1,650 (Onsite)</li>
  <li>Single Day Member: $550 (ends March 17), $575 (Onsite)</li>
  <li>Single Day Non-Member: $675 (ends March 17), $700 (Onsite)</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="amia-informatics-summithttpswwwamiaorgsummit2020">12. <a href="https://www.amia.org/summit2020">AMIA Informatics Summit</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/AMIAinformatics/">@AMIAinformatics</a></p>

<p>March 23 – 26, 2020<br />
<strong>Houston, TX</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/BBjHsHIywSWQNJEdSueOq/cd72f7623e56a4314e093dedd02f6a23/12._AMIA_Informatics_Summit.png" alt="12. AMIA Informatics Summit" /></p>

<p>The AMIA 2020 Informatics Summit will focus on cutting edge research around four main areas: Translational Bioinformatics, Clinical Research Informatics, Implementation Informatics and Data Science. The meeting will bring together researchers from these fields and beyond to share their work and promote a vibrant exchange of ideas leading to new collaborations, innovation and discovery. The program will be diverse including research presentations, keynote speakers, panels and short “elevator pitch” presentations highlighting the newest developments in the field of informatics with the goal of enhancing the sharing of methods and approaches across the four areas of focus. The conference welcomes students, educators, researchers from academia as well as industry who will all benefit from participating in the AMIA 2020 Informatics Summit and learning about the newest informatics developments. This year we are excited to host the meeting in Houston for the first time and welcome all of you to join us there!</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Member: $975 (by 2/20), $1,085 (by 2/21-3/12), $1,185 (after 3/12)</li>
  <li>Non-Member: $1,340 (by 2/20), $1,340 (by 2/21-3/12), $1,440 (after 3/12)</li>
  <li>Student Member: $495 (by 2/20), $545 (by 2/21-3/12), $595 (after 3/12)</li>
  <li>Student Non-Member: $605 (by 2/20), $605 (by 2/21-3/12), $705 (after 3/12)</li>
  <li>Author Member: $925 (by 2/20), $1,035 (by 2/21-3/12), $1,135 (after 3/12)</li>
  <li>Author Non-Member: $1,290 (by 2/20), $1,290 (by 2/21-3/12), $1,390 (after 3/12)</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="th-annual-world-health-care-congresshttpswwwworldhealthcarecongresscom">13. <a href="https://www.worldhealthcarecongress.com/">17th Annual World Health Care Congress</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/wrldhealthcare">@wrldhealthcare</a></p>

<p>March 29 – April 1, 2020
<strong>Washington, D.C.</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/3pLRSk0kN6fDY0qmXjdrdk/80acb0731e03bf52eb6fc48489da1bc2/13._17th_Annual_World_Health_Care_Congress.png" alt="13. 17th Annual World Health Care Congress" /></p>

<p>Although its name may be splashy, the 2019 Health Datapalooza  Conference is an event that outlines the most critical current and  emerging innovations shaping the health IT sector today. Now in its 10th year, the conference has one of the most impressive and distinct  speaker schedules of 2019; its list includes individuals working in  network, provider, non-profit, startup, and government roles. The 2019  Health Datapalooza Conference will take place at the Washington Hilton  in our nation’s capital.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong> </p>

<ul>
  <li>Standard: $3,595</li>
  <li>Pharma/Biotech: $3,295</li>
  <li>Health Plans: $2,095</li>
  <li>Hospital and Health Plans: $1,495</li>
  <li>Academic: $1,495</li>
  <li>TPA and Brokers: $1,495</li>
  <li>Government: $495</li>
  <li>Employer HQ Gold Circle: $1-$400</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="beckers-hospital-review-11th-annual-meetinghttpswwwbeckershospitalreviewcomconference">14. <a href="https://www.beckershospitalreview.com/conference/">Becker’s Hospital Review 11th Annual Meeting</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/beckershr">@beckershr</a></p>

<p>April 6 – 9, 2020 
<strong>Chicago, IL</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/UGxFgyj0SjgUg4uTZexJL/0db90975ed8db04ad39e9a5ad56776c7/14._Becker___s_Hospital_Review_11th_Annual_Meeting_.png" alt="14. Becker’s Hospital Review 11th Annual Meeting" /></p>

<p>Currently gearing up for its 10th year, the Becker’s Hospital Review Annual Meeting is the premier 2020 healthcare event for healthcare executives, featuring the biggest names in politics, information technology, non-profits, and more. The event’s list of speakers includes Former President, George W. Bush and Fist Lady, Laura Bush, Earvin “Magic” Johnson, and a long list of CEOs from the most influential healthcare companies in the country. The event will be held at the Hyatt Regency in Chicago.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong> </p>

<ul>
  <li>First attendee: $950</li>
  <li>Additional attendees: $900</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="chime-healthcare-cio-boot-camphttpschimecentralorghealthcare-cio-bc">15. <a href="https://chimecentral.org/healthcare-cio-bc/">CHIME Healthcare CIO Boot Camp</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/CIOCHIME">@CIOCHIME</a></p>

<p>April 18 – 21, 2020 
<strong>Chicago, IL</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/7fNbb5crByP8NQfvRpEzcI/21678d5a797514d3c4d7457a38c9cb78/15._CHIME_Healthcare_CIO_Boot_Camp.png" alt="15. CHIME Healthcare CIO Boot Camp" /></p>

<p>The Healthcare CIO Boot Camp™ is an intensive three and one-half day education program offered by the College of Healthcare Information Management Executives (CHIME) taught by a faculty of healthcare CIO thought leaders. Combining presentations, small group discussions, case studies and interactive problem solving, participants learn the real-world skills necessary to become a successful healthcare CIO. Participation in the Boot Camp is currently limited to members of CHIME, AEHIS, AEHIT and AEHIA, and their direct reports (including Affiliates).</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Attendee: $4,995 (must be paid by March 13)</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="th-annual-bio-it-world-conference--expo-2020httpwwwgiiconferencecomchi909998">16. <a href="http://www.giiconference.com/chi909998/">19th Annual Bio-IT World Conference &amp; Expo 2020</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/bioitworld">@bioitworld</a></p>

<p>April 21 – 23, 2020 
<strong>Boston, MA</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/1tSgDzRMhb8AACQSTJHVgl/c6ef8722ddfa1d8f7730019328204c8a/16.png" alt="16" /></p>

<p>In the spirit of open collaboration, the world’s premier bio-IT conference will bring together the community to focus on how we are using technologies and analytic approaches to solve problems, accelerate science, and drive the future of precision medicine. With a focus on AI, data science and other “data-driven” technologies that are advancing biomedical research, drug discovery and healthcare, the Bio-IT World Conference &amp; Expo ‘20 will bring together more than 3,000 participants to the Seaport World Trade Center in Boston from April 21-23.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Main Conference (Commercial): $2,249</li>
  <li>1 Workshop (Commercial): $599</li>
  <li>2 Workshops (Commercial): $899</li>
  <li>Main Conference (Academic, Government, Hospital Affiliated): $799</li>
  <li>1 Workshop (Academic, Government, Hospital Affiliated): $299</li>
  <li>2 Workshops (Academic, Government, Hospital Affiliated): $499</li>
  <li>Poster Discount: $50</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="semantic-technology-conferencehttps2020-ussemanticscc">17. <a href="https://2020-us.semantics.cc">Semantic Technology Conference</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/semanticsconf">@semanticsconf</a></p>

<p>April 21 – 23, 2020<br />
<strong>Austin, TX</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/5YwBFyMKvZcBnAqf6O4gNB/b8689354ddce2770de0f74f9badc93e5/17.__Semantic_Technology_Conference_.png" alt="17. Semantic Technology Conference" /></p>

<p>SEMANTiCS US will bring together the world’s experts, practitioners, and researchers in Knowledge Graphs, Ontologies, and AI to share their experience and knowledge. It will serve as a meeting place and collaborative opportunity for business and IT to come together to discuss the latest trends, successes, and challenges in this constantly evolving space, with specific programming for all skill and experience levels.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong> </p>

<ul>
  <li>Early Bird (ends 2/13): $850</li>
  <li>Entire Event: $975</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="state-healthcare-it-connect-summithttpwwwhealthcareitconnectcom2020-state-healthcare-it-connect-summit">18. <a href="http://www.healthcareitconnect.com/2020-state-healthcare-it-connect-summit/">State Healthcare IT Connect Summit</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/HealthITCONNECT">@HealthITCONNECT</a></p>

<p>April 27 – 29, 2020 
<strong>Baltimore, MD</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/2EyxTjBbuoE8D677DPNZFJ/a3900e477e1a9f605f0dc17c29f90a87/18.__State_Healthcare_IT_Connect_Summit_.png" alt="18. State Healthcare IT Connect Summit" /></p>

<p>The 2020 meeting will be the 11th annual State Healthcare IT Connect Summit. The conference has grown and evolved into an important national venue for public and private sector thought leaders to share ideas and benchmark implementation strategies of State Health IT Systems. We anticipate 1000+ attendees &amp; 45+ state teams at the 2020 program.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Federal, State, and Local Government: FREE</li>
  <li>Media: FREE</li>
  <li>Payers and Providers: $595 (Early)  $795 (Regular Rate)</li>
  <li>Industry: $795 (Early) $995 (Regular Rate)</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="epic-ugm-2019httpsugmepiccom">19. <a href="https://ugm.epic.com">EPIC UGM 2019</a></h2>

<p>April 27 – May 8, 2020 
<strong>Verona, WI</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/35O9dpPWz2CO3AfTwvq9EN/f15cc4e7ff2f861ea01a5fe963320c64/19.__EPIC_UGM_2019_.png" alt="19. EPIC UGM 2019" /></p>

<p>Software firm, Epic, will be hosting UGM 2019 this summer, a conference that celebrates the company’s 40th-year in business and educates attendees on all things new in healthcare IT. The four-day event is set to feature a wide range of speaker and collaborative opportunities, including “Unsessions,” that allow participants to have frank and, hopefully productive, conversations with their peers. This event will be held on Epic’s Verona Campus in Vernoa, Wisconsin.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong> Contact for attendance cost</p>

<h2 id="nd-quarter-health-it-conferences">2nd Quarter Health IT Conferences</h2>

<h2 id="ata20httpsgotelehealthorg2020-ata-telehealth-conference">20. <a href="https://gotelehealth.org/2020-ata-telehealth-conference/">ATA20</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/AmericanTelemed">@AmericanTelemed</a></p>

<p>May 3-5, 2020 
<strong>Los Angeles, CA</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/6vpYlloA1pp8yXTpZ51osV/e1fa38158e3d6e4748bf5fd454cb976a/20.__ATA20_.png" alt="20. ATA20" /></p>

<p>At ATA2020, you will become immersed in the novel application of virtual care technologies, deepen your understanding of patient and consumer perspectives and motivations, and bring clarity to the challenges, policies and opportunities to implementing telehealth solutions in value-based delivery models. Attendees will be armed with the practical knowledge, best practices and actionable insights that will allow you to identify opportunities for your organization and create the future of care delivery. Our speakers, our content and our partners create a solid foundation on which to build your telehealth expertise and success. Only at ATA2020, you will get a glimpse of where the market is going in the next five years, from the thought leaders and innovators creating that future.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Explorer Pass Member: $525 (through 2/28)</li>
  <li>Explorer Pass Non-Member: $675 (through 4/14)</li>
  <li>All Access Pass Member: $1,035 (through 2/28)</li>
  <li>All Access Non-Member: $1,295 (through 4/14)</li>
  <li>Government All-Access Pass: $725</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="ibm-think-2020httpswwwibmcomeventsthink">21. <a href="https://www.ibm.com/events/think/">IBM THINK 2020</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/ibmlive">@ibmlive</a></p>

<p>May 4 – 7, 2020
<strong>San Francisco, CA</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/6GNsS09l4rWfLsGpiUFCHd/de2948a2c14757e2eae0af4b3539e9ce/21.__IBM_THINK_2020_.png" alt="21. IBM THINK 2020" /></p>

<p>Acquire hands-on experience with the latest advancements in open technologies from hybrid multicloud to data and AI – then meet the luminaries who are using them to transform our lives. Think isn’t a single conference for thousands of people. It’s thousands of curated conferences in one.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Super Saver (ends 2/14): $1,995</li>
  <li>Early Bird (ends 4/5): $2,295</li>
  <li>Standard: $2,495</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="th-bi-annual-dodva--gov-health-it-summithttpiehrsummitdsigrouporg">22. <a href="http://iehrsummit.dsigroup.org">17th Bi-Annual DoD/VA &amp; Gov Health IT Summit</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/dsi_group">@dsi_group</a></p>

<p>May 6 – 7, 2020<br />
<strong>Alexandria, VA</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/1xNBIakgjHmYYgf762yQqU/67cb9fe059771e03e1854d01ead46ec9/22.__17th_Bi-Annual_DoD_VA___Gov_Health_IT_Summit_.png" alt="22. 17th Bi-Annual DoD:VA &amp; Gov Health IT Summit" /></p>

<p>The 17th Annual DoD/VA &amp; Government HIT Summit is designed as a “Town Hall” style forum that illustrates the DoD, VA and Federal Government’s efforts at facilitating an interoperable and modernized health IT ecosystem. This event will discuss the acquisition and current innovations in technologies that are being integrated across the DoD, VA, and Federal Government to further enable a compatible, efficient &amp; secure electronic health record system for all active duty &amp; veterans. It will also detail advancements that have been made to secure medical devices in the healthcare system from various cyber-attacks and breaches.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong> Contact for attendance cost</p>

<h2 id="hospital--healthcare-it-conferencehttpswwwhlthcpcomconferences2020-spring-hospital-healthcare-itprovideroverview">23.<a href="https://www.hlthcp.com/conferences/2020-spring-hospital-healthcare-it/provider/overview">Hospital &amp; Healthcare IT Conference</a></h2>

<p>May 18 – 20, 2020<br />
<strong>New Orleans, LA</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/2Ed8JjXBWGtZoPovAFLUDI/466bf9704e6d9bb81466dcaf321f3d77/23.__Hospital___Healthcare_IT_Conference_.png" alt="23. Hospital &amp; Healthcare IT Conference" /></p>

<p>With our concurrent conference model, you will have opportunities to make even more connections during networking events - the Keynote Address, Meals, Hospitality Suites, and Dinner &amp; Entertainment events will be held jointly - while maintaining dedicated focus on the subjects and solutions that matter most to you during the Reverse Expo and Educational Sessions. </p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong> Contact for attendance cost</p>

<h2 id="hitrust-annualhttpswebcventcomeventa0070a08-2137-4498-8303-42c38de877bdsummaryrefidhtwrtyvvm14iifkcjri4hyejota">24. <a href="https://web.cvent.com/event/a0070a08-2137-4498-8303-42c38de877bd/summary?RefId=HTW&amp;rt=YvVM14IIFkCjri4hYEjotA">HITRUST Annual</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/HITRUST">@HITRUST</a></p>

<p>May 19 – 21, 2020
<strong>Grapevine, TX</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/6IPybxFbLR9rtqB6nGizBO/3425fd5cdb3b2fac74c0be9d1db0a571/24.__HITRUST_Annual__.png" alt="24. HITRUST Annual" /></p>

<p>HITRUST® Collaborate is the most comprehensive and definitive information risk management conference for privacy, security, and compliance professionals. If safeguarding sensitive information and preventing a data breach is important to your organization, your company will want to be part of this high-impact event. The goal of HITRUST Collaborate is to enable attendees to learn, collaborate, and deliver more effective methods for risk management, compliance, information protection, and address privacy requirements. HITRUST Collaborate attendees will listen to and participate in discussions on the latest trends and best practices.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Early Bird (by 3/2): $1,750</li>
  <li>Standard (after 3/2): $2,000</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="amia-clinical-informatics-conferencehttpswwwamiaorgcic2020">25. <a href="https://www.amia.org/cic2020">AMIA Clinical Informatics Conference</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/AMIAinformatics">@AMIAinformatics</a></p>

<p>May 19 – 21, 2020
<strong>Seattle, WA</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/1c9yUXleu4AmK70uqqNGNH/8fa9fdc817079f5781d469d0a2fd4d4d/25.__AMIA_Clinical_Informatics_Conference_.png" alt="25. AMIA Clinical Informatics Conference" /></p>

<p>AMIA’s second event of the year AMIA’s Clinical Informatics Conference – CIC – is making a mark on healthcare. CIC is where practitioners in health informatics including physicians, nurses, physician assistants, technicians, HIT developers, data analysts, C-suite executives, and all members of the health care team come together at their home conference. Our collective goal is to advance healthcare systems driven by data, evidence, and best practice with the explicit purpose of creating better health information technologies. Known as AMIA’s “doing conference,” this conference features workshops, presentations, and networking events that provide attendees with tools to support their day-to-day efforts while working toward the quadruple aim. CIC comes to Seattle in 2020 bringing a conference filled with unbiased content combining evidence and experience-based informatics to foster a true learning health system.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong> Contact for attendance cost</p>

<h2 id="himss-health-20-europehttpswwwhimsseuropeconferenceeu">26. <a href="https://www.himsseuropeconference.eu">HiMSS Health 2.0 Europe</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/himsseurope">@himsseurope</a></p>

<p>May 26-28, 2020
<strong>Helsinki, Finland</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/1Z4bbGbmgWgdvA0xd5bX7/d46c8076f77a7324f567ad9fd3b8f4dd/26.__HiMSS_Health_2.0_Europe_.png" alt="26. HiMSS Health 2.0 Europe" /></p>

<p>The most influential digital health conference in Europe will be returning to Helsinki, Finland on 26-28 May 2020 for three days of the latest innovation, exciting learning and unmatchable networking opportunities.The conference will welcome over 3,000 healthcare leaders and more than 200 speakers from the entire ecosystem under the same roof, gathering the best of both worlds: the HIMSS expertise and thought leadership and the Health 2.0 network of entrepreneurs and investors. Together, in addition to engaging with each other, hearing about real best practices and learning new skills, delegates will get a unique chance to see some of the technologies that are making a positive difference to patients today.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong> </p>

<ul>
  <li>Attendee (Health Professionals, Govt, Clinicians) member: €750</li>
  <li>Non-sponsoring Vendor member: €2,050</li>
  <li>Start-Ups/SME member: €750</li>
  <li>Attendee (Health Professionals, Govt, Clinicians) non-member: €825</li>
  <li>Non-sponsoring Vendor non-member: €2,125</li>
  <li>Start-Ups/SME non-member: €825</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="e-health-2019httpswwwe-healthconferencecom">27. <a href="https://www.e-healthconference.com">e-Health 2019</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/eHealthConf">@eHealthConf</a></p>

<p>May 31 – June 1, 2020<br />
<strong>Parq Vancouvre, BC</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/gZPaqfRuvl0oU4O44H28p/a40e3b923bcdae2f2fa9cfbab29df7da/27.__e-Health_2019_.png" alt="27. e-Health 2019" /></p>

<p>For 20 years, the annual e-Health Conference and Tradeshow has created unique and valuable learning and networking opportunities for organizations and people working to make a difference in Canadian health through information and technology.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong> </p>

<ul>
  <li>Digital Canada Member: $975 (Early Bird), $1,200 (Regular), $1,400 (Onsite)</li>
  <li>Non-Member: $1,175 (Early Bird), $1,400 (Regular), $1,600 (Onsite)</li>
  <li>Student: $275 (Early Bird), $325 (Regular), $475 (Onsite)</li>
  <li>Abstract Presenter: $625 (Early Bird), $725 (Regular), $875 (Onsite)</li>
  <li>One-Day Registration Member: $475 (Early Bird), $595 (Regular), $745 (Onsite)</li>
  <li>One-Day Registration Non-Member: $595 (Early Bird), $695 (Regular), $845 (Onsite)</li>
  <li>Sunday Workshop: $95</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="digital-health-pharma-congresshttpswwwpharmaweekcom">28. <a href="https://www.pharmaweek.com">Digital Health Pharma Congress</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/CHI_Healthtech">@CHI_Healthtech</a></p>

<p>June 2 – 4, 2020 
<strong>Boston, MA</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/5OLcHmAguAhZA5U2P48kA8/7105aac22219fc1731a4deb94afd622e/28.__Digital_Health_Pharma_Congress__.png" alt="28. Digital Health Pharma Congress" /></p>

<p>Digital Health World Pharma Conference, an event which is part of CHI’s World Pharma Week, is debuting for the very first time this year. The conference, which is hosted by the Cambridge Healthtech Institute, is a four-day program that provides education on the topics of biosensors, mobile devices and wearables, Internet of Things (IoT), mobile health platforms, artificial intelligence, and much more. The Digital Health Pharma Conference will take place at the Seaport World Trade Center in Boston.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong> </p>

<ul>
  <li>Commercial: $1,999 (until 2/7), $2,499 (standard/onsite)</li>
  <li>Academic, Government, Hospital Affiliated: $999 (until 2/7), $1,299 (standard/onsite)</li>
  <li>Student: $495</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="telehealth2020httpvaluebasedcaresummitcomtelehealth2020">29. <a href="http://valuebasedcaresummit.com/telehealth2020">Telehealth2020</a></h2>

<p>June 3 – 5, 2020
<strong>Austin, TX</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/2h09dzACmvtlyHF3u2AUdl/56b92548f82ce55a6c8b342afe18f26b/29.__Telehealth2020_.png" alt="29. Telehealth2020" /></p>

<p>The Value-Based Care Summit in Austin, Texas, will convene key decision-makers from leading payer and provider organizations to discuss solutions to challenges facing the industry’s transition to value-based payment. The show will offer a blended experience for those looking to learn about the connection between value-based care and telehealth. Enjoy ample networking throughout the three day event to connect with your peers while discussing the problems, challenges, and solutions tied to new models of care delivery and reimbursement.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Healthcare Provider/Payer: $399 (ends 2/27), $599 (ends 4/2), $799 (regular), $899 (onsite)</li>
  <li>Bio/Pharma: $799 (regular), $999 (onsite)</li>
  <li>Vendor/Consultant: $1,600 (ends 2/27) $1,900 (ends 4/2) $2,200 (regular/onsite)</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="aami-exchangehttpswwwaamiorgaamiexchangeindexaspxnavitemnumber7024">30. <a href="https://www.aami.org/AAMIExchange/index.aspx?navItemNumber=7024">AAMI Exchange</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/aami_connect">@aami_connect</a></p>

<p>June 12 – 15, 2020 
<strong>New Orleans, LA</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/3NA4nKccpaaPolxBZpJnjs/4c27da5366dd44804d26c9ba9b4cdb01/30.__AAMI_Exchange_.png" alt="30. AAMI Exchange" /></p>

<p>The AAMI Exchange is the premier health technology event which seeks to connect the full gamut of AAMI stakeholders—biomedical and clinical engineers, technicians, cybersecurity and sterilization experts, hospital administrators and managers, and the industry’s leading service and solution providers. The AAMI Exchange provides a forum for broad conversations among these stakeholders on the ever-changing industry of medical technology.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong> Contact for attendance cost</p>

<h2 id="chia-convention--exhibithttpscaliforniahiaorgconvention-exhibit">31. <a href="https://californiahia.org/convention-exhibit">CHIA Convention &amp; Exhibit</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/californiahia">@californiahia</a></p>

<p>June 13 – 17, 2020 
<strong>Riverside, CA</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/1j7V3ohb7QtQpFfR9VOmp6/0ee894fe0ad57b8c29a8d576b8301cd9/31.__CHIA_Convention___Exhibit_.png" alt="31. CHIA Convention &amp; Exhibit" /></p>

<p>The CHIA Convention &amp; Exhibit is California’s premier event for health information management (HIM) professionals. Health care and the role and opportunities for HIM professionals are on the cusp of unprecedented change. This one-stop event will address today’s most important topics and offers networking opportunities to a broad spectrum of HIM professionals. Discover innovative ideas and strategies for tackling day-to-day issues as leading industry experts discuss challenges facing today’s HIM professionals in electronic health record best practices, patient access/release of information, compliance, organizational leadership and management, data integrity, clinical documentation improvement, consumer/patient engagement, coding, compliance and more.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong> Contact for attendance cost</p>

<h2 id="hl7-fhir-devdayshttpwwwhl7orgeventsfhir-devdayscfmrefnav">32. <a href="http://www.hl7.org/events/fhir-devdays.cfm?ref=nav">HL7® FHIR® DevDays</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/HL7">@HL7</a></p>

<p>June 16 – 18, 2020 
<strong>Cleveland, OH</strong></p>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/2nIKnWjyfIqLqULXyBa1sj/ef3c001d6bf34abbf57254a87c4a43cb/32.__HL7___FHIR___DevDays_.png" alt="32. HL7® FHIR® DevDays" /></p>

<p>HL7 FHIR Days is one of our hottest events and we are heading to Cleveland, Ohio on June 16-18, 2020! Registration opens in January, so sign up to be notfied and you can secure your seat as we expect a full house.  Designed to deliver a unique education experience within a collaborative environment, FHIR DevDays offers a combination of focused hackathons, tutorials, keynotes and networking. Top FHIR experts from around the world instruct, guide and discuss the further improvement of the HL7 FHIR standard.</p>

<p><strong>Cost to Attend:</strong> Contact for attendance cost</p>

<h2 id="ready-to-read-part-2">Ready to read Part 2?</h2>

<p><a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/top-health-it-conferences-part-2/">Top Health IT Conferences, Part 2</a></p>

<p><a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/top-health-it-conferences"> Continue reading, &quot;Top 50 Health IT Conferences to Attend in 2020&quot;</a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to Comply When You Receive a HIPAA Breach Notification</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/how-to-comply-when-you-receive-a-hipaa-breach-notification"/>
    <id>https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/how-to-comply-when-you-receive-a-hipaa-breach-notification</id>
    <published>2019-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Grant Barrick</name>
    </author>
    <summary>A HIPAA breach isn’t beneficial for any parties involved, but that doesn’t mean you can’t prepare in advance to comply in the event a breach does happen.</summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/xm1q7HsfG0u4Nw2OADFRs/2d1670627a04ce91b48c8ac170aa5b6d/iStock-1125105809.jpg?fit=crop&w=840&h=420&fm=jpg&q=40" width="420" alt="How to Comply When You Receive a HIPAA Breach Notification"><p>No matter how prepared an organization is for potential cyber threats, there is still a chance for a data breach. A “<a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/academy/what-is-data-breach-gdpr-and-hipaa/">data breach</a>,” according to the <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/academy/hipaa-101-a-primer/">Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act</a> (HIPAA) is, “an impermissible use or disclosure under the Privacy Rule that compromises the security or privacy of the protected health information” (<a href="https://www.hhs.gov/hipaa/for-professionals/breach-notification/index.html">US </a><a href="https://www.hhs.gov/hipaa/for-professionals/breach-notification/index.html">Department of Health and Human Services</a> ).</p>
<p>Impermissible use or disclosure essentially means protected health information (PHI) being public or seen by those who aren’t supposed to have access. When something like this occurs, it’s typically considered a breach, which is where the Breach Notification Rule of HIPAA comes into play. The moment an organization realizes  PHI data is exposed, it is their responsibility to notify all affected parties and follow all parts of the HIPAA breach rules (<a href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/cfr/text/45/164.402">45 CFR §§ 164.400-414</a>).</p>

<p>Ignoring this rule puts patient data at greater risk and results in costly violation fines and penalties. HIPAA violations range from $100 to $50,000 per violation with a maximum of $1.5 million per year.</p>

<h2 id="breach-notification-rule">Breach Notification Rule</h2>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/4HGBxTzVO5fwzztFKB3IV8/8462d54d8931fd47f591cf21538e96c1/stockfresh_10046259_data-breach-concept_sizeXS.jpg" alt="stockfresh 10046259 data-breach-concept sizeXS" /></p>

<p>HIPAA’s breach notification rule is intended to promote transparency and clarity when private data is mishandled or stolen. In addition to a clear definition of what constitutes a breach, the bill also outlines situations that are not considered breaches, including:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Unintentional use by individuals under the covering of the entity storing PHI (as long as the information was not further compromised and accessed in good faith).</li>
  <li>Inadvertent disclosure between one member of the entity storing the protected information and another member of the same organization (as long as the data is not further used and/or exposed).</li>
  <li>“A disclosure of PHI where a covered entity or business associate has a good faith belief that an unauthorized person to whom the disclosure was made would not reasonably have been able to retain such information.”</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="performing-a-hipaa-breach-notification">Performing a HIPAA Breach Notification</h2>

<p>There are three separate notifications any entity affected by a breach may need to issue:</p>

<ol>
  <li>the individuals affected</li>
  <li>the media</li>
  <li>the Secretary of HHS</li>
</ol>

<p><strong>Note:</strong> In the event that law enforcement believes a breach notification would hinder an investigation, timelines and potentially the notifications given may change.</p>

<h2 id="notifying-individuals-of-a-breach">Notifying Individuals of a Breach</h2>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/5UjOdHtcR5ZzEPPuLSJkTr/70d1d317a028f9321379d9520a6dd83e/stockfresh_352473_envelopes_sizeXS.jpg" alt="stockfresh 352473 envelopes sizeXS" /></p>

<p>Any entity suffering a data breach of PHI is <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/academy/hipaa-and-data-breaches/">required to notify every individual affected</a>. The notification should take place within 60 calendar days from when the breach was first discovered (except when law enforcement investigations are in progress).</p>

<h2 id="required-elements-of-an-individuals-breach-notification">Required Elements of an Individual’s Breach Notification</h2>

<p>There are five required elements laid out in section <a href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/cfr/text/45/164.404">45 CFR § 164.404</a> of the law. They include:</p>

<ul>
  <li>A description of the breach (dates, what happened, etc.)</li>
  <li>Types of data included in the breach</li>
  <li>Steps individuals should take</li>
  <li>Describe actions being taken by the entity concerning the breach</li>
  <li>Contact details which must include a toll-free phone number, email, website, or mailing address.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Note:</strong> The entire notification is required to be in “plain language.” In other words, language that’s easily understood by a layperson, without industry or legal jargon.</p>

<p>All this information is sent to every individual’s last known mailing address via first-class mail. If individuals have agreed to electronic communication, an email delivery is acceptable.</p>

<h2 id="notification-of-the-media">Notification of the Media</h2>

<p>When a breach affects more than 500 people in a certain state or jurisdiction, the media must be notified ( <a href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/cfr/text/45/164.406">45 CFR § 164.406</a>). Elements of this notification should follow the same guidelines outlined in the individual notification section of the bill.</p>

<h2 id="notification-of-the-hhs-secretary">Notification of the HHS Secretary</h2>

<p>There are two ways in which HHS may be notified of breaches.</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Breaches Over 500:</strong> For larger breaches, the same requirements for media and individuals are in effect, including the elements of the notification itself.</li>
  <li><strong>Breaches Under 500:</strong> Any breach with fewer than 500 individuals will need to keep a log of the incident (and any others). This log will then be reported to the HHS secretary once per year.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="preparing-for-a-breach">Preparing for a Breach</h2>

<p>No one wants a breach to occur. However, it’s best practice to be prepared in case of the event patient data is compromised. There are several things a provider should do in preparation:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Review the law:</strong> Reading the actual law and consulting with an expert about it is great preparation before a breach occurs.</li>
  <li><strong>Train employees:</strong> Privacy is everyone’s responsibility and the legal requirements should be known by all. In the event of a breach, one of an entity’s employees could be the one to discover that data is compromised. They should be trained to know what to do.</li>
  <li><strong>Create a plan:</strong> Putting together a response plan, including delegating responsibilities would decrease confusion if an event occurs.</li>
</ul>

<p>Preparing for a breach, even with the most secure data protection software and policies, will allow for minimal interruption and full compliance with the law. Every organization who falls under HIPAA should consider their plan in the event of a data compromise.</p>
<p><a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/how-to-comply-when-you-receive-a-hipaa-breach-notification"> Continue reading, &quot;How to Comply When You Receive a HIPAA Breach Notification&quot;</a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Top 3 Cloud Compliance Takeaways from AWS re:Invent</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/top-3-cloud-compliance-takeaways-from-aws-re-invent"/>
    <id>https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/top-3-cloud-compliance-takeaways-from-aws-re-invent</id>
    <published>2019-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Grant Barrick</name>
    </author>
    <summary>Our team attended AWS re:Invent 2019 in Las Vegas from December 2-6. There was so much to see and do, so much to engage with and learn from. To recap our time at the conference, here’s a breakdown of key things we noted.</summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/2iXVpsLgAIak83l07sw9q4/3b86ac3b61909225fe3270d1b3216f4e/Image_from_iOS__2_.jpg?fit=crop&w=840&h=420&fm=jpg&q=40" width="420" alt="Top 3 Cloud Compliance Takeaways from AWS re:Invent"><p>Our team attended AWS re:Invent 2019 in Las Vegas that spanned across four (long) days from December 2-6. As usual, it was a tremendous event with over 60,000 attendees, making it the biggest AWS event to date. Andy Jasse, CEO of Amazon Web Services, <a href="https://twitter.com/ajassy/status/1203398881058275328">noted on Twitter</a> this is their favorite week of the year, and anyone in attendance would see why. There is so much to see and do, so much to engage with and learn from, and so many physical locations that it can be hard to take it all in. To recap our time at the conference, here’s a breakdown of key things we noted:</p>
<p><strong>1. Lots of new services, but a maturity gap exists</strong></p>

<p>AWS continues to <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/new/reinvent/">release new services</a> with a wide range of functionality–notably Amazon Transcribe Medical getting the most attention. It’s an exciting time to be working with them! However, for those in highly regulated spaces, like healthcare, there is a wide chasm to cross from an operational, legal, and regulatory perspective. These new HIPAA-eligible services are great building blocks for digital health vendors but using them still demands complicated security and compliance efforts. This is a natural evolution, and it was clear through numerous conversations that associating these services with a cloud compliance Managed Service Provider (MSP) is necessary to unlock their potential in a compliant manner. On the show floor, <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/who-is-hitrust-csf-certified/">HITRUST certification</a> was the most frequently mentioned certification framework our team heard from prospects.</p>

<p><strong>2. Microservices can drive innovation</strong></p>

<p>As noted above, the proliferation of new microservices continues at a breathtaking pace. This provides continual opportunity for new innovation. As the industry continues to move away from monolithic architecture – a move enabled by the robust microservice offerings – there is more opportunity to build at the speed of innovation. It is easier to scale up/down and to try different approaches in this environment. Vendors are enjoying the flexibility these services offer to their development efforts and are looking for the same from their compliance partners. No longer are digital health vendors willing to accept rigid offerings from MSPs. Instead, they seek <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/cloud-compliance/">flexible offerings</a> that are commensurate with their AWS infrastructure. They demand the flexibility to control what the need to, while leaving compliance to their MSP partners.</p>

<p><strong>3. It is always easier starting fresh</strong></p>

<p>While innovation opportunities abound with AWS services, the difficulty of managing a fragmented infrastructure remains very real. For those managing varied deployment models (on-premises, hybrid, etc.) there is great difficulty in transitioning and scaling. When trying to solve for the future using the past’s infrastructure and deployment models, it can be incredibly difficult to move forward with the desired speed. This is a reality that will continue to exist for many larger vendors who have invested many resources in their existing model. Transitioning to the new world is difficult – but an opportunity for digital health vendors to seek out integration and compliance expertise from those who have helped others manage this very same challenge.</p>

<p>We had a blast at AWS re:Invent and hope our team had the chance to meet you in person! If  not, and you’d like to learn more about how Datica can help you achieve your cloud compliance needs, please let us know – we would love to hear from you at hello@datica.com.</p>
<p><a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/top-3-cloud-compliance-takeaways-from-aws-re-invent"> Continue reading, &quot;Top 3 Cloud Compliance Takeaways from AWS re:Invent&quot;</a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>4 Tips to Know For AWS re:Invent 2019</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/tips-to-know-for-aws-re-invent"/>
    <id>https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/tips-to-know-for-aws-re-invent</id>
    <published>2019-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ryan Rich</name>
    </author>
    <summary>Datica’s Chief Product Officer and experienced AWS re:Invent attendee helps you navigate one of the largest cloud events of the year. Get insights on travel, planning, sessions, and more!</summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/4kDvUHT1zjzvXF02BVQ0FZ/d4040bc3840e277dbcf9001f9c496ed0/modern-geometric-triangular-shiny-silver-steel-cladding-with-highlights-in-gold-and-copper-tones-and-perforated-design-1087.jpeg?fit=crop&w=840&h=420&fm=jpg&q=40" width="420" alt="4 Tips to Know For AWS re:Invent 2019"><p>AWS re:Invent 2019 is just around the corner, taking place this year from December 2-6, 2019 in Las Vegas. Hosted by Amazon Web Services, re:Invent is considered the biggest cloud event of the year, with over 55,000 attendees at last year’s conference. And this year is expected to be bigger and bigger with an increase in attendees and its campus spanning across two miles in multiple buildings.</p>

<p>Yet, navigating this conference can be very overwhelming, especially if it’s your first year attending. Have no fear! We’ve pulled together our 2019 guide to AWS re:Invent with helpful tips to make the most of your time at the conference.</p>

<p>And, don’t forget to stop by <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/events/aws-re-invent-19/">Datica’s booth #3820</a>!</p>
<p><strong>Sessions</strong></p>

<p>re:Invent sessions are very popular. Unlike other conferences, people actually attend the breakout sessions at re:Invent. It’s very common to have a room with 600 people for a single session. And, with over 2,500 sessions, re:Invent has something for everyone. If you’re brand new to working within the cloud as an Engineer, or if you’re a non-technical business user, you’ll find relevant sessions at the 200 level. Engineers and technical people that are more familiar with AWS will find 300 and 400 level sessions the most beneficial.</p>

<p><em>Helpful Tip: Even if you’re on a waitlist for a session, don’t expect to get in. To give yourself the best chance, arrive at least 30 minutes early. This can be tricky with sessions spanning across 5 hotels this year. For that reason, we recommend planning your sessions by day. Ex: Day 1 - all sessions in Venetian, Day 2 - all session in Aria, etc.</em></p>

<p><strong>Plan Ahead</strong></p>

<p>Aside from planning ahead for sessions, it’s important to plan for business meetings, what you plan on doing that day and how you’ll travel around the conference. We recommend jotting down a rough structure for each day ahead of time. Be sure to include travel times in your schedule, as the campus will be busy, in addition to being in Las Vegas.</p>

<p><em>Helpful tip: Write down your day. From where you’ll pick up free breakfast (typically provided by the conference), to which sessions you’ll attend, to which events you’re going to check out at night. We also recommend devoting at least half your day to the vendor hall. The re:Invent expo hall is massive, and there are a lot of interesting companies (plus a lot of decent and free swag available).</em></p>

<p><strong>Travel</strong></p>

<p>Traveling to and around Las Vegas can be tricky. As previously mentioned, the re:Invent campus spans across two miles, and depending on where your lodging is, you might have to walk multiple miles per day. Vegas does have public transport, via Monorail, and in our experience is fairly reliable.</p>

<p>In addition, shuttle services are provided between campus buildings but do note that does not include any locations outside those 5 hotels. Download the re:Invent mobile app to get real-time updates of travel times for shuttle services.</p>

<p>We wouldn’t recommend relying on ride share services. In our experience, both Lyft and Uber seem to be understaffed every year at re:Invent. Plus, rideshares seem to have surcharges applied during the conference.</p>

<p><em>Helpful Tip: Give yourself time. Finding a cab or a ride share service from the airport to the strip can take a long time and can be relatively expensive. Be sure to give yourself at least an hour between when you land, and when you want to arrive to the conference. Also, don’t forget your walking shoes! You’ll be traversing the strip all week.</em></p>

<p><strong>Rest</strong></p>

<p>This tip might seem odd, but it should be taken seriously. With over 30 expo exhibitor hours spanning across 4 days, re:Invent is exhausting. And then comes the nightlife. The conference has its array of hosted events, in addition to meeting with clients, prospects and co-workers over drinks. It’s pretty common to be having fun for five nights in a row. This can be mentally and physically draining. Be sure to get enough sleep, drink enough fluids, and workout or walk as much as possible.</p>

<p><em>Helpful Tip: Be sure to get a solid 6-8 hours of sleep per night. re:Invent is busy, there are always things to do, events to checkout, conversations to be had. We recommend being aware that it’s a long week, and you need to take care of yourself.</em></p>
<p><a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/tips-to-know-for-aws-re-invent"> Continue reading, &quot;4 Tips to Know For AWS re:Invent 2019&quot;</a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Who is HITRUST CSF Certified?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/who-is-hitrust-csf-certified"/>
    <id>https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/who-is-hitrust-csf-certified</id>
    <published>2019-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Grant Barrick</name>
    </author>
    <summary>The HITRUST certification is the highest Degree of Assurance a company can obtain. The HITRUST certification is increasingly required of business associates by some entities, such as health insurance providers, in order to ensure that business associates have the adequate security controls and protections in...</summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/oIZfM3B1MF5dZPZd1Zw8j/9dbe4304ea7baa3062f1f46a70cb5587/HITRUST_image_7_800x400_png-01.png?fit=crop&w=840&h=420&fm=jpg&q=40" width="420" alt="Who is HITRUST CSF Certified?"><p>The HITRUST certification is the highest Degree of Assurance a company can obtain. The HITRUST certification is increasingly required of business associates by some entities, such as health insurance providers, in order to ensure that business associates have the adequate security controls and protections in place to protect sensitive personal data.</p>
<p><strong>What does it mean to be HITRUST certified?</strong></p>

<p>Organizations that are HITRUST certified have gone through a <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/5-steps-to-hitrust-csf-certification/">rigorous certification process</a>, including a comprehensive <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/what-is-a-hitrust-csf-self-assessment">self-assessment</a> that assesses the security measures an organization has in place against the 156 controls and associated <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/what-are-hitrust-requirements">requirements of the HITRUST CSF</a>. These controls are grouped into 19 domains encompassing every facet of an organization’s security posture.</p>

<p>Controls are mapped to specifications and requirements of various regulations and frameworks, such as HIPAA, NIST, PCI, ISO, and others. Within each control, there are three levels of implementation with increasingly stringent requirements. The appropriate implementation level is based on the organization’s size and other risk factors, such as the number of health records the organization handles. Through a series of scoping questions, self-assessments are customized to the needs of the organization, resulting in a report that reveals areas in which the organization is compliant as well as non-compliance issues. From this assessment, organizations can create a corrective plan of action to address areas of non-compliance.</p>

<p>Those who are compliant with all applicable requirements move on to the next phase, a HITRUST CSF verification. In this phase, a third-party CSF assessor evaluates the organization’s assessment report and verifies it. Following verification, organizations seeking formal certification provide their assessment and verification, along with supporting information, which is reviewed and certified by HITECH.</p>

<p><strong>Who requires HITRUST certification?</strong></p>

<p>If your organization wants to do business with a covered entity or business associate that requires HITRUST certification, you’ll need to get HITRUST certified in order to work with that entity. For example, Anthem, Health Care Services Corp., Highmark, Humana, and UnitedHealth Group require their business associates to obtain HITRUST certified. Those that were not certified when the companies announced their decision had to obtain HITRUST certification within 24 months following the announcement.</p>

<p><strong>Why work with HITRUST CSF certified companies?</strong></p>

<p>For these insurance providers, as well as other companies that now make HITRUST certification a requirement, it’s a means of reducing third-party risk. Organizations that are HITRUST certified have demonstrated that they have effective security and privacy practices in place that are in line with strict healthcare industry regulations like HIPAA (as well as all the requirements of the HITRUST CSF). Because covered entities may be liable for their business associates’ or subcontractors’ violations, a HITRUST certification serves as an additional layer of regulatory protection for healthcare organizations. Thus, HITRUST certified companies have more opportunities to partner with healthcare organizations that must <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/academy/proving-hipaa-compliance/">meet stringent regulatory requirements, such as HIPAA</a>.</p>

<p><strong>Who is HITRUST CSF certified?</strong></p>

<p>Many people fail to realize that the Health Information Trust Alliance, known simply as HITRUST, is not a framework at all, but an organization comprised of healthcare industry leaders who regard information security as a fundamental component to data systems and exchanges. HITRUST, in partner with other technology and information security leaders, created and maintains the Common Security Framework (CSF). To become HITRUST CSF certified is regarded to be the pinnacle of compliance because:</p>

<ul>
  <li>There is no “secret sauce” to achieving HITRUST Certification. Simply put, certification is the result of intensive detailed preparation, exceedingly long hours, exceptionally talented individuals and being willing to learn every step of the way.</li>
  <li>The process is incredibly laborious and consumed time and resources beyond our wildest expectations, even with a team that has experienced HIPAA from all imaginable angles - technical auditors, mobile app vendors, clinicians, compliant platform vendors, etc.</li>
</ul>

<p>So how do you find out who is HITRUST CSF certified? Ask them for proof of certification.</p>

<p><strong>Why does HITRUST matter?</strong></p>

<p>As healthcare is becoming further dependent on evolving technologies to store and transmit data, cybersecurity and compliance have become a progressively emphasized, yet convoluted, matter. Navigating the tortuous labyrinth of federal, state, and third-party security mandates has become a feat that can quickly consume an organization’s resources. If that isn’t enough, getting through all the twists, turns and pitfalls to achieve compliance is only half the battle. Healthcare organizations and IT vendors must also prove their compliance to guarantee they are a trusted business partner. With all considerations, isn’t it obvious that the industry needs a system that is clear, standard, and secure? Thankfully, that’s exactly what HITRUST has established in order to put the trust in data security.</p>

<p>Healthcare is complex and can seem overwhelming, but it doesn’t have to be.  Whether you’re an industry professional or not, it is commonly felt that more time is spent understanding the healthcare conundrum versus solving it. That’s where Datica comes in. We have set out to investigate the underlying logic behind the astounding regulatory maze of this field and distill the information to those searching for it. Why spend your time mastering the problem when you could be discovering the innovative solutions?</p>

<p>For more information on HITRUST, check out the <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/academy/">Datica Academy</a> or <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/">Datica Blog</a>. Additional questions? <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/contact/">Contact one of our experts today</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/who-is-hitrust-csf-certified"> Continue reading, &quot;Who is HITRUST CSF Certified?&quot;</a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What Are HITRUST Requirements?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/what-are-hitrust-requirements"/>
    <id>https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/what-are-hitrust-requirements</id>
    <published>2019-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Grant Barrick</name>
    </author>
    <summary>The healthcare regulatory landscape is complex. The HITRUST CSF is a framework designed and created to streamline regulatory compliance. Companies that implement HITRUST CSF controls and strive to meet HITRUST requirements are better equipped for audits and lower their regulatory risk, but what are those...</summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/1ivdhkGTzfIzI1XtGOm9zG/9e0e2a46391afd6747bba25593fa889a/HITRUST_image_5_800x400_png-01.png?fit=crop&w=840&h=420&fm=jpg&q=40" width="420" alt="What Are HITRUST Requirements?"><p>The healthcare regulatory landscape is complex. The HITRUST CSF is a framework designed and created to streamline regulatory compliance through a common set of security controls mapped to the various standards to enable organizations to achieve and maintain compliance. Because the HITRUST CSF combines information from several regulatory standards, companies that implement HITRUST CSF controls and strive to meet HITRUST requirements are better equipped for audits and lower their regulatory risk.</p>
<p><strong>What does HITRUST mean?</strong></p>

<p>Many people fail to realize that the Health Information Trust Alliance, known simply as HITRUST, is not a framework at all, but an organization comprised of healthcare industry leaders who regard information security as a fundamental component to data systems and exchanges. In collaboration with information security, business technology, and healthcare leaders, HITRUST developed the <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/what-is-the-hitrust-framework/">HITRUST Common Security Framework</a> (CSF). The HITRUST CSF combines information from various standards, such as HIPAA, NIST, HITECH, and others, as a certified framework of controls mapped to these standards designed to help organizations achieve complete compliance.</p>

<p><em>**RELATED: **</em> *Get your complimentary copy of the condensed guide to the What, Why, and How of HITRUST; *<a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/guide/hitrust/"><em>HITRUST Explained for Everyone</em></a></p>

<p><strong>How many HITRUST controls are there?</strong></p>

<p>In contrast to HIPAA, the HITRUST CSF does not create broad buckets like Administrative and Security controls. The HITRUST CSF is divided into 19 different control domains:</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th> </th>
      <th> </th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>1. Information Protection Program</td>
      <td>11. Access Control</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>2. Endpoint Protection</td>
      <td>12. Audit Logging &amp; Monitoring</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>3.  Portable Media Security</td>
      <td>13. Education, Training and Awareness</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>4. Mobile Device Security</td>
      <td>14. Third Party Assurance</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>5. Wireless Security</td>
      <td>15. Incident Management</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>6. Configuration Management</td>
      <td>16. Business Continuity &amp; Disaster Recovery</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>7. Vulnerability Management</td>
      <td>17. Risk Management</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>8. Network Protection</td>
      <td>18. Physical &amp; Environmental Security</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>9. Transmission Protection</td>
      <td>19. Data Protection &amp; Privacy</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>10. Password Management</td>
      <td> </td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>In addition to the domains above, HITRUST also has 75 control objectives and 156 specific controls.</p>

<p><strong>What are the HITRUST requirements?</strong></p>

<p>For each of the 156 controls defined by HITRUST, three distinct implementation levels exist. Each implementation level builds on the one below - level 2 includes all of level 1 plus additional requirements, level 3 includes all of level 2 plus additional requirements. Therefore, level 3 has the most stringent set of requirements. Implementation levels in the CSF are determined for each organization based on their risk profile, accounting for aspects like the size of an organization and the number of stored health records. Most organizations have varied levels of implementation for their controls from level 1, 2, or 3.</p>

<p><strong>What is HITRUST compliance?</strong></p>

<p>HITRUST compliance means that an organization has implemented the appropriate requirements from the HITRUST CSF. HITRUST compliance doesn’t look the same for every organization. Because there are three levels of implementation, some organizations may have stricter requirements for certain controls, while other organizations can comply by implementing less-stringent requirements for the same controls.</p>

<p>To achieve HITRUST compliance, an organization must comply with the requirements set forth for the organization’s specific implementation level for each control across all HITRUST domains.</p>

<p><strong>Who requires HITRUST certification?</strong></p>

<p>Healthcare organizations and business associates that want to prove their compliance with HIPAA and other relevant regulations may conduct a Self-Assessment, or they may opt to become HITRUST CSF Validated or HITRUST CSF Certified. These three options are known as Degrees of Assurance, or levels of confidence that an organization meets all relevant HITRUST requirements.</p>

<p>A <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/what-is-a-hitrust-csf-assessment/">Self-Assessment</a> is the simplest Degree of Assurance to achieve. Using the HITRUST myCSF tool, organizations answer a series of questions to obtain a customized HITRUST assessment designed to evaluate the organization’s unique environment against the relevant compliance criteria. Through the assessment, areas for improvement are identified, as well as areas in which the organization is already compliant with HITRUST requirements.</p>

<p>Organizations that want additional compliance assurance following a Self-Assessment can obtain validation from a third-party CSF Assessor. This Degree of Assurance is known as CSF Validated.</p>

<p>Certification is the highest Degree of Assurance, and it requires the most effort and time to achieve. To obtain HITRUST CSF Certification, organizations send their validated assessment to HITRUST for review and certification. A HITRUST CSF Certification is valid for two years.</p>

<p><a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/5-steps-to-hitrust-csf-certification/">HITRUST certification</a> is increasingly important as more healthcare organizations, such as health insurance providers, are requiring their business associates to be CSF Verified or CSF Certified.</p>

<p><strong>Why does HITRUST matter?</strong></p>

<p>Well, as healthcare is becoming further dependent on evolving technologies to store and transmit data, cybersecurity and compliance have become a progressively emphasized, yet convoluted, matter. Navigating the tortuous labyrinth of federal, state and third-party security mandates has become a feat that can quickly consume an organization’s resources. If that isn’t enough, getting through all the twists, turns, and pitfalls to achieve compliance is only half the battle. Healthcare organizations and IT vendors must also <strong>prove</strong> their compliance to guarantee they are a trusted business partner. With all considerations, isn’t it obvious that the industry needs a system that is clear, standard, and secure? Thankfully, that’s exactly what HITRUST has established in order to put the <em>trust</em> in data security.</p>

<p>Healthcare is complex and can seem overwhelming, but it doesn’t have to be. Whether you’re an industry professional or not, it is commonly felt that more time is spent understanding the healthcare conundrum versus solving it. That’s where Datica comes in. We have set out to investigate the underlying logic behind the astounding regulatory maze of this field and distill the information to those searching for it. Why spend your time mastering the problem when you could be discovering the innovative solutions?</p>

<p>HITRUST isn’t easy, and it shouldn’t be. The experience we’ve gained as a company and the extensive testing of our technology brings great value to our customers. For more information on HITRUST, visit the <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/academy/">Datica Academy</a> or <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/">Datica Blog</a>. Additional questions? <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/contact/">Contact</a> one of our experts today.</p>
<p><a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/what-are-hitrust-requirements"> Continue reading, &quot;What Are HITRUST Requirements?&quot;</a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What is the HITRUST Framework?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/what-is-the-hitrust-framework"/>
    <id>https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/what-is-the-hitrust-framework</id>
    <published>2019-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Grant Barrick</name>
    </author>
    <summary>Most don’t realize HITRUST is not a framework at all, but an organization comprised of healthcare industry leaders. Let’s dive into the HITRUST CSF Framework, developed by the HITRUST organization, in partner with other technology and information security leaders.</summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/2lbo5kP4iYiQlowZHuFtjZ/8569f3411e46d1147693b4fcf4e67c15/HITRUST_image_4_800x400_png-01.png?fit=crop&w=840&h=420&fm=jpg&q=40" width="420" alt="What is the HITRUST Framework?"><p>Many people fail to realize that the Health Information Trust Alliance, known simply as <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/academy/what-is-hitrust/">HITRUST</a>, is not a framework at all, but an organization comprised of healthcare industry leaders who regard information security as a fundamental component to data systems and exchanges. The HITRUST organization, in partner with other technology and information security leaders, created and maintains the Common Security Framework (CSF), commonly known as the HITRUST CSF or the HITRUST framework.</p>
<p><strong>What is a common security framework?</strong></p>

<p>A common security framework is a set of policies and procedures that guide the development, implementation, and management of an organization’s security. Common security frameworks are often used to improve an organization’s security posture and to aid organizations in meeting regulatory requirements and maintain compliance with various regulations and standards.</p>

<p><strong>What is the HITRUST framework?</strong></p>

<p>The CSF, currently in version nine, is a certifiable framework that encompasses and harmonizes several other compliance frameworks and standards including HIPAA, HITECH, PCI, ISO/IEC, COBIT, NIST RMF and varying state requirements. According to the <a href="https://hitrustalliance.net/hitrust-csf-version-9-release-now-available/">HITRUST Alliance</a>, an interim release of HITRUST CSF v9.1 will incorporate the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). This interim release will also map the CSF’s privacy and security requirements to the AICPA Trust Services Criteria for Privacy.</p>

<p>By utilizing this framework, HITRUST has constructed a system infrastructure roadmap so that <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/the-truth-about-hitrust-and-why-it-should-become-the-industry-standard/">any healthcare organization</a> can certify that they securely create, access, store or transmit protected health information (PHI).</p>

<p><strong>What are the HITRUST domains?</strong></p>

<p>The CSF does not create broad buckets like Administrative and Security controls. The HITRUST framework is divided into 14 different control domains. The 14 HITRUST CSF domains include:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Information Protection Program</li>
  <li>Endpoint Protection</li>
  <li>Portable Media Security</li>
  <li>Mobile Device Security</li>
  <li>Wireless Security</li>
  <li>Configuration Management</li>
  <li>Vulnerability Management</li>
  <li>Network Protection</li>
  <li>Transmission Protection</li>
  <li>Password Management</li>
  <li>Access Control</li>
  <li>Audit Logging &amp; Monitoring</li>
  <li>Education, Training and Awareness</li>
  <li>Third Party Assurance</li>
  <li>Incident Management</li>
  <li>Business Continuity &amp; Disaster Recovery</li>
  <li>Risk Management</li>
  <li>Physical &amp; Environmental Security</li>
  <li>Data Protection &amp; Privacy</li>
</ol>

<p><strong>How many HITRUST controls are there?</strong></p>

<p>The HITRUST framework includes 156 controls and 75 control objectives. Each HITRUST control has three implementation levels: level one, level two, and level three. The <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/what-are-hitrust-requirements/">requirements</a> for each level build on the requirements of the previous level. Level two includes all the requirements of level one plus additional requirements, and level three includes all the requirements of level two plus additional requirements. Level three has the most stringent set of requirements with the largest number of controls and compliance requirements.</p>

<p>Within each domain there are one or more security objectives, or groups of controls that have a common purpose. Each control includes a control specification as well as implementation requirements for each of the three implementation levels. Implementation requirements address policies, practices, procedures, guidelines, or organizational structures.</p>

<p>Implementation requirements for each level of implementation are integrated from various regulatory sources and practice frameworks, such as HIPAA, NIST, PCI-DSS, and others. The appropriate implementation level for each specification is based on the organization’s organizational, system, and regulatory risk factors.</p>

<p><strong>What does it mean to be HITRUST certified?</strong></p>

<p>Organizations that want to prove compliance with regulations such as HIPAA may choose to become HITRUST Certified. HITRUST certification indicates that an organization meets all requirements for the applicable HITRUST controls at the appropriate implementation level. It’s a several-step process that begins with a <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/what-is-a-hitrust-csf-assessment/">HITRUST CSF Self-Assessment</a> which is then verified by a third-party CSF Assessor. The results of the self-assessment and third-party verification are then sent to HITRUST for certification. HITRUST certification is issued for two years. HITRUST certification is costly, but more organizations are pursuing certification as a growing number of providers and other organizations are requiring their business associates to be certified.</p>

<p><strong>Why does HITRUST matter?</strong></p>

<p>As healthcare is becoming further dependent on evolving technologies to store and transmit data, cybersecurity and compliance have become a progressively emphasized, yet convoluted, matter. Navigating the tortuous labyrinth of federal, state, and third-party security mandates has become a feat that can quickly consume an organization’s resources. If that isn’t enough, getting through all the twists, turns and pitfalls to achieve compliance is only half the battle. Healthcare organizations and IT vendors must also <strong>prove</strong> their compliance to guarantee they are a trusted business partner. With all considerations, isn’t it obvious that the industry needs a system that is clear, standard, and secure? Thankfully, that’s exactly what HITRUST has established in order to put the <em>trust</em> in data security.</p>

<p>Healthcare is complex and can seem overwhelming, but it doesn’t have to be. Whether you’re an industry professional or not, it is commonly felt that more time is spent understanding the healthcare conundrum versus solving it. That’s where Datica comes in. We have set out to investigate the underlying logic behind the astounding regulatory maze of this field and distill the information to those searching for it. Why spend your time mastering the problem when you could be discovering the innovative solutions?</p>

<p>For more information on HITRUST, check out the <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/academy/">Datica Academy</a> or <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/">Datica Blog</a>. Additional questions? <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/contact/">Contact</a> one of our experts today.</p>
<p><a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/what-is-the-hitrust-framework"> Continue reading, &quot;What is the HITRUST Framework?&quot;</a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>HIPAA vs HITRUST</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/hipaa-vs-hitrust"/>
    <id>https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/hipaa-vs-hitrust</id>
    <published>2019-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Grant Barrick</name>
    </author>
    <summary>HITRUST and HIPAA are two critical topics in healthcare, but do you know how they differ? Let’s break it down and explore additional resources to learn more.</summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/1rlPtxTjGnLaHYuWav69h7/56c68da1d46ec749c72122b8b99206ff/HITRUST_image_3_800x400_png-01.png?fit=crop&w=840&h=420&fm=jpg&q=40" width="420" alt="HIPAA vs HITRUST"><p>Healthcare is complex and can seem overwhelming, but it doesn’t have to be.  Whether you’re an industry professional or not, it is commonly felt that more time is spent understanding the healthcare conundrum versus solving it. That’s where Datica comes in. We have set out to investigate the underlying logic behind the astounding regulatory maze of this field and distill the information to those searching for it. Why spend your time mastering the problem when you could be discovering the innovative solutions?</p>
<p><strong>What does HITRUST mean?</strong></p>

<p>Many people fail to realize that the Health Information Trust Alliance, known simply as <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/academy/what-is-hitrust/">HITRUST</a>, is not a framework at all, but an organization comprised of healthcare industry leaders who regard information security as a fundamental component to data systems and exchanges.</p>

<p>The HITRUST organization, in partner with other technology and information security leaders, created and maintains the Common Security Framework (CSF). HITRUST is not a new set of standards. The HITRUST CSF® is a system that helps organizations comply with HIPAA and other regulations such as PCI, NIST, and ICO through a detailed, yet flexible and efficient approach for regulatory and compliance management. The most widely used security framework in the U.S. healthcare industry today, the HITRUST CSF is continually updated and improved. An interim release of HITRUST CSF v9.1 will incorporate the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and map the CSF’s privacy and security requirements to the AICPA Trust Services Criteria for Privacy, according to the <a href="https://hitrustalliance.net/hitrust-csf-version-9-release-now-available/">HITRUST Alliance</a>.</p>

<p><strong>What does HIPAA mean?</strong></p>

<p>The Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA) is United States legislative act that was signed into law in August, 1996. In 2013, HIPAA was expanded with the HIPAA Omnibus Rule to implement additional guidelines in accordance with the guidelines set forth in the HITECH Act. HIPAA outlines requirements for healthcare organizations and their business associates related to ensuring the security of sensitive patient data.</p>

<p><strong>What is the HITRUST Common Security Framework?</strong></p>

<p>The HITRUST CSF maps the CSF controls to specific HIPAA standards and specifications. Many specifications are mapped to multiple CSF controls. Each CSF control has multiple levels with varying requirements, so that organizations can implement the most relevant requirements for each control based on systems, organizational considerations, and regulatory risk factors.</p>

<p>Organizations wanting to comply with HITRUST have three options, known as Degrees of Assurance:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Self-Assessment: Companies can perform a self-assessment using the myCSF tool. This assessment helps to identify areas in compliance with HITRUST as well as areas for improvement.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>CSF Validated: This is a step often taken after an organization has completed the self-assessment and implemented corrective actions to rectify any non-compliance issues identified. A third-party, HITRUST-approved CSF Assessor verifies the information gathered through the assessment with an onsite visit. HITRUST issues a Validated Report after reviewing the validated assessment.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>CSF Certified: This Degree of Assurance requires the most time and effort. It’s a step above CSF Validated, with HITRUST reviewing and certifying the organization’s information and the CSF Assessor’s validation, after which a HITRUST CSF Certification is granted for a period of two years.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p><strong>What is the difference between HITRUST and HIPAA?</strong></p>

<p>HITRUST and HIPAA are both two hot topics in healthcare but what is the difference?</p>

<ul>
  <li>HITRUST builds on HIPAA. It takes HIPAA, a non-standardized and non-prescriptive compliance framework, and creates a standardized compliance framework, assessment, and <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/5-steps-to-hitrust-csf-certification/">certification process</a> for the healthcare industry.</li>
  <li>HITRUST “harmonizes” HIPAA with other compliance frameworks such as PCI and NIST. HITRUST also adapts requirements for certification to the risks of an organization based on organizational, system, and regulatory factors.</li>
  <li>As opposed to HIPAA, which has defined penalties for security breaches, the enforcement of HITRUST is dependent on the healthcare industry itself, typically covered entities like hospitals and payers, requiring HITRUST CSF Certification of vendors.</li>
  <li>Having been through both HIPAA audits and a Certified CSF Assessment, it is safe to say that HITRUST CSF Certification is a much more rigorous process, with a higher burden of proof put on the organization trying to achieve certification, than a HIPAA audit.</li>
  <li>Achieving HITRUST CSF Certification requires significantly more time, effort, and resources than a HIPAA audit. Being HITRUST CSF Certified should be seen as a more significant badge for security and compliance than completing a HIPAA audit.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>HITRUST vs. HIPAA</strong></p>

<p>HITRUST vs. HIPAA is not an either-or consideration. Because HIPAA is a set of standards, and the HITRUST CSF provides a prescriptive set of controls that meet the requirements of not only HIPAA, but other security standards such as PCI and NIST. As such, HITRUST is a valuable resource for risk management and compliance for organizations that handle sensitive data. Rather than a HITRUST vs. HIPAA scenario, the two go hand in hand.</p>

<p>It’s not possible for healthcare organizations to become HIPAA-certified, as there is no official certification process or accreditation. An external audit is the best way to ensure HIPAA compliance. When partnering with third-party organizations, covered entities have business associates sign a Business Associate Agreement that’s essentially a promise that they’ve implemented the right security controls to protect sensitive data. As a certifiable framework with controls mapped to every HIPAA standard and specification, HITRUST CSF certification provides a more reliable and consistent way for covered entities to ensure that their business associates are, in fact, compliant. Several major healthcare payors already require their business associates to comply with the HITRUST CSF. Certification adds a dose of confidence and a layer of trust.</p>

<p><strong>Why is HITRUST important?</strong></p>

<p>Why does HITRUST matter? Well, as healthcare is becoming further dependent on evolving technologies to store and transmit data, cybersecurity and compliance have become a progressively emphasized, yet convoluted, matter. Navigating the tortuous labyrinth of federal, state, and third-party security mandates has become a feat that can quickly consume an organization’s resources. If that isn’t enough, getting through all the twists, turns and pitfalls to achieve compliance is only half the battle. Healthcare organizations and IT vendors must also <strong>prove</strong> their compliance to guarantee they are a trusted business partner.</p>

<p>With all considerations, isn’t it obvious that the industry needs a system that is clear, standard, and secure? Thankfully, that’s exactly what HITRUST has established in order to put the <em>trust</em> in data security.</p>

<p>HITRUST isn’t easy, and it shouldn’t be. The experience we’ve gained as a company and the extensive testing of our technology brings great value to our customers.</p>

<p>For more information on HITRUST, check out the <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/academy/">Datica Academy</a> or <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/">Datica Blog</a>. Additional questions? <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/contact/">Contact</a> one of our experts today.</p>
<p><a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/hipaa-vs-hitrust"> Continue reading, &quot;HIPAA vs HITRUST&quot;</a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What is a HITRUST CSF Self-Assessment?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/what-is-a-hitrust-csf-assessment"/>
    <id>https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/what-is-a-hitrust-csf-assessment</id>
    <published>2019-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Grant Barrick</name>
    </author>
    <summary>Here’s what you need to know about the HITRUST CSF Self-Assessment, how it works, and how to determine if the self-assessment option is sufficient for your organization.</summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/1YX4VkAanrDumcWnjCQXDh/39e2504852d819bd51baceea2caf0ac2/HITRUST_image_6_800x400_png-01.png?fit=crop&w=840&h=420&fm=jpg&q=40" width="420" alt="What is a HITRUST CSF Self-Assessment?"><p>Organizations that want to demonstrate their compliance with HITRUST have a few options with increasing levels of assurance, known as Degrees of Assurance. The first and simplest level is the HITRUST CSF Self-Assessment. Here’s what you need to know about the HITRUST CSF Self-Assessment, how it works, and how to determine if the self-assessment option is sufficient for your organization.</p>
<p><strong>What is HITRUST CSF?</strong></p>

<p>Many people fail to realize that the Health Information Trust Alliance, known simply as HITRUST, is not a framework at all, but an organization comprised of healthcare industry leaders who regard information security as a fundamental component to data systems and exchanges. The HITRUST organization, in partner with other technology and information security leaders, created and maintains the <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/what-is-the-hitrust-framework/">Common Security Framework</a> (CSF).</p>

<p>The HITRUST CSF harmonizes standards such as HIPAA, NIST, PCI, and ISO to create a single reference with required controls mapped to each standard. There are <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/what-are-hitrust-requirements/">19 control domains and 156 specific controls</a> overall. Within each control, there are three different implementation levels, allowing organizations to build a customized compliance program based on the size of the company, the number of health records stored, and other risk factors.</p>

<p><strong>What is a HITRUST CSF assessment?</strong></p>

<p>Organizations can gauge their compliance to the HITRUST CSF by performing many types of assessments. There are a few types of HITRUST CSF assessments, but what is a HITRUST self-assessment specifically?</p>

<ul>
  <li>HITRUST CSF self-assessment is simply an organization completing the CSF through HITRUST’s myCSF tool on its own. It is valuable, typically as an internal tool, because it’s done with a standardized framework.</li>
  <li>External parties don’t verify any aspects of this type of assessment. It results in a HITRUST issued CSF Self Assessment Report.</li>
  <li>Every HITRUST assessment begins with gathering information on the entity being assessed. This information is used to gauge the organization, system, and regulatory requirements for the assessment to determine the risk and scope.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>What is myCSF?</strong></p>

<p>HITRUST’s myCSF tool is a SaaS information risk management platform providing assessment tools for organizations to achieve and maintain regulatory compliance with international, federal, and state regulations, including HIPAA, NIST, ISO, and other standards.</p>

<p>With myCSF, organizations can perform CSF assessments and risk assessments, manage corrective action plans, and measure against industry benchmarks. Organizations can tailor assessments to their specific needs by selecting broad regulatory factors or specific control requirement statements. After answering a series of scoping questions, organizations receive a customized assessment based on factors such as organization size and the number of health records it manages. The CSF assessment results identify the areas in which the organization meets CSF requirements based on the specific implementation level and reveals areas for improvement to achieve full compliance. Using the myCSF tool, organizations can quickly identify non-compliance issues and create targeted corrective action plans to speed the path to compliance.</p>

<p><strong>What is a HITRUST assessment report?</strong></p>

<p>After completing a self-assessment through myCSF, organizations receive a HITRUST Self Assessment report. The HITRUST assessment report reveals areas for improvement and areas the organization already has the necessary controls in place (based on the organization’s implementation level for each control) for compliance. A report-only option is available for myCSF, which provides access to the tool for 90 days and starts at $2,500 (costs are based on the organization’s net income). A yearly subscription is also available, which starts at about $10,000, for organizations that prefer continuous access for ongoing auditing and assessment. Corporate and premier subscriptions are also available for large organizations and enterprises.</p>

<p><strong>How do I get HITRUST certified?</strong></p>

<p>The HITRUST CSF Self-Assessment is the lowest Degree of Assurance; however, it’s also a starting point for organizations that want to achieve a higher Degree of Assurance, such as CSF Verified or <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/5-steps-to-hitrust-csf-certification/">CSF Certified</a>. If either of these Degrees of Assurance are pursued, the CSF assessment is a required first step in the process.</p>

<p><strong>Why does HITRUST matter?</strong></p>

<p>As healthcare is becoming further dependent on evolving technologies to store and transmit data, cybersecurity and compliance have become a progressively emphasized, yet convoluted, matter. Navigating the tortuous labyrinth of federal, state, and third-party security mandates has become a feat that can quickly consume an organization’s resources. If that isn’t enough, getting through all the twists, turns and pitfalls to achieve compliance is only half the battle. Healthcare organizations and IT vendors must also <strong>prove</strong> their compliance to guarantee they are a trusted business partner. With all considerations, isn’t it obvious that the industry needs a system that is clear, standard, and secure? Thankfully, that’s exactly what HITRUST has established in order to put the <em>trust</em> in data security.</p>

<p>Healthcare is complex and can seem overwhelming, but it doesn’t have to be. Whether you’re an industry professional or not, it is commonly felt that more time is spent understanding the healthcare conundrum versus solving it. That’s where Datica comes in. We have set out to investigate the underlying logic behind the astounding regulatory maze of this field and distill the information to those searching for it. Why spend your time mastering the problem when you could be discovering the innovative solutions?</p>

<p>HITRUST isn’t easy, and it shouldn’t be. The experience we’ve gained as a company and the extensive testing of our technology brings great value to our customers.</p>

<p>For more information on HITRUST, check out the <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/academy/">Datica Academy</a> or <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/">Datica Blog</a>. Additional questions? <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/contact/">Contact</a> one of our experts today.</p>
<p><a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/what-is-a-hitrust-csf-assessment"> Continue reading, &quot;What is a HITRUST CSF Self-Assessment?&quot;</a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Solving Healthcare Compliance in a Post-Cloud World</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/solving-healthcare-compliance-in-a-post-cloud-world"/>
    <id>https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/solving-healthcare-compliance-in-a-post-cloud-world</id>
    <published>2019-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ryan Rich</name>
    </author>
    <summary>In a post-cloud world, balancing innovation and compliance will be key for healthcare companies. In this blog, we explore the critical factors for compliance.</summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/43BLF5MYRIVFk0BvdPxmmA/7a0011566dd445a5fcae8a58255b0214/Cloud_Computing_BW_2_copy.png?fit=crop&w=840&h=420&fm=jpg&q=40" width="420" alt="Solving Healthcare Compliance in a Post-Cloud World"><p><em>Know the complete compliance state of your cloud environment</em></p>

<p>Disruption brought on by the cloud is inevitable. However, for the highly-regulated healthcare industry, the burden of compliance often blocks the innovation necessary to compete.</p>
<p>Let’s explore some of the critical factors behind this. Developers building healthcare software are increasingly leveraging cloud managed services (computer resources including storage, compute power, container orchestration, big data tools, etc.) packaged as APIs or interactive products delivered via software. This has helped to substantially improve developer experience, but securing this infrastructure has also now become their responsibility. Many have limited understanding of the privacy, security, and compliance implications of using the different services that cloud providers offer.
As on-premise hardware is increasingly moved to the cloud, enterprises have handed off more responsibilities—completely changing how compliance should be implemented, measured, monitored, and managed. Risk aversion for cloud-based technologies in healthcare is often rooted in the complexity of understanding where liabilities actually exist between the data center and cloud service provider customer, and who is responsible for ensuring the protection of PHI and when.</p>

<p>For example, HIPAA–the primary regulatory framework in the U.S. healthcare industry–kicks in when a digital health product handles PHI. When that digital health product stores, processes, or transmits PHI, HIPAA asserts rules on how it should handle a multitude of security, privacy, and policy procedures, called “controls.” Demonstrating that a company and its digital health product meets all of those controls is how it can call itself compliant.</p>

<p>The problem explodes with the sheer number of cloud services and instances (usually in the thousands). Developers must often reinvent the wheel of mapping compliance controls in totality to a new managed service. As a result, enterprises are increasingly worried about the risk in moving sensitive data to the cloud; the lack of transparency, in particular with shared responsibility, is a major roadblock to cloud adoption.</p>

<h2 id="simplifying-cloud-compliance">Simplifying Cloud Compliance</h2>

<p>These issues are driving the need for a more robust approach to compliance. One of the most difficult aspects of compliance is knowing that the proper configuration state is mapped to a specific control. 
Cloud compliance management technologies can help by providing a constant understanding of the precise state of cloud environments. A cloud compliance management system can evaluate the implementation of managed services against critical compliance controls, check configuration states on a continual basis, and track those states in a historical data model across popular HIPAA-eligible cloud provider services, reshaping the way that organizations operate in the cloud and speeding adoption for healthcare.
Furthermore, to be most effective, a cloud compliance management system should be uniquely designed to fit the specific requirements of the industry. For healthcare compliance, a tool should:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Have built-in policies and procedures designed to meet the needs of HIPAA, GDPR, and GxP.</li>
  <li>Include a continuous monitoring tool to focus on checking specific compliance controls.</li>
  <li>Help developers with the most important part of compliance: proving it.</li>
</ul>

<p>In short, the transformational shift of the cloud can only be successfully enabled if organizations rethink their fundamental approach to compliance.</p>

<p>Interested in learning more? <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/innovation/solving-healthcare-compliance-in-a-post-cloud-world-wp/">Download our new Datica white paper on cloud compliance in healthcare.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/solving-healthcare-compliance-in-a-post-cloud-world"> Continue reading, &quot;Solving Healthcare Compliance in a Post-Cloud World&quot;</a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Support for Amazon S3 and EC2 Now Available in Latest Release of Datica Monitor Cloud Compliance Management System</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/support-for-amazon-s3-ec2-available"/>
    <id>https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/support-for-amazon-s3-ec2-available</id>
    <published>2019-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ryan Rich</name>
    </author>
    <summary>In this blog, we walkthrough our latest release of Datica Monitor and its added cloud compliance support capabilities for Amazon’s S3 and EC2 products.</summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/5zMfl0VlUnr00lAAWMsk1P/615f3b6b996c3c0966fb534753c6eb08/iStock-1000849912_copy.jpg?fit=crop&w=840&h=420&fm=jpg&q=40" width="420" alt="Support for Amazon S3 and EC2 Now Available in Latest Release of Datica Monitor Cloud Compliance Management System"><p>Following the recent release of complete cloud compliance management for Amazon Relational Database Service (RDS) and Amazon ElastiCache, Datica is proud to announce support for Amazon Simple Storage Service (Amazon S3) and Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) in the latest release of its Datica Monitor product.</p>
<p>As explored in our previous <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/complete-cloud-compliance-amazon-rds-elasticache/">blog post</a>, most modern cloud environments are a constellation of managed services, enabling developers to deploy, manage, and scale cloud infrastructure at will. Amazon S3 and EC2 are two of the most well-established and widely deployed managed services today.</p>

<p>EC2 provides secure, resizable compute capacity. It is the preeminent general compute service and is commonly deployed in combination with other managed services, as it essentially acts as an engine to power them. For example, developers commonly use Amazon EC2 to get an application or web server online very quickly. EC2 enables users to obtain and configure capacity with minimal effort, as well as to rapidly scale capacity up or down as computing requirements vary, making web-scale cloud computing easier for developers.</p>

<p>Amazon S3 provides a secure, scalable object storage infrastructure. It enables any amount of data to be protected, stored, and retrieved from anywhere, for a wide range of use cases including big data analytics, enterprise applications, mobile applications, backup and recovery, archival, and more.</p>

<p>As the healthcare industry continues to increasingly adopt the cloud, patient data—specifically protected health information (PHI)—is more important than ever to help power the new wave of applications that will enable healthcare organizations to refine care delivery, improve health outcomes, realize new solutions for treatment, and much more. Along with this influx of new and critical data comes a substantial obligation to safeguard that information, while planning for improved accessibility, scalability, and performance within already tight budgets.</p>

<p>This is an example of where a managed service such as Amazon S3 is a natural fit. As the industry standard for object storage, Amazon S3 is commonly used in healthcare applications to store extremely sensitive PHI object files such as telemedicine videos, radiology images and MRIs, doctor’s audio files, and much more. 
When any digital health product stores, processes, or transmits PHI, regulations such as HIPAA dictate how it should handle security, privacy, and policy procedures. A digital health product becomes compliant when it can successfully demonstrate that all those controls have been met. 
However, understanding where liabilities exist, and who is responsible for ensuring the protection of PHI at what point in time, is complex. It is increasingly the developer’s responsibility—completely changing how compliance is implemented, measured, monitored, and managed.</p>

<p>Managing compliance requires a continuous understanding of the precise configuration state of cloud environments. Datica Monitor can help. The Datica Monitor cloud compliance management system evaluates the implementation of managed services against critical compliance controls, checking configuration states on a continual basis and tracking those states in a historical data model across the most widely-used HIPAA-eligible cloud services—including Amazon RDS, Amazon Elasticache, Amazon S3, and Amazon EC2. Until now, the only option for solving this was services—throwing IT teams at it, which is difficult to scale.</p>

<p>With Datica Monitor, developers can now plug in popular managed services and get real-time compliance configuration data, providing unparalleled visibility into the compliance state. Datica Monitor provides continuous monitoring, attestation tools, risk and incident details, remediation guidance, and historical reporting. For example, the tool runs eight checks for Amazon S3 that span 41 different compliance requirements. For Amazon EC2, it runs nine checks that span 29 different compliance requirements.</p>

<p>A unique new feature included in the latest release of Datica Monitor is inline remediation documentation. When an issue or check failure is present, e.g. Amazon S3 encryption is not on, the remediation documentation that is external in competitive solutions is included directly inline within the Monitor console. This prescriptive approach ensures that failures/issues are reported as well as the information needed to remedy the error.</p>

<p>As a result, Datica Monitor will remove many of the existing barriers for healthcare developers and gives them the freedom and flexibility to use popular managed services—reshaping the way organizations operate in the cloud.</p>

<p>Datica Monitor is live and available now - <a href="/monitor">click here</a> to learn more. Keep an eye on Datica’s blog to learn about more new releases coming soon!</p>
<p><a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/support-for-amazon-s3-ec2-available"> Continue reading, &quot;Support for Amazon S3 and EC2 Now Available in Latest Release of Datica Monitor Cloud Compliance Management System&quot;</a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Complete Cloud Compliance for Amazon RDS and Amazon ElastiCache</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/complete-cloud-compliance-amazon-rds-elasticache"/>
    <id>https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/complete-cloud-compliance-amazon-rds-elasticache</id>
    <published>2019-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ryan Rich</name>
    </author>
    <summary>Being able to show complete cloud compliance with managed services like Amazon RDS and ElastiCache can be a challenge, unless you’re using Datica Monitor.</summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/4ymQhIaBXVdgyQQD97dGNf/d778c826c72471d3c4eff63cf6cceb13/RDS_Elasticache_Blog.jpeg?fit=crop&w=840&h=420&fm=jpg&q=40" width="420" alt="Complete Cloud Compliance for Amazon RDS and Amazon ElastiCache"><p>Many cloud environments today are a constellation of managed services, enabling developers to deploy, manage and scale cloud infrastructure at will. While tremendously beneficial, securing this infrastructure has also now become the developer’s responsibility—completely changing how compliance is implemented, measured, monitored, and managed.</p>
<p>Developers often must reinvent the wheel of mapping compliance controls in totality to a new managed service. For example, when a digital health product stores, processes, or transmits protected health information (PHI), HIPAA how it should handle a multitude of security, privacy, and policy procedures, called “rules.” Demonstrating that a digital health product meets all those controls is how it becomes compliant. However, understanding where liabilities exist between the data center and a cloud service provider customer, and who is responsible for ensuring the protection of PHI at what point in time, is increasingly complex.</p>

<h3 id="cloud-compliance-management-can-help">Cloud Compliance Management Can Help</h3>

<p>The missing piece for managing compliance in the cloud is a continuous understanding of the precise configuration state of cloud environments. A cloud compliance management system (CCMS) can evaluate the implementation of managed services against critical compliance controls, check configuration states on a continual basis, and track those states in a historical data model across popular HIPAA-eligible cloud services.</p>

<p>Datica is introducing support for two of the most widely used managed services, Amazon Relational Database Service (RDS) and Amazon ElastiCache, in the latest release of its new product, Datica Monitor. With Datica Monitor, developers can plug in managed services and get real-time compliance configuration data, providing unparalleled visibility into the compliance state.</p>

<p>Databases are the basic architecture of any application—and simultaneously one of the most complicated to manage. Amazon RDS makes it simple to set up, operate, and scale a relational database in the cloud, while automating many time-consuming tasks such as hardware provisioning, database setup, backups, and more. This enables developers to focus on their application.</p>

<p>Amazon ElastiCache is the premier in-memory data store managed service offered by Amazon Web Services (AWS). It enables users to seamlessly deploy, run, and scale popular open source, such as Redis-compatible in-memory data stores, helping developers to build or improve the performance of data-intensive applications by retrieving data from high throughput and low latency in-memory data stores.</p>

<p>Once the decision has been made to use either Amazon RDS or Amazon ElastiCache in a healthcare application, the challenge of ensuring HIPAA compliance emerges. AWS provides security and monitoring tools that can be configured to comply with HIPAA; but these tools are not pre-configured for HIPAA. Datica Monitor will alert the user to exactly what they need to do to configure the service for HIPAA compliance, and continuously monitor it.</p>

<p>A simplified scenario is that a database containing PHI cannot be publicly available. If there are hundreds of instances of Amazon RDS running in an environment and even one is misconfigured to be publicly available, there are serious potential consequences such as a breach—along with all the associated cost implications, brand damage and more. However, with Datica Monitor continuously monitoring the environment, if that situation was to occur, an alert would be generated along with the prescriptive steps needed to remediate the issue.</p>

<p>We believe that Datica Monitor has the potential to reshape the way that organizations operate in the cloud. The secure implementation is up to the user so they can pick the tools they want to use. The system will then check to ensure it is compliant on a continual basis, giving them the peace of mind that everything is configured properly. As a result, Datica Monitor removes many existing barriers for healthcare developers and gives them the freedom and flexibility to adopt popular managed services, bringing consumer rate adoption to healthcare cloud environments.</p>

<p>Datica Monitor is live and available now. You can sign up <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/monitor">here</a>, or if you have questions you can reach out to us here. Keep an eye on Datica’s blog to learn about new and existing releases coming soon!</p>
<p><a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/complete-cloud-compliance-amazon-rds-elasticache"> Continue reading, &quot;Complete Cloud Compliance for Amazon RDS and Amazon ElastiCache&quot;</a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Health IT in the Cloud: Why It’s Inevitable and What You Need to Know Now</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/health-it-in-the-cloud-why-its-inevitable-and-what-you-need-to-know-now"/>
    <id>https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/health-it-in-the-cloud-why-its-inevitable-and-what-you-need-to-know-now</id>
    <published>2019-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dave Levin, MD</name>
    </author>
    <summary>A brief recap from our “Health IT in the Cloud” presentation at Catalyst HTI in Denver.</summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/7g8oRPZZi9VZLgqWAUYmUi/2f3eb0f1e67abd77d9dc69c7a8f116ad/Banner-FAQ.jpg?fit=crop&w=840&h=420&fm=jpg&q=40" width="420" alt="Health IT in the Cloud: Why It’s Inevitable and What You Need to Know Now"><p><em>Reflections from Datica Hosted Lunch + Learn</em></p>

<p>Recently, Datica had the pleasure of hosting a Lunch + Learn panel discussion on health IT in the cloud at Catalyst HTI, a healthcare innovation ecosystem bringing together relevant stakeholders with the healthcare industry to accelerate innovation and drive real, lasting change.</p>
<p>The session, “Health IT in the Cloud: Why It’s Inevitable and What You Need to Know Now,” was moderated by Dave Levin, MD, Chief Medical Officer at Datica, and panelists included Travis Good, MD, co-founder and CTO at Datica, as well as Rob Valuck, CEO of OpiSafe, and CJ Singh, CTO of Healthgrades.</p>

<p>For years, cloud computing has been a game-changer to the way data is exchanged and stored, significantly advancing the promise of technology, and impacting the way we go about our lives on a day-to-day basis. Now that cloud adoption has moved into the healthcare industry, it’s essential that we know how to meet the challenges and complexity of health data exchange and compliance to enable a data-driven future for healthcare in the cloud.</p>

<p>We had a strong turnout for the session (in fact, setting the highest attendance record at Catalyst HTI, even before a long holiday weekend!), which illustrates how strong the interest is in this topic. During the session, the audience was truly engaged while we provided an overview of the driving factors that make health IT in the cloud inevitable, explored practical challenges and opportunities with this approach, and described what steps organizations can take to get started.</p>

<p>Of particular interest during the session was a discussion around where exactly the evolution of healthcare in the cloud stands. There continues to be a mix of on-premises and cloud environments in health systems. ISVs have to decide if they should go with the cloud from scratch or figure out how to “port” an existing app to cloud. Many agreed that simply putting a healthcare app in the cloud is of little use if it can’t get data in/out.</p>

<p>As we discussed the continued need to migrate to the cloud in today’s data-driven world, the concept of the “onramp to the cloud” came up. Because data from electronic health records is already being integrated to the cloud and software-as-a-service apps, we’re already on the onramp. However, because of the complexities involved with not only integrating data, but also doing so in a compliant manner, we haven’t yet moved beyond that.</p>

<p>There will continue to be many challenges faced by innovators during this transition. At Datica, we are here to help. Contact us for help solving your unique compliance and data integration challenges. Together, we can accelerate healthcare’s transformation to a data-driven future.</p>
<p><a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/health-it-in-the-cloud-why-its-inevitable-and-what-you-need-to-know-now"> Continue reading, &quot;Health IT in the Cloud: Why It’s Inevitable and What You Need to Know Now&quot;</a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>50 Best HIPAA-Compliant Cloud Storage Solutions</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/50-best-hipaa-compliant-cloud-storage-solutions"/>
    <id>https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/50-best-hipaa-compliant-cloud-storage-solutions</id>
    <published>2019-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Grant Barrick</name>
    </author>
    <summary>Our list of the 50 best HIPAA-compliant cloud storage solutions will help you find the best solution with the functionality and features for your business.</summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/3Y5HYoTzdoru3nIkKR1GE4/d2a99d3c83bbeedb10ce82c96abcad8c/50_HIPAA_Compliant_Storage.jpg?fit=crop&w=840&h=420&fm=jpg&q=40" width="420" alt="50 Best HIPAA-Compliant Cloud Storage Solutions"><p>Over the last few years, cloud storage has risen both in popularity and effectiveness. The convenience of cloud computing is undeniable, allowing users to access data, apps, and services from any location with an Internet connection. It’s no surprise that businesses across every industry are embracing cloud storage.</p>
<p>For healthcare providers and related organizations, though, it’s a bit more complicated. Healthcare providers and other businesses that handle sensitive personal health information (PHI) must <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/what-are-the-hipaa-cloud compliance-options-for-healthcare/">comply with strict regulations</a> such as the <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/guide/hipaa/">Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act</a> (HIPAA) when storing, collecting, or transmitting PHI. If you want to store your sensitive data in the cloud, the solution you choose must sign a <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/academy/business-associate-agreements/">Business Associate Agreement</a> (BAA) – a document that lays out its compliance with all HIPAA regulations, providing assurance that the company will appropriately safeguard all PHI it creates or receives on your organization’s behalf.</p>

<p>Since there are so many options on the market, we’ve created a list of the 50 best HIPAA-compliant cloud storage solutions to help you find the best solution with the functionality and features your business needs. While features and pricing vary, the options listed here make cloud storage a breeze, even for companies that must comply with HIPAA. <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/backup/">AWS Backup</a>, for instance, makes it incredibly easy to automate and centralize the backup of data across all AWS services in the cloud and on-premise using the <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/storagegateway/">AWS Storage Gateway</a>. AWS provides several HIPAA-compliant cloud storage solution services covered by their BAA, and you can view the complete list <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/compliance/hipaa-eligible-services-reference/">here</a> – including non-storage services. </p>

<p><em><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> At Datica, we don’t fully endorse any company that claims to be HIPAA compliant without having the HITRUST CSF certification to prove it. When selecting cloud storage solutions, be sure to do due diligence when researching and evaluating your options.</em></p>

<p>Please note that the following cloud storage solutions are organized alphabetically and are not rated or ranked in any way.</p>

<p>Find part 2 of the 50 Best HIPAA-Compliant Cloud Storage Solutions <a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/50-best-hipaa-compliant-cloud-storage-solutions-part-2">here</a>.</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="synchttpsen4synccom-4synchttpstwittercom4sync">1. <a href="https://en.4sync.com/">4Sync</a> (<a href="https://twitter.com/4Sync">@4Sync</a>)</h3>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/Y5ZUkLkbZAbWkNY2Dn7ze/9234a7cd5a72d2642478c9e229cf2787/4Sync.jpg" alt="4Sync" /></p>

<p>4Sync is a trustworthy online storage platform for photos, documents, and other assets. 4Sync makes it easy to access your data from any location on smartphones, tablets, or computers, all from an intuitive user interface. It offers 1 TB of online storage space initially for all users, with the ability to purchase any amount of traffic as needed. In addition to being an encryption-enabled service, this solution safeguards all your data against human errors, equipment failure, or disasters to make your data security a priority.</p>

<p><strong>Key Features:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Files are easy to synchronize, access, and share at any time</li>
  <li>It provides 1 TB of online storage space</li>
  <li>Unlimited bandwidth</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Cost:</strong> $8.25/month or $99/year</p>

<h3 id="adrivehttpwwwadrivecomenterprisecloudstorage">2.<a href="http://www.adrive.com/enterprise/cloudStorage">ADrive</a></h3>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/6wm9mbcUvUKJGYF5uuiE2a/d6855b8a6818b67e7effd8b8b084775e/ADrive.jpg" alt="ADrive" /></p>

<p>The ADrive cloud storage solution liberates your system administrators from the tasks and costs associated with the operation of on-premise storage systems. This solution is readily available for immediate integration into your already existing infrastructure. ADrive deploys enterprise-class storage systems and guarantees 99.9% uptime. In addition to providing data protection and backups, this solution offers the option to mirror your data to various locations for historic snapshotting and read-only cache functionality.</p>

<p><strong>Key Features:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Secured with VPN encryption</li>
  <li>On-demand scalability</li>
  <li>Optional mirroring to various data centers for extra protection</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Cost:</strong> Contact for a quote</p>

<h3 id="amazon-elastic-block-storehttpsawsamazoncomebs-awscloudhttpstwittercomawscloud">3. <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/ebs/">Amazon Elastic Block Store</a> (<a href="https://twitter.com/awscloud">@awscloud</a>)</h3>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/3Al7HAqyXT5AL6LeSZ9mVD/36264951e33c5fa3f72a45934c46d16d/Amazon_Elastic_Block_Store.jpg" alt="Amazon Elastic Block Store" /></p>

<p>This high performance and easy-to-use block storage solution is often used with the Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud for transaction-intensive workloads and high throughput. Amazon EBS allows for the deployment of a wide range of workloads, such as enterprise applications, big data analytics engines, media workflows, and file systems. EBS volumes are easy to replicate within Availability Zones and can be scaled to data volumes reaching petabytes. EBS is also designed to be secure for data compliance, and newly created EBS volumes can be encrypted with a single account setting.</p>

<p><strong>Key Features:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Virtually unlimited scale</li>
  <li>Performance for any workload</li>
  <li>Secure for data compliance</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Cost:</strong> $0.1 per GB/month of provisioned storage (free tier also available with 30GB storage, volume pricing also available).</p>

<h3 id="amazon-elastic-file-systemhttpsawsamazoncomefs-awscloudhttpstwittercomawscloud">4. <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/efs/">Amazon Elastic File System</a> (<a href="https://twitter.com/awscloud">@awscloud</a>)</h3>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/2F9UfnUJDG7AiHrf1kYBjy/1e063c7eeeaf5f892fec104b1fcbc758/Amazon_Elastic_File_System.jpg" alt="Amazon Elastic File System" /></p>

<p>Amazon EFS provides a simple, elastic, scalable file system for Linux-based workloads for use with on-premise resources and AWS Cloud services. This solution is designed to scale on-demand to petabytes without interrupting any applications, automatically shrinking and growing as you remove and add files. Amazon EFS is designed to offer parallel shared access to hundreds of Amazon EC2 instances, enabling all applications to achieve high throughput and low latency. Since it’s a fully managed service, it doesn’t require changes to your existing tools and applications.</p>

<p><strong>Key Features:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Elastic and scalable</li>
  <li>Shared access</li>
  <li>Storage classes and lifecycle management</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Cost:</strong> $0.3 per GB/month of provisioned storage (Standard Storage), $0.045 per GB/month (Infrequent Access Storage), $0.01 per GB-transferred (Infrequent Access Requests), $6 per MBs/month (Provisioned Throughput).</p>

<h3 id="amazon-fsx-for-lustrehttpsawsamazoncomfsxlustre-awscloudhttpstwittercomawscloud">5. <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/fsx/lustre/">Amazon FSx for Lustre</a> (<a href="https://twitter.com/awscloud">@awscloud</a>)</h3>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/7tJV2u4iphFx8h0hbcmCYK/fa1345d3fab6102921890bfd8933791e/Amazon_FSx_for_Lustre.jpg" alt="Amazon FSx for Lustre" /></p>

<p>Amazon FSx for Lustre offers a high-performance system that’s optimized for the fast processing of workloads like financial modeling, high-performance computing, electronic design automation, and machine learning. Amazon FSx works natively with Amazon S3, making it incredibly easy for you to process cloud data sets with a high-performance file system. You can also use Amazon FSx as a standalone high-performance file system to burst all workloads from on-premise to cloud. There are no upfront software or hardware costs, minimum commitments, or additional fees.</p>

<p><strong>Key Features:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Seamless access to your data</li>
  <li>Storage for high-performance workloads</li>
  <li>High throughput and low latencies</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Cost:</strong> $0.14 per GB/month of provisioned storage</p>

<h3 id="amazon-fsx-for-windows-file-serverhttpsawsamazoncomfsxwindows-awscloudhttpstwittercomawscloud">6. <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/fsx/windows/">Amazon FSx for Windows File Server</a> (<a href="https://twitter.com/awscloud">@awscloud</a>)</h3>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/k5dHi99sqtHct4J5LgxjX/9639ec25f171cdb8c542d72a16004651/Amazon_FSx_for_Windows_File_Server.jpg" alt="Amazon FSx for Windows File Server" /></p>

<p>Amazon FSx for Windows File Server offers a fully managed native Microsoft Windows file system so that you can easily migrate your Windows-based applications to AWS. It also provides shared file storage with all the features and compatibility needed for Windows-based applications, including full support for Distributed File System (DFS), Active Directory (AD) integration, and Windows NTFS. Amazon FSx utilizes SSD storage to provide the fast performance users and applications demand, with consistent sub-millisecond latencies and high levels of throughput.</p>

<p><strong>Key Features:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Native Windows compatibility</li>
  <li>Fully managed service</li>
  <li>Broadly accessible since it supports the SMB protocol</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Cost:</strong> $0.13 per GB/month (Storage capacity), $2.2 per MBps-month (Throughput capacity), and $0.05 per GB/month (Backup storage).</p>

<h3 id="amazon-s3-glacierhttpsawsamazoncomglacier-awscloudhttpstwittercomawscloud">7. <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/glacier/">Amazon S3 Glacier</a> (<a href="https://twitter.com/awscloud">@awscloud</a>)</h3>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/6w6rHDr0lXQPYuixdzRxeH/23424dc0d2e2eff00a059d17b22915f1/Amazon_S3_Glacier.jpg" alt="Amazon S3 Glacier" /></p>

<p>Amazon S3 Glacier is a durable, secure, and low-cost cloud storage class for long-term backup and data archiving. This solution is designed to offer 99.9% durability while providing comprehensive compliance and security capabilities that aid in meeting even the most stringent regulatory requirements. You can store data for as low as $1 per terabyte per month as well as enjoy three data retrieval options that fit any use case.</p>

<p><strong>Key Features:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Storage management and monitoring</li>
  <li>Access management and security</li>
  <li>Makes transferring large amounts of data easy</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Cost:</strong> $0.004 per GB/month (All storage)</p>

<h3 id="apptixhttpwwwapptixcomcloud-solutionsaspx-apptixhttpstwittercomapptix">8. <a href="http://www.apptix.com/cloud-solutions.aspx">Apptix</a> (<a href="https://twitter.com/apptix">@Apptix</a>)</h3>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/2T51kNnQFUslSCx0UD11K6/e90d7858ac060c9fd30828d661120057/Apptix.jpg" alt="Apptix" /></p>

<p>Apptix provides several cloud-based infrastructure, collaboration, and communication solutions. The specialized compliance and security services make it possible for you to fulfill all regulatory requirements and protect data in the cloud. With Apptix cloud infrastructure, you can enjoy the benefits of secure, reliable infrastructure without the attention or expense needed to maintain costly on-premise data storage solutions.</p>

<p><strong>Key Features:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Disaster Recovery as a service</li>
  <li>Server backup and servers on demand</li>
  <li>Virtual Desktop as a service</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Cost:</strong> Contact for a quote</p>

<h3 id="asigrahttpswwwasigracom-asigrahttpstwittercomasigra">9. <a href="https://www.asigra.com/">Asigra</a> (<a href="https://twitter.com/asigra">@Asigra</a>)</h3>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/5HY5gElh2Tig3JMSnayM4u/8e2be2905cffff8ef990a0874261c257/Asigra.jpg" alt="Asigra" /></p>

<p>If you’re looking to manage all your backup data with a single solution, Asigra is a great option. With this platform, you know that you’re fully secure and compliant, as well as always prepared for disaster recovery. Whether you want a private, public, or hybrid cloud environment, Asigra offers it all. You can also mass-deploy backup configurations to various cloud application users at a time for consistent protection. Better yet, new users are automatically detected for inclusion.</p>

<p><strong>Key Features:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Restore at any granularity</li>
  <li>Mass deployment and customer onboarding</li>
  <li>Continuous data protection</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Cost:</strong> Contact for a quote</p>

<h3 id="atlanticnethttpswwwatlanticnet-atlanticnethttpstwittercomatlanticnet">10. <a href="https://www.atlantic.net/">Atlantic.net</a> (<a href="https://twitter.com/AtlanticNet">@AtlanticNet</a>)</h3>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/4itDhBPXGpLh5yxTbTa6uK/eda0ae26167c0b91ed1664adf427416c/Atlantic.net.jpg" alt="Atlantic.net" /></p>

<p>Atlantic.net cloud storage is fully audited and complies with all HIPAA and HITECH requirements, providing data sharing and storage for growing organizations. This cloud storage solution is great for mission-critical applications without compromising security, reliability, and speed. It’s also useful for file transfer, storing large datasets, online storage, and health records that need encryption. You can choose between a dedicated and a cloud storage platform, and with Atlantic.net’s full suite of HIPAA-compliant storage solutions, you will enjoy the best-in-class managed cloud services.</p>

<p><strong>Key Features:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Firewall and intrusion prevention service</li>
  <li>Robust log management</li>
  <li>Fully-encrypted Virtual Private Network</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Cost:</strong> Contact for a quote</p>

<h3 id="aws-backuphttpsawsamazoncombackup-awscloudhttpstwittercomawscloud">11. <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/backup/">AWS Backup</a> (<a href="https://twitter.com/awscloud">@awscloud</a>)</h3>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/6AN6ZNaQrfbQgDCtGVU8ty/f54832e3274ac2314336a4a10918b512/AWS_Backup.jpg" alt="AWS Backup" /></p>

<p>This fully managed backup service makes it incredibly easy for you to centralize and automate data backups across multiple AWS services in the cloud and on-premise using AWS Storage Gateway. With this solution, you can centrally configure your backup policies as well as monitor backup activity for AWS resources. AWS backup consolidates and automates backup tasks that were previously done on a service-by-service basis, eliminating the need for manual processes. It also offers a fully managed policy-based backup solution, simplifying overall backup management while helping you meet all regulatory backup compliance requirements.</p>

<p><strong>Key Features:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Centralized backup management</li>
  <li>Automated backup scheduling</li>
  <li>Backup data encryption</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Cost:</strong>  $0.01 - $0.10 per GB/month</p>

<h3 id="aws-storage-gatewayhttpsawsamazoncomstoragegateway-awscloudhttpstwittercomawscloud"><a href="https://aws.amazon.com/storagegateway/">12. AWS Storage Gateway</a> (<a href="https://twitter.com/awscloud">@awscloud</a>)</h3>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/5CH1uMQG5PVYpabyDIFEHK/6ef182bf034c7afc4e48d61523e98817/AWS_Storage_Gateway.jpg" alt="AWS Storage Gateway" /></p>

<p>This hybrid cloud storage service provides on-premise access to unlimited cloud storage. Customers utilize AWS Storage Gateway to simplify storage management and cut the costs for key hybrid cloud storage use instances. This service provides three gateway types – Volume Gateway, Tape Gateway, and File Gateway – which seamlessly connect your on-premise applications to cloud storage. Your applications then connect to this service through a hardware gateway appliance or virtual machine using standard storage protocols.</p>

<p><strong>Key Features:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Standard storage protocols</li>
  <li>AWS integrated</li>
  <li>Optimized and secured data transfer</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Cost:</strong> $0 – $0.023 per GB/month</p>

<h3 id="backblazehttpswwwbackblazecom-backblazehttpstwittercombackblaze">13. <a href="https://www.backblaze.com/">BackBlaze</a> (<a href="https://twitter.com/backblaze">@backblaze</a>)</h3>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/HG42gxbSalZAaxjcnCHiy/c269f2bc81b3600ca81eb9012368d5d9/Backblaze.jpg" alt="Backblaze" /></p>

<p>Backblaze is a cloud storage solution that offers the same for a fraction of the price compared to other solutions. With this service, you only pay for what you need – no tiers, minimums, or fine print. Besides backing up and archiving data, Backblaze lets you manage and store large amounts of media files and build your apps’ storage to save time and money. Their pricing model applies to all regions, and you receive 10 GB of free storage on your first sign up.</p>

<p><strong>Key Features:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>No complicated pricing tiers</li>
  <li>Pay for what you store</li>
  <li>No access delays and no hidden retrieval fees</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Cost:</strong> $0.005 - $0.01 per GB/month</p>

<h3 id="boxhttpswwwboxcom-boxhttpstwittercombox">14. <a href="https://www.box.com/">Box</a> (<a href="https://twitter.com/Box">@Box</a>)</h3>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/3hLv7CnY58YmyQjaAJYgwZ/06ccd2640319f4dc1e5414f25e58259d/Box.jpg" alt="Box" /></p>

<p>This cloud storage solution is similar to Dropbox but offers more options. Specifically, Box enables providers to view, share, and store DICOM images. It includes several features that ease the sharing and management of digital documents. It also has desktop clients for Mac OSX and Windows, although Box does not provide a Linux client. With one business plan, you can create an account for up to three users, and this includes unlimited storage and advanced security and user reporting.</p>

<p><strong>Key Features:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Online office third-party integration</li>
  <li>Desktop clients and integration</li>
  <li>DICOM image viewer</li>
</ul>

<p>__Cost: __ $5.80 - $28.70 per user/month</p>

<h3 id="carbonitehttpswwwcarbonitecom-carbonitehttpstwittercomcarbonite"><a href="https://www.carbonite.com/">15. Carbonite</a> (<a href="https://twitter.com/carbonite">@Carbonite</a>)</h3>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/51Hq37x1W6pKKWOZRwZFuQ/fa4ccb66d29484a8754c8e090c83fde1/Carbonite.jpg" alt="Carbonite" /></p>

<p>For personal cloud backup, Carbonite provides an easy-to-install and configure platform that runs automatically. It also includes backup software and unlimited cloud storage for one computer. While you can easily recover files from any web-connected device, it is also available for external hard drives and other forms of external storage. For business cloud backup, Carbonite offers advanced encryption both at-rest and in-flight.</p>

<p><strong>Key Features:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Personal and business cloud backup with 24/7 support</li>
  <li>Advanced encryption at-rest and in-flight</li>
  <li>Available for external hard drives</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Cost:</strong> $6 - $50 per month</p>

<h3 id="carecloudhttpswwwcarecloudcomhipaa-compliant-cloud-storage-carecloudhttpstwittercomcarecloud">16. <a href="https://www.carecloud.com/hipaa-compliant-cloud-storage/">CareCloud</a> (<a href="https://twitter.com/CareCloud">@CareCloud</a>)</h3>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/669wxc5bQtu4HslBDfbT1P/9931a0a87834f54ba5ae1bbfbbd29fd9/Carecloud.jpg" alt="Carecloud" /></p>

<p>CareCloud’s cloud-based software is HIPAA compliant, meeting security standards for data storage and transmission. This solution uses industry-preferred encryption products to protect data during transmission and a commercial-grade firewall to prevent unauthorized access. Information is stored in secure data centers and maintained with the highest security standards. And although CareCloud hosts and protects all your data, you still retain full control.</p>

<p><strong>Key Features:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Physical data storage</li>
  <li>You control your data</li>
  <li>Client-side security</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Cost:</strong> $279+ per provider/month</p>

<h3 id="centurylinkhttpswwwcenturylinkcombusinesshybrid-it-cloudcloud-storagehtml-centurylinkhttpstwittercomcenturylink">17. <a href="https://www.centurylink.com/business/hybrid-it-cloud/cloud-storage.html">CenturyLink</a> (<a href="https://twitter.com/CenturyLink">@CenturyLink</a>)</h3>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/1iwwAIYhfGS1Aqo1v92xMC/21f006ea8daf6c11f697d21449b49728/CenturyLink.jpg" alt="CenturyLink" /></p>

<p>From disaster recovery to standard block storage, CenturyLink offers an array of flexible solutions which scale with the magnitude of your workloads. CenturyLink provides enterprise-grade object storage while their cloud servers manage and store files in a fault-tolerant, highly scalable datastore. They also boast a multi-cloud data recovery platform that protects production systems and enterprise data to avoid the substantial cost of IT downtime.</p>

<p><strong>Key Features:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Cloud disaster recovery as a service</li>
  <li>Object cloud storage</li>
  <li>Block storage</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Cost:</strong> $0.05 per GB/month</p>

<h3 id="comodohttpswwwcomodocom-comododesktophttpstwittercomcomododesktop">18. <a href="https://www.comodo.com/">Comodo</a> (<a href="https://twitter.com/comododesktop">@comododesktop</a>)</h3>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/2U2LJALvlUE7RtWEpXrxdp/fe6571a55bf66c84a106e59575296b25/Comodo.jpg" alt="Comodo" /></p>

<p>Comodo cloud is an open service that is currently being used as an online storage and authentication service globally. Comodo provides smart profiles that allow one-click backups, command-line prompts for administrator-level configurations, and scheduled backups with multiple options. File versioning is also available for regularly updated documents, and the online drive lets you edit documents and watch videos directly from storage. Comodo ensures your files are encrypted before being uploaded to the cloud and are stored in an encrypted form to prevent deciphering or sniffing.</p>

<p><strong>Key Features:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Smart profiles</li>
  <li>Command line and scripting</li>
  <li>Versioning capabilities</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Cost:</strong> $8 per month or $80 per year</p>

<h3 id="crashplanhttpswwwcrashplancomen-us-crashplanhttpstwittercomcrashplan">19. <a href="https://www.crashplan.com/en-us/">CrashPlan</a> (<a href="https://twitter.com/crashplan">@crashplan</a>)</h3>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/2CNj6HiMl0sqeFy7cXwaeh/431cdd12b1dddd0e1b31b61562c0e41f/CrashPlan.jpg" alt="CrashPlan" /></p>

<p>CrashPlan makes it fast and easy to protect your files on devices, including external hard drives and file servers, so you never have to worry about losing business-critical data. With this platform, there are no size restrictions or additional fees for space utilization. In addition to giving you control over how long your deleted files are stored, CrashPlan also offers 256-bit AES data encryption, configurable security settings, and a BAA to support all your HIPAA compliance needs.</p>

<p><strong>Key Features:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Automatic data protection</li>
  <li>Unlimited storage</li>
  <li>Ransomware recovery</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Cost:</strong> $10 per month per computer</p>

<h3 id="dattohttpswwwdattocomcontinuitynascloud-backup-storage-and-recovery-dattohttpstwittercomdatto">20. <a href="https://www.datto.com/continuity/nas/cloud-backup-storage-and-recovery">Datto</a> (<a href="https://twitter.com/datto">@datto</a>)</h3>

<p>Datto provides businesses with SOC2 and HIPAA compliance, enabling streamlined cloud storage while adhering to the highest privacy standards. Thanks to Datto’s centralized management, you can consistently monitor, track, and manage devices, users, storage, and activity in a single platform. Plus, Datto’s simple and quick file restoration process protects you from data loss and corruption, so you’re always one step ahead of ransomware and other threats.</p>

<p><strong>Key Features:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Centrally managed and configured</li>
  <li>Reduce backup time with smart delta backups</li>
  <li>Fast and easy file restore</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Cost:</strong> Contact for a quote</p>

<h3 id="degoohttpsdegoocom-degoobackuphttpstwittercomdegoobackuplangen">21. <a href="https://degoo.com/">Degoo</a> (<a href="https://twitter.com/degoobackup?lang=en">@DegooBackup</a>)</h3>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/5q6IwA7VHAJXXBxrIb9q1Q/884c3023cdf993a03e67b8c5206dcfdd/Degoo.jpg" alt="Degoo" /></p>

<p>With 10 TB of premium cloud storage, Degoo offers a “secure bank vault” that prevents anyone but you from accessing your files. In addition to files being encrypted with a passphrase only known to you, you can connect and access your cloud services in a single account. Files are also encoded into chunks and then spread out to various data centers around the world so that no single data center has sufficient data to access your entire file. There are no file size limitations, and you can share files securely with end-to-end encryption.</p>

<p><strong>Key Features:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Storage replication</li>
  <li>Zero-knowledge encryption</li>
  <li>Unlimited file size with no reduction in quality</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Cost</strong>: $3.00 - $9.99 per month (free plan also offered with 100 GB storage)</p>

<h3 id="dropboxhttpswwwdropboxcomlandingdbv2-dropboxhttpstwittercomdropbox">22. <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/?landing=dbv2">Dropbox</a> (<a href="https://twitter.com/Dropbox">@Dropbox</a>)</h3>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/2ibnYDLDAKEawlsMaBhN3J/0f218ad96623530bd99895e9ad95c066/Dropbox.jpg" alt="Dropbox" /></p>

<p>Dropbox has two cloud storage plans, with the business plan being the best option for those requiring HIPAA compliance. With a central platform to access and share your files, Dropbox will help your business grow while giving you complete control over crucial information and user activity. For enhanced security, Dropbox offers advanced 256-bit encryption as well as two-factor authentication. Although there are paid plans, this platform also offers a 30-day trial period for anyone wanting to test the waters.</p>

<p><strong>Key Features:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>256-bit AES encryption security</li>
  <li>Efficient syncing</li>
  <li>Automatic organization and backup</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Cost:</strong> $12.50 - $20 per user per month (starting at 3 users)</p>

<h3 id="ebox-enguard-boxhttpswwwenguardcomebox-enterpriseguardhttpstwittercomenterpriseguard">23. <a href="https://www.enguard.com/ebox">eBox (EnGuard Box)</a> (<a href="https://twitter.com/enterpriseguard">@enterpriseguard</a>)</h3>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/jOePfyARPi9qA4kYhpgB4/0aa18a3acbcce86f853bc8ed0e0e9a01/EnGuard_Box.jpg" alt="EnGuard Box" /></p>

<p>EnGuard Box is an easy-to-use, secure file sharing, sync, and endpoint backup solution for businesses and individuals. This HIPAA-compliant cloud solution can also function as Network Attached Storage (NAS) for users in multiple locations (on PC and Mac), with the eBox Drive for on-the-go access for Android and iOS devices. You can send and receive files of up to 2 GB with TLS encryption for data-in-transit and email encryption for data-at-rest.</p>

<p><strong>Key Features:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Cloud drive mapping</li>
  <li>Automatic file locking</li>
  <li>Work with files offline</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Cost:</strong> $5 - $10 per user per month</p>

<h3 id="egnytehttpswwwegnytecom-egnytehttpstwittercomegnyte">24. <a href="https://www.egnyte.com/">Egnyte</a> (<a href="https://twitter.com/Egnyte">@Egnyte</a>)</h3>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/3z6AWDNnQ38ar4hdIgM2Fb/fce00f634fa06ce6340ef42787375190/Egnyte.jpg" alt="Egnyte" /></p>

<p>Egnyte is a business-focused solution that unifies storage, data management, and file access to provide a standard, efficient way to manage centralized content.  An intuitive self-service experience enables IT to protect business content while maintaining regulatory compliance, Egnyte uses machine learning to locate and classify potentially sensitive information across multiple repositories, reducing the risk of a data breach while protecting data stored on-premises and in the cloud. The platform’s backup aspect lets you set it up as a hybrid system for redundancy and ultimate protection, and custom branding features allow you to use a personalized URL for your portal and interface, complete with your company’s logo.</p>

<p><strong>Key Features:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Comprehensive file support</li>
  <li>File transmissions are encrypted using 256-bit AES over SSL</li>
  <li>Automatic and continual synchronization between online files and local copies</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Cost:</strong> $8 - $20 per employee per month</p>

<h3 id="filecloudhttpswwwgetfilecloudcom-getfilecloudhttpstwittercomgetfilecloud">25. <a href="https://www.getfilecloud.com/">FileCloud</a> (<a href="https://twitter.com/getfilecloud">@getfilecloud</a>)</h3>

<p><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/6oY31TY17PxTu6oWIBaH9v/0916e5b836190ecfc850f831d2dcdebc/FileCloud.jpg" alt="FileCloud" /></p>

<p>This document management solution allows enterprises and organizations to share, sync, and backup their files on the cloud. It integrates easily with different applications for greater efficiency while making it easy to access data from any location. FileCloud uses various levels of protection, including anti-virus scanning, two-factor authentication, and at-rest and in-transit encryption, all of which provide end-to-end data security.</p>

<p><strong>Key Features:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>FileCloud hosted or self-hosted options</li>
  <li>Integration with the existing servers</li>
  <li>Content management and collaboration</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Cost:</strong> $4.20 - $15 per user per month (billed yearly)</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="part-2-of-the-50-best-hipaa-compliant-cloud-storage-solutionshttpsdaticacomblog50-best-hipaa-compliant-cloud-storage-solutions-part-2"><a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/50-best-hipaa-compliant-cloud-storage-solutions-part-2">Part 2 of the 50 Best HIPAA-Compliant Cloud Storage Solutions</a></h2>

<p><a href="https://datica-2019.netlify.app/blog/50-best-hipaa-compliant-cloud-storage-solutions"> Continue reading, &quot;50 Best HIPAA-Compliant Cloud Storage Solutions&quot;</a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
