<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Datica Health Press Releases</title>
  <id>https://datica.com/press/</id>
  <subtitle>Datica Health Press Releases and Media Coverage</subtitle>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/press/" type="text/html"/>
  <link rel="self" href="https://datica.com/press/feed.xml" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <author>
    <name>Datica Health, Inc.</name>
  </author>
  <icon>https://images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/32chySeS5qMcCWeAwEyCQM/cf6c8d516896bc66f0c67d142869360a/datica-icon-256.png?w=48</icon>
  <logo>https://images.contentful.com/189dvqdsjh46/4SwayIJ5AcCe4iCU820mQs/504b8e57eacc0d81032d01ace96bc622/datica_logo__black.png?w=150</logo>
  <updated>2019-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <entry>
    <title>Datica to Introduce Cloud Compliance Solution at AWS re:Invent</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/press/datica-to-introduce-cloud-compliance-solution-at-aws-re-invent"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/press/datica-to-introduce-cloud-compliance-solution-at-aws-re-invent</id>
    <published>2019-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Grant Barrick</name>
    </author>
    <summary>At AWS re:Invent 2019, Datica will introduce a fully managed, end-to-end cloud compliance solution enables developers to scale with a flexible and automated mix of technology and services.</summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><em>A Fully Managed, End-to-End Cloud Compliance Solution Enables Developers to Scale with a Flexible and Automated Mix of Technology and Services</em></p>

<p><strong>Minneapolis, MN</strong> – <strong>November 21, 2019</strong> – <a href="https://datica.com/">Datica</a>, provider of a complete, cloud-based platform that mitigates the complexity and risk of integrating and using healthcare data in the cloud, today announced that it will introduce its new cloud compliance solution at AWS re:Invent in Las Vegas.</p>

<p>Over 84 percent of hospitals and health plans use the HITRUST CSF framework (<a href="https://hitrustalliance.net/content/uploads/2016/02/HITRUST-CSF-AWAC-Cyber-Insurance-PR_final-for-wire.pdf">HITRUST Alliance</a>). Increasingly, these same entities are making it a requirement that the health IT vendors they work with must be HITRUST certified. Designed to solve the many complexities of compliance on the cloud, Datica’s Cloud Compliance solution offers end-to-end cloud managed services that enable developers to scale and grow at their own pace – without having to worry about HIPAA compliance or HITRUST certification.</p>

<p>Developing healthcare applications on the cloud requires data integration and compliance with complicated rules and controls. Often, developers face restrictions on availability of services, or are required to use certain technology systems. With Datica, developers are free to use any Amazon Web Services (AWS) they want – without any constraints or requirements. By creating a secure cloud environment on AWS, Datica already has the controls and configurations in place to ensure security and compliance with HIPAA standards and achieve HITRUST certification.</p>

<p>“Datica Cloud Compliance reshapes the way health care operates in the cloud,” said Ryan Rich, Chief Product Officer at Datica. “It removes existing barriers for healthcare developers and gives them the freedom to adopt sophisticated cloud services, enabling scale and automation previously unavailable to health IT developers.”</p>

<p>Datica understands that cloud compliance isn’t a one-size-fits all challenge. Solving these challenges requires various services to meet developer needs, wherever they are on the road to healthcare compliance. With Datica’s Cloud Compliance solution, developers can use any AWS HIPAA-eligible services, leverage compliance and security controls already set in place, access common developer tools, and integrate patient data seamlessly in the cloud.</p>

<p>Are you looking to take the stress out of cloud compliance? Click <a href="https://datica.com/events/aws-re-invent-19/">here</a> to schedule a meeting during the AWS re:Invent conference or stop by our booth, #3820.</p>

<p><strong>About Datica</strong></p>

<p><a href="https://datica.com/">Datica</a> provides the most complete, cloud-based platform available to accelerate healthcare’s transformation to a data-driven future. It achieves this by mitigating the complexity and risk of integrating and using health data in the cloud.</p>

<p>Leveraging patient data and context has become essential to deliver effective digital health solutions that improve outcomes and reduce costs. However, healthcare regulations create several integration and compliance issues. To solve these challenges, Datica simplifies and speeds the development process for those that need end-to-end security and scalability to integrate health data from any source into the cloud. For more information, visit <a href="https://datica.com">https://datica.com</a>.</p>
]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>HIStalk Interviews Jeremy Pierotti, CEO, Datica</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/press/histalk-interviews-jeremy-pierotti-ceo-datica"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/press/histalk-interviews-jeremy-pierotti-ceo-datica</id>
    <published>2019-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Grant Barrick</name>
    </author>
    <summary>Our CEO, Jeremy Pierotti, sits down with HIStalk to chat about the future of the cloud and what it means for health IT vendors, EHR vendors, and the healthcare industry as a whole.</summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Jeremy covers a wide range of topics in sitting down with HIStalk. Get a sneak preview of the types of questions here and head over to the interview!</p>

<ul>
  <li>What is driving the need for cloud-based services?</li>
  <li>How will the ‘new’ Datica solve the challenges of data exchange and cloud compliance in healthcare?</li>
  <li>What part will the 21st Century Cares Act play in accelerating healthcare’s adoption of the cloud?</li>
  <li>How are cloud partnerships with AWS and Google Cloud changing the speed of cloud adoption for healthcare organizations?</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="histalk-interviews-jeremy-pierotti-ceo-daticahttpshistalk2com20190916histalk-interviews-jeremy-pierotti-ceo-datica"><a href="https://histalk2.com/2019/09/16/histalk-interviews-jeremy-pierotti-ceo-datica/">HIStalk Interviews Jeremy Pierotti, CEO, Datica</a></h4>
]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Datica Introduces New Health Data Integration Platform</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/press/datica-introduces-new-health-data-integration-platform"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/press/datica-introduces-new-health-data-integration-platform</id>
    <published>2019-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Grant Barrick</name>
    </author>
    <summary>Announcing the only any-to-any solution combining healthcare data integration and compliance, enabling the development of secure, HIPAA-compliant healthcare applications in the cloud.</summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><em>The Only Any-to-Any Solution Combining Healthcare Data Integration and Compliance, Enabling the Development of Secure, HIPAA-Compliant Healthcare Applications in the Cloud</em></p>

<p><strong>Minneapolis, MN – September 4, 2019</strong> – <a href="https://datica.com/">Datica</a>, provider of a complete, cloud-based platform that mitigates the complexity and risk of integrating and using healthcare data in the cloud, today introduced Integrate, its new health data integration platform. The industry’s first and only any-to-any solution that combines healthcare data integration with compliance, as well as a full set of services to ensure successful integration, its integration APIs work with any EHR, any available data, in any format.  It results in the most complete and scalable solution for those who collect, store, manage and share protected health information (PHI) in the cloud.</p>

<p>Healthcare’s adoption of the cloud is on the rise, which has resulted in an increased need to use patient data to power the next wave of innovative healthcare applications. However, the complexity of healthcare data exchange and compliance has created significant hurdles to bringing advanced digital health solutions to market. Datica Integrate now offers a complete solution to solve the complexities of both healthcare data interoperability and compliance, helping to streamline the development and management of HIPAA-compliant, cloud-based digital health solutions. As a result, previously cumbersome development processes become frictionless, resulting in enhanced, secure solutions at lower cost and with greater speed to market.</p>

<p>Integrate is scalable and centralized, enabling seamless, secure data exchange with any EHR, real-time access to patient records, and the ability to both push and pull data. It brings together two industry-leading solutions, Datica’s Compliant Managed Integration and Emissary, into a single advanced solution as a result of the recent <a href="https://datica.com/press-release/sansoro-health-datica-announce-merger/">merger</a> between Datica Health, Inc. and Sansoro Health, Inc. The combined product enables users to code once to Datica’s advanced API, and connect with both open standards as well as custom end-points. Datica is also the only provider that enables connection to custom end-points, enabling a much richer data set and streamlined workflow.</p>

<p>“Developing healthcare applications in the cloud means overcoming key obstacles like compliance and integration - a big challenge for innovation teams that often prevents them from creating the breakthrough solutions healthcare needs,” said Dave Levin, MD, Chief Medical Officer at Datica. “Integrate removes the stress, risk and complexity of EHR integrations—without sacrificing PHI security—so our customers can focus on delivering exceptional solutions to today’s healthcare challenges.”</p>

<h3 id="about-datica">About Datica</h3>
<p><a href="https://datica.com/">Datica</a> evolved in 2019 when Datica Health, Inc. merged with <a href="https://datica.com/about">Sansoro Health</a>, Inc. The company now provides the most complete, cloud-based platform available to accelerate healthcare’s transformation to a data-driven future. It achieves this by mitigating the complexity and risk of integrating and using health data in the cloud.</p>

<p>Leveraging patient data and context has become essential to deliver effective digital health solutions that improve outcomes and reduce costs. However, healthcare regulations create a number of integration and compliance issues. To solve these challenges, Datica simplifies and speeds the development process for those that need end-to-end security and scalability to integrate health data from any source into the cloud. For more information, visit <a href="https://datica.com/">https://datica.com</a>.</p>
]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Datica CEO Jeremy Pierotti to Highlight the Complexity and Risk of Building Healthcare Applications in the Cloud at MedCity Invest Digital Health </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/press/ceo-jeremy-pierotti-highlight-complexity-risk-building-healthcare-applications-cloud"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/press/ceo-jeremy-pierotti-highlight-complexity-risk-building-healthcare-applications-cloud</id>
    <published>2019-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Jeremy Pierotti</name>
    </author>
    <summary>Datica CEO, Jeremy Pierotti, will be speaking at MedCity Invest Digital Health about the most effective approaches of a cloud compliance management system and how it should be uniquely designed to fit the specific requirements of the healthcare industry.</summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h2 id="who">Who</h2>

<p><a href="https://datica.com/">Datica</a> is the provider of a complete, cloud-based platform that mitigates the complexity and risk of integrating and using health data in the cloud. The company’s chief executive officer, Jeremy Pierotti, will <a href="https://events.medcitynews.com/invest-twincities/agenda/">lead a feature session</a> at <a href="https://events.medcitynews.com/invest-twincities/agenda/">MedCity Invest Digital Health</a> (formerly INVEST Twin Cities), an event for healthcare investors and startups in the digital health sector to network and connect. Attendees include innovative investors across the healthcare spectrum, prominent industry players and the most promising digital health startups offering innovative approaches will come together to try to solve some of healthcare’s greatest challenges.</p>

<h2 id="what">What</h2>

<p>Uniting to facilitate investment opportunities with the most innovative companies from the digital health sector, MedCity Invest Digital Health connects active investors with healthcare executives to transform health through technology. To support the innovators and developers working to enable data-driven healthcare in the cloud, Datica CEO Jeremy Pierotti will present the session, “The Complexity &amp; Risk of Building Healthcare Applications in the Cloud.” He will speak to the most effective approaches of a cloud compliance management system and how it should be uniquely designed to fit the specific requirements of the healthcare industry. This includes built-in policies and procedures designed to meet the needs of HIPAA, HITRUST, GDPR, and GxP; a continuous monitoring tool to focus on checking specific compliance controls; and how developers can prove compliance.</p>

<p>*For a media briefing please contact Kay Kelly at <a href="mailto:kay.kelly@svmpr.com">kay.kelly@svmpr.com</a>. *</p>

<h2 id="where">Where</h2>

<p>The Depot Renaissance Minneapolis Hotel, 225 3rd Avenue South Minneapolis, MN 55401</p>

<h2 id="when">When</h2>

<p>Tuesday, September 17, 2019. Jeremy is speaking from 4:50 PM CT – 5:10 PM CT. For the full conference schedule, <a href="https://events.medcitynews.com/invest-twincities/agenda/">please click here</a>.</p>

<h3 id="about-medcity-events">About MedCity Events</h3>

<p>MedCityNews.com is one of the fastest growing sites focused on B2B healthcare innovation, and producer of MedCity Events, dynamic and unique innovation-focused events that gather industry experts and innovators to address the challenges facing all of healthcare.</p>

<p>MedCity events include MedCity INVEST, focused on healthcare investing; MedCity CONVERGE, focused on healthcare convergence innovation; and MedCity ENGAGE, focused on innovation in patient engagement.</p>

<h2 id="about-datica">About Datica</h2>

<p><a href="https://datica.com">Datica</a> evolved in 2019 when Datica Health, Inc. merged with <a href="https://datica.com/about">Sansoro Health, Inc.</a> The company now provides the most complete, cloud-based platform available to accelerate healthcare’s transformation to a data-driven future. It achieves this by mitigating the complexity and risk of integrating and using health data in the cloud.</p>

<p>Leveraging patient data is essential to deliver effective digital health solutions that improve outcomes and reduce costs. However, healthcare regulations create a number of integration and compliance issues. To solve these challenges, Datica simplifies and speeds the development process for those that need end-to-end security and scalability to integrate health data from any source into the cloud. For more information, visit <a href="https://datica.com">https://datica.com</a>.</p>

<hr />

<p>__Media Contact: __</p>

<p>Kay Kelly
SVM Public Relations 
Kay.kelly@svmpr.com
401.490.9700</p>
]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Datica Chief Medical Officer Dave Levin to Discuss Effective Outcomes with Cloud-Based Health IT at Health 2.0 Conference</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/press/dave-levin-to-discuss-effective-outcomes-cloud-health-it-health-2-0"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/press/dave-levin-to-discuss-effective-outcomes-cloud-health-it-health-2-0</id>
    <published>2019-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dave Levin, MD</name>
    </author>
    <summary>At this year’s Health Conference 2.0, catch Datica Chief Medical Officer, Dave Levin, discussing effective outcomes with cloud-based health IT.</summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h2 id="who">Who</h2>

<p><a href="https://datica.com/">Datica</a> chief medical officer (CMO) Dave Levin, MD has been named <a href="https://www.h2fallcon.com/santa-clara/2019/session/datica-10-min-session">a feature speaker</a> at <a href="https://www.h2fallcon.com/santa-clara/2019">Health 2.0</a>, an annual conference that  emphasizes the revolutionary ideas and practical solutions that fuel healthcare technology. The company is a provider of a complete, cloud-based platform that mitigates the complexity and risk of integrating and using health data in the cloud. Event attendees include a full spectrum of early-stage tech, highly-vetted startups, top investors, policy-focused dialogues, and authentic provider perspectives.</p>

<h2 id="what">What</h2>

<p>As the leading market intelligence on new health technology companies, the 13th annual Health 2.0 conference will work to discover the next frontier of health technology. The event will showcase and catalyze innovations in healthcare that bring together the best minds, and resources for compelling panels, discussions and product demonstrations.</p>

<p>To support healthcare’s data-driven future in the cloud, Dave Levin will present the session, “Superior Outcomes Require Cloud-Based Health IT,” highlighting the importance of a cloud compliance management system and integrated health data. This approach helps healthcare organizations evaluate critical compliance controls, checks configuration states on a continual basis, and tracks those states in a historical data model across popular HIPAA-eligible cloud provider services. <a href="https://datica.com/events/health-2-0-2019/">Datica executives will also be available in booth #2 to highlight successful cloud-based health IT operations. </a></p>

<p>*For a media briefing please contact Kay Kelly at <a href="mailto:kay.kelly@svmpr.com">kay.kelly@svmpr.com</a>. *</p>

<h2 id="where">Where</h2>

<p>The Santa Clara Convention Center, 5001 Great America Parkway, Santa Clara, CA 95054. <a href="https://datica.com/events/health-2-0-2019/">Booth #2.</a></p>

<h2 id="when">When</h2>

<p>September 16-18, 2019. Dave Levin is speaking at 1:40 pm PST on Tuesday, September 17. For the full conference schedule, <a href="https://www.h2fallcon.com/santa-clara/2019/schedule">please click here.</a></p>

<h3 id="about-health-20">About Health 2.0</h3>

<p><a href="http://health2con.com/">Health 2.0</a> is the premier showcase and catalyst for the advancement of new health technologies. Through a global series of conferences, thought leadership roundtables, developer competitions, pilot programs, and leading market intelligence, Health 2.0 drives the innovation and collaboration necessary to transform health and healthcare.</p>

<h2 id="about-datica">About Datica</h2>

<p><a href="https://datica.com">Datica</a> evolved in 2019 when Datica Health, Inc. merged with <a href="https://datica.com/about">Sansoro Health, Inc.</a> The company now provides the most complete, cloud-based platform available to accelerate healthcare’s transformation to a data-driven future. It achieves this by mitigating the complexity and risk of integrating and using health data in the cloud.</p>

<p>Leveraging patient data is essential to deliver effective digital health solutions that improve outcomes and reduce costs. However, healthcare regulations create a number of integration and compliance issues. To solve these challenges, Datica simplifies and speeds the development process for those that need end-to-end security and scalability to integrate health data from any source into the cloud. For more information, visit <a href="https://datica.com">https://datica.com</a>.</p>

<hr />

<p>__Media Contact: __</p>

<p>Kay Kelly
SVM Public Relations 
Kay.kelly@svmpr.com
401.490.9700</p>
]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Sansoro Health and Datica Announce Merger</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/press/sansoro-health-datica-announce-merger"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/press/sansoro-health-datica-announce-merger</id>
    <published>2019-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Laleh Hassibi</name>
    </author>
    <summary>Combined Product Suite Enables Innovators to Build Secure, Compliant, Integrated Applications for Healthcare</summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<script src="https://fast.wistia.com/embed/medias/ezc2zbafj2.jsonp" async=""></script>
<script src="https://fast.wistia.com/assets/external/E-v1.js" async=""></script>
<div class="wistia_responsive_padding" style="padding:56.25% 0 0 0;position:relative;"><div class="wistia_responsive_wrapper" style="height:100%;left:0;position:absolute;top:0;width:100%;"><div class="wistia_embed wistia_async_ezc2zbafj2 videoFoam=true" style="height:100%;position:relative;width:100%"><div class="wistia_swatch" style="height:100%;left:0;opacity:0;overflow:hidden;position:absolute;top:0;transition:opacity 200ms;width:100%;"><img src="https://fast.wistia.com/embed/medias/ezc2zbafj2/swatch" style="filter:blur(5px);height:100%;object-fit:contain;width:100%;" alt="" onload="this.parentNode.style.opacity=1;" /></div></div></div></div>

<blockquote>
  <p>There are staggering hurdles to bringing advanced digital health solutions to market. We know the complexity of health data exchange and compliance, and our products streamline development and management of cloud-based applications. Our combined company offers a complete, scalable platform to meet these challenges and enable data-driven healthcare in the cloud.”</p>
</blockquote>

<div class="media-object card-person group font-serif"> <div class="media-object-section media-object--avatar"><img src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/1Ef1SLIo0gMVSM9TYTzxzX/02c78fda0895fbc7dafcb4b48d544cad/Leadership-Jeremy.jpg?f=face&amp;fit=thumb&amp;w=64&amp;h=64&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=30" data-src="//images.ctfassets.net/189dvqdsjh46/1Ef1SLIo0gMVSM9TYTzxzX/02c78fda0895fbc7dafcb4b48d544cad/Leadership-Jeremy.jpg?f=face&amp;fit=thumb&amp;w=128&amp;h=128&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=60" class="lozad avatar avatar--large circle" alt="Jeremy Pierotti" /></div> <div class="media-object-section media-object--info main-section align-self-middle"> <div class="person-name"> <a href="/about/jeremy-pierotti/" title="Learn more about Jeremy Pierotti"> Jeremy Pierotti </a></div> <p class="person-title nomargin">Co-founder and CEO</p></div></div>

<p>Minneapolis, MN – June 26, 2019 – <a href="https://www.sansorohealth.com/">Sansoro Health, Inc.</a> and <a href="https://datica.com">Datica Health, LLC</a> announced today they have merged, offering a self-service platform for securing cloud-based applications and integrating patient data from multiple sources. The combined entity retains the Datica name and is headquartered in Minneapolis, MN. <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeremyedespierotti">Jeremy E. Pierotti</a>, previous CEO and co-founder of Sansoro Health, will assume the role of CEO. <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/travisjgood">Travis Good, MD</a>, previous Datica CEO and co-founder, will serve as Chief Technology Officer (CTO).</p>

<p>Healthcare is rapidly migrating to the cloud. Healthcare cloud spend will grow from $24 billion this year to $55 billion by 2025 (<a href="https://marketersmedia.com/healthcare-cloud-computing-market-projected-to-register-15-cagr-to-2025/508770">Market Study Report</a>), and 84% of companies use multiple clouds (<a href="https://www.digitalcommerce360.com/2019/04/01/why-healthcare-data-managers-need-to-have-their-head-in-cloud-computing/">RightScale</a>). Using patient data, however, frequently blocks cloud application development because of data integration and compliance requirements.</p>

<p>“There are staggering hurdles to bringing advanced digital health solutions to market,” said Jeremy E. Pierotti, CEO. “We know the complexity of health data exchange and compliance, and our products streamline development and management of cloud-based applications. Our combined company offers a complete, scalable platform to meet these challenges and enable data-driven healthcare in the cloud.”</p>

<p>Travis Good, MD, CTO adds, “We give our customers a reliable partner for developing solutions that make use of patient data in the cloud. With our platform, previously cumbersome development processes become frictionless, resulting in enhanced, secure solutions at lower cost and with greater speed to market.”</p>

<p>The combined company is solving these problems today for an impressive list of customers; including Johnson &amp; Johnson, VigiLanz, Vineti, and more.</p>

<p>“We’ve had great success partnering with both Sansoro Health and Datica for data integration with our platforms,” said Jean-Claude Saghbini, CTO of Wolters Kluwer Health. “Datica’s vision of bringing data together to support digital healthcare in a manner that is compliant with the security requirements of the industry aligns with the future of health IT. This has the opportunity to unlock tremendous innovation.”</p>

<p>“There is an obvious need for SaaS products that allow innovators to develop compliant, cloud-based digital health solutions,” added Yumin Choi, Partner at Bain Capital Ventures. “Healthcare’s growing adoption of the cloud is inevitable, and that means increased use of patient data. We are thrilled to support the growth of Datica’s trusted solutions that solve the complexities of interoperability and compliance.”</p>

<p>The new Board of Directors includes individuals from the previous Sansoro Health and Datica boards. These individuals are Yumin Choi, Partner at Bain Capital Ventures; Keith J. Figlioli, General Partner at LRVHealth; Brian Hopcraft, Managing Director at Lewis and Clark Ventures; Omar Hussain, former CEO of Imprivata; Micky Tripathi, CEO of the Massachusetts eHealth Collaborative; Travis Good, MD; and Jeremy E. Pierotti. The terms of the deal were not released.</p>

<h3 id="about-datica">About Datica</h3>

<p><a href="https://datica.com">Datica</a> evolved in 2019 when Datica Health, Inc. merged with <a href="https://www.sansorohealth.com/">Sansoro Health, Inc.</a> The company now provides the most complete, cloud-based platform available to accelerate healthcare’s transformation to a data-driven future. It achieves this by mitigating the complexity and risk of integrating and using health data in the cloud.</p>

<p>Leveraging patient data and context has become essential to deliver effective digital health solutions that improve outcomes and reduce costs. However, healthcare regulations create a number of integration and compliance issues. To solve these challenges, Datica simplifies and speeds the development process for those that need end-to-end security and scalability to integrate health data from any source into the cloud. For more information, visit <a href="https://datica.com/">https://datica.com</a>.</p>
]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Datica to Speak at HITRUST 2019 Annual Conference</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/press/datica-speaks-at-hitrust-2019"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/press/datica-speaks-at-hitrust-2019</id>
    <published>2019-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Laleh Hassibi</name>
    </author>
    <summary>Travis Good MD to participate in panel discussion about HITRUST and NIST Assurance</summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Datica, the leading provider of cloud compliance tools for digital health applications, <a href="https://www.prweb.com/releases/datica_to_speak_on_nist_panel_at_hitrust_2019_annual_conference/prweb16259942.htm">today announced</a> participation in a panel discussion at the <a href="https://web.cvent.com/event/02834e3f-f30c-4138-8726-f310ccef995f/summary">HITRUST 2019 annual conference</a>, May 21-23 in Grapevine, TX. The annual conference, which attracts professionals in privacy, security, and compliance, is focused on information risk management in the healthcare industry.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>We are excited to continue our active participation with the HITRUST Alliance by speaking at the 2019 conference. Datica has always taken a lead role in understanding not just compliance, but the value of HITRUST to assure information security and compliance, which is a crucial step for digital health businesses to achieve market value. - Travis Good, MD</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Travis Good MD, Co-Founder, CEO, and chief privacy officer of Datica, will speak on Wednesday, May 22nd at 2:00 pm during a panel discussion titled, “Leveraging HITRUST Programs for NIST Assurance.” Joined by industry leaders from Mayo Clinic, Humana, and the U.S. Department of Treasury’s Office of the Comptroller of the Currency (OCC). Good will share how Datica has used third-party assessments and the HITRUST CSF to demonstrate compliance with NIST standards.</p>

<p>This marks the eighth time Datica has participated as a distinguished presenter at an official HITRUST event since becoming one of the first cloud-based organizations to be HITRUST CSF Certified in 2015. During that time, Dr. Good was also <a href="https://datica.com/press-release/travis-good-md-selected-to-the-hitrust-business-associate-council/">named to the HITRUST Business Associates Council in 2016</a>, to which he and the Datica team advise on compliance topics related to the public cloud.</p>

<h2 id="about-datica">About Datica</h2>

<p>Datica de-risks the cloud for digital health with software that manages all ongoing compliance and security burdens not covered by cloud service providers. Through its suite of products, customers deploy cloud-native applications and integrate with EHRs. Datica is HITRUST CSF Certified, and services all who handle PHI in the cloud, from startups to the Fortune 100. For more information, go to <a href="https://datica.com">Datica.com</a>.</p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Datica to Showcase Portfolio of Products to Manage PHI on Public Clouds at HIMSS 2019</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/press/datica-products-manage-phi-on-public-clouds-at-HIMSS"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/press/datica-products-manage-phi-on-public-clouds-at-HIMSS</id>
    <published>2019-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Laleh Hassibi</name>
    </author>
    <summary>Exhibits and presentations in the Datica, AWS, and Microsoft booths.</summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Seattle, Wash.— Datica, the leading provider of cloud compliance tools for digital health applications, will be demonstrating its comprehensive portfolio of solutions at the upcoming HIMSS Global Conference &amp; Exhibition held at the Orange County Convention and Exhibition Center in Orlando, FL from February 11-15. Datica is exhibiting in booth #621, presenting in the AWS booth #5058, and is a showcased partner in the Microsoft booth #2500. The HIMSS 2019 event brings together more than 45,000 health information and technology professionals, clinicians, executives and market suppliers from around the world.</p>

<h2 id="datica-booth-621">Datica Booth #621</h2>

<p>Datica’s product family includes solutions to manage healthcare compliance on the cloud and EHR integrations. Powerful when used on their own but meant to work together, the entire product suite will be on display at HIMSS in the Datica booth, #621.
Compliant Platform as a Service (CPaaS) - A compliant, hosted platform to build and deploy digital health applications. Offers simplicity and speed to emerging digital health products that need to demonstrate credibility without taking on the burdens of security and compliance. For more information, visit <a href="https://datica.com/cpaas/">datica.com/cpaas</a></p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Compliant Kubernetes Service (CKS)</strong> - A secure, compliant Kubernetes cluster for enterprise scalability of complex digital health applications.  As applications and services scale so does the need for orchestration and developer control along with the ability to take on more of the compliance responsibility. For more information, visit <a href="https://datica.com/cks/">datica.com/cks</a></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Cloud Compliance Management System (CCMS)</strong> - Datica’s newest SaaS product that manages and monitors the precise compliance state of cloud environments. The CCMS helps manage compliance within a customer’s AWS, Azure, or Google cloud account by reporting the exact configuration state of their respective cloud services, and then monitors it daily to ensure those services remain in the proper configuration state. For more information, visit <a href="https://datica.com/ccms/">datica.com/ccms</a></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Compliant Management Integration (CMI)</strong> - Scalable and secure data exchange with any EHR. Customers not only have to worry about PHI compliance on the cloud but also need a secure way to get PHI data in and out of EHRs. CMI has been used to complete 200+ live integrations with all major EHRs at hospitals and clinical facilities. For more information, visit <a href="https://datica.com/cmi/">datica.com/cmi</a></p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>Visitors who complete a tour of Datica’s product family will be eligible to receive a MiiR insulated cup or a copy of Datica’s new book, Complete Cloud Compliance.</p>

<h2 id="aws-booth-5058">AWS Booth #5058</h2>

<p>On Thursday, February 14 at 9:30 am, Kris Gösser, Datica chief marketing officer, will present, “HITRUST Assessments on Amazon Web Services,” in the AWS booth, #5058. As AWS customers gear up for their next audit, this thirty-minute presentation will help prepare them for a HITRUST CSF assessment. Attendees will learn how the Datica Cloud Compliance Management System (CCMS) streamlines continuous compliance management and simplifies reporting of their complex AWS environment.</p>

<h2 id="microsoft-booth-2500">Microsoft Booth #2500</h2>

<p>Datica is also a showcased partner in the Care Coordination section of the Microsoft booth #2500. Mark Olschesky, Datica chief data officer will demonstrate how Datica’s Compliant Managed Integration (CMI) product helps facilitate interoperability between Office 365 platforms and provider EHR systems. Attendees will also be able to inquire about how the Cloud Compliance Management System (CCMS) product helps prepare their Azure cloud environments for a HITRUST assessment.</p>

<h2 id="about-datica">About Datica</h2>

<p>Datica de-risks the cloud for digital health with software that manages all ongoing compliance and security burdens not covered by cloud service providers. Through its suite of products, customers deploy cloud-native applications and integrate with EHRs. Datica is HITRUST CSF Certified, and services all who handle PHI in the cloud, from startups to the Fortune 100. For more information, go to Datica.com.</p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Datica Book Complete Cloud Compliance now available online</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/press/datica-book-complete-cloud-compliance-now-available-online"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/press/datica-book-complete-cloud-compliance-now-available-online</id>
    <published>2018-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Laleh Hassibi</name>
    </author>
    <summary>Breakthrough new book provides a framework and approach to unblocking the cloud on the path to digital transformation.</summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Datica today announced the general availability of its new book titled Complete Cloud Compliance: How regulated companies de-risk the cloud and kickstart transformation. The book, co-authored by CEO Travis Good, MD, and CMO Kris Gösser, shares new insights pioneered by Datica’s expertise at the intersection of healthcare and cloud computing. <a href="https://datica.com/press-release/datica-premiers-new-book-complete-cloud-compliance-at-2018-hitrust/">Dr. Good previously announced the book</a> and detailed key concepts while speaking about the topic of cloud compliance at the 2018 HITRUST Annual Conference.</p>

<h2 id="why-this-book-is-so-important">Why This Book is so Important</h2>

<p>The cloud is a healthcare organization’s biggest risk — if they don’t adopt it. Regulated companies have a hard problem to solve. They run the existential risk of becoming obsolete due to an inability to adopt new technology rapidly enough. The cloud can help but balancing the requirements of compliance is difficult to understand. Complete Cloud Compliance gives the playbook for regulated companies to adopt the cloud with confidence.</p>

<p>The Complete Cloud Compliance book was written for those making healthcare better by enabling the industry’s triple aim — lower costs, better outcomes, better experience. Entrepreneurs just starting out and those who are part of larger organizations competing in the emerging new world order of data-driven healthcare will equally benefit from the ideas and frameworks presented in the book.</p>

<p>The biggest challenge for healthcare workloads on the cloud comes down to confusion among engineers and compliance officers. Most engineers don’t yet understand how compliance works and the path forward to attaining compliance. The engineering teams assume their technology is compliant until, to their detriment, risk assessments and audits confirm they are far off the mark.  At the same time, most compliance officers aren’t technical enough to keep pace with the rapid changes of the cloud, so are reluctant to include cloud services in their programs. This divide results in stagnation of digital health advancements.</p>

<p><em>The book is written to bridge that divide.</em></p>

<p>Engineers learn the fundamentals of compliance to become relative experts by the end of the one hundred and twelve pages. Compliance owners are taught the basics of the cloud (and post-cloud world) to confidently enact an internal compliance program that empowers the cloud.</p>

<p>“Given the prevalence of cloud services today and the many and varied ways in which they’re provided, healthcare organizations need to have a very good understanding of how sensitive health information is safeguarded in the cloud,” said Dr. Bryan Cline, vice president of standards analysis, HITRUST. “This includes who is responsible for specific security and privacy controls, whether it’s the healthcare organization, service provider or both. ‘Complete Cloud Compliance’ can greatly facilitate that understanding.”</p>

<h2 id="now-available-online-at-amazon-barnes--noble-and-blurb">Now Available online at Amazon, Barnes &amp; Noble, and Blurb</h2>

<p>The Complete Cloud Compliance book is now available for general purchase from three online retailers. Readers have their choice of purchasing a softcover version at <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Complete-Cloud-Compliance-Risk-Transformation/dp/1364016451/">Amazon</a> or <a href="https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/complete-cloud-compliance-travis-good-md/1129967731">Barnes and Noble</a>, or a hardcover version at <a href="http://www.blurb.com/b/9029120-complete-cloud-compliance-how-regulated-industries">Blurb</a>. The book is being sold at-cost in the hopes of having it shared broadly so the most people possible have access to its ideas. This aligns with Datica’s central tenets of transparency and a sincere desire to advance healthcare.</p>

<h2 id="about-datica">About Datica</h2>

<p>Datica de-risks the cloud for digital health with software that manages all ongoing compliance and security burdens not covered by cloud service providers. Through its suite of products, customers deploy cloud-native applications and integrate with EHRs. Datica is HITRUST CSF Certified, and services all who handle PHI in the cloud, from startups to the Fortune 100. For more information, go to Datica.com.</p>
]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Datica to Speak on Managing Risk on the Cloud at Pacific Northwest Enterprise Risk Forum </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/press/datica-to-speak-on-managing-risk-on-the-cloud-at-pacific-northwest"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/press/datica-to-speak-on-managing-risk-on-the-cloud-at-pacific-northwest</id>
    <published>2018-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Laleh Hassibi</name>
    </author>
    <summary>Panel discussion to feature four prominent healthcare industry leaders who share ideas on managing risk on the cloud to accelerate innovation.</summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[
<p>Seattle, WA - Datica, the leading industry cloud for digital health, today announced a panel event at the <a href="http://www.enterpriseriskforum.org/">Pacific Northwest Enterprise Risk Forum</a> in Seattle, WA. The one-day summit, tailored to the needs of audit, finance, and risk professionals will be held November 8, 2018, at the Grand Hyatt. Travis Good, CEO of Datica, will join a panel titled “Managing Risk on the Cloud as a Way to Accelerate Organizational Innovation” from 2:45 pm to 3:45 pm in the Princess II Ballroom.</p>

<p>Attendees will hear from four distinguished panelists:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Michael Parisi</strong>, VP, Assurance Strategy &amp; Community Development, HITRUST</li>
  <li><strong>Hector Rodriguez</strong>, Worldwide Health Chief Information Security Officer, Microsoft</li>
  <li><strong>Steve Suter</strong>, President &amp; CEO, Healthcare Management Administrators (HMA)</li>
  <li><strong>Travis Good</strong>, Co-founder, CEO, and Chief Privacy Officer, Datica Health, Inc.</li>
</ul>

<p>The cloud is a key accelerator to enterprise innovation and has propelled a future around Big Data, AI, and data-driven decisions. But healthcare has had a challenging time adopting it due to compliance and risk concerns. In this session, experts discuss the business imperatives of cloud adoption, how it can act as an accelerant to innovation and growth, and then dive into how to properly manage risk in a way to facilitate organizational innovation.</p>

<p>The key insight: Develop a dynamic approach to moving to the cloud that fosters innovation and happens to be compliant!</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>We are excited to be a part of the Enterprise Risk Forum and to bring this dynamic session to the summit. Since the company’s founding five years ago, we’ve witnessed first-hand the industry’s hopes and frustrations in adopting the cloud due to compliance and risk concerns,” said Travis Good, MD, Datica CEO. “This panel provides the opportunity to create a dynamic open forum discussion that will help aid the healthcare industry’s cloud migration.”</p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="about-datica">About Datica</h2>

<p>Datica de-risks the cloud for digital health with software that manages all ongoing compliance and security burdens not covered by cloud service providers. Through its suite of products, customers deploy cloud-native applications and integrate with EHRs. Datica is HITRUST CSF Certified, and services all who handle PHI in the cloud, from startups to the Fortune 100. For more information, go to Datica.com.</p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Datica Announces First-Ever Complete Cloud Compliance Tool for Developers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/press/first-ever-complete-cloud-compliance-tool-for-developers"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/press/first-ever-complete-cloud-compliance-tool-for-developers</id>
    <published>2018-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Laleh Hassibi</name>
    </author>
    <summary>The Datica Cloud Compliance Management System solves the problem of continuous compliance and security in a cloud-native world.</summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[
<p>Seattle, WA — Datica, the leading industry cloud for digital health, today announced its fourth product, the Cloud Compliance Management System (CCMS). The new product completes Datica’s suite of offerings focused on the two most difficult technology problems for digital health: cloud compliance and health data interoperability.</p>

<p>The dynamic nature of the cloud has greatly outpaced existing compliance tools available to developers. The modern cloud is no longer simply someone else’s computer but is now a constellation of managed services delivered as software that sits on top of the leading cloud service providers, like AWS, Microsoft Azure, and Google Cloud.</p>

<h2 id="api-driven-continuous-compliance">API-Driven Continuous Compliance</h2>

<p>Current compliance tools available to developers focus on monitoring at the level of the cloud account, including monitoring cloud user-level access and the host (operating system) level. The problem is most developers now rely on managed services, deploying technologies such as AWS Relational Database Service (RDS) or Azure Cosmos DB versus setting up their own databases on virtual machines, for example. Compliance in this new world of cloud managed services is opaque. Cloud account and host-level monitoring are inadequate to reduce organizational risk and ensure compliance.</p>

<p>Datica CCMS fixes that. It empowers developers with the flexibility to use the cloud services of their choice while remaining in compliance. It uses a first-of-its-kind approach to collecting configuration details via APIs from available cloud services, then reports the real-time compliance state back to end-users. The checked configurations are to the exact control specifications of HITRUST CSF v9.1, meaning the configuration states of available services are in compliance with HIPAA, GDPR, and GxP. CCMS users can leverage reports to attest compliance of a given cloud service during an audit or assessment. The totality of cloud compliance coverage is a unique benefit only available from Datica because other monitoring tools only watch access management via security groups or are focused on specific security concepts, like if encryption is turned on. No offering works backward from compliance controls and monitors the configuration states of managed services against the compliance control specification.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Compliance monitoring tools have not kept pace with the breakneck speed of the cloud, creating roadblocks for developers and new liabilities for enterprises. The Datica CCMS is a culmination of our experience with thousands of compliant cloud deployments and working closely with HITRUST as a founding member of their Business Associate Council. - Travis Good MD, CoFounder, CEO, and Chief Privacy Officer</p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="transparent-compliant-cloud-configurations">Transparent Compliant Cloud Configurations</h2>

<p>To coincide with the product announcement, available today are public configurations for three of the most popular cloud managed database services: <a href="https://datica.com/academy/azure-cosmos-db-guide-how-to-configure-cosmos-db-to-comply-with-hipaa-and-hitrust/">Azure Cosmos DB</a>, <a href="https://datica.com/academy/aws-rds-guide-how-to-configure-rds-to-comply-with-hipaa-and-hitrust/">Amazon RDS</a>, and <a href="https://datica.com/academy/google-cloud-sql-guide-how-to-configure-gcp-cloud-sql-to-comply-with-hipaa/">Google Cloud SQL</a>. The Datica Academy now includes step-by-step guides that explain how to configure these services to align with the HITRUST CSF. Every service the CCMS supports in the future will be publicly documented for complete transparency. The reason is straightforward: Healthcare moves at the speed of trust and customers must be able to trust-but-verify that the CCMS is monitoring configurations to the exact specifications of HITRUST. The gesture also extends Datica’s commitment to transparency, a central tenet that has guided decision making since its internal compliance policies were open sourced in 2015.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>We don’t believe in lock-in. Never have, never will. Datica’s objective is to remove the burden of compliance for developers which starts with education. We’re happy to explain how to make every cloud service HITRUST CSF Certified, which will only help healthcare in the long run. Meanwhile, the Datica CCMS will remove the day-to-day burden of continuously monitoring compliance states of cloud services that change frequently while the historical and contextual reporting of those services will save tremendous amounts of time during audits. - Ryan Rich, Chief Product Officer</p>
</blockquote>

<p>While the <a href="https://datica.com/blog/configuring-popular-managed-database-services-for-hitrust-csf/">three cloud service configurations</a> are open and available today, the <a href="https://datica.com/blog/announcing-future-cloud-compliance-management-system/">Datica CCMS</a> will be generally available for purchase starting early 2019, with limited availability for customers starting this fall. Until then, many more configurations will be publicly published. Those interested in being notified of new configuration available can sign up at <a href="https://datica.com/cloud-compliance-management-system/">datica.com/ccms</a>.</p>

<h2 id="about-datica">About Datica</h2>

<p>Datica de-risks the cloud for digital health with software that manages all ongoing compliance and security burdens not covered by cloud service providers. Through its suite of products, customers deploy cloud-native applications and integrate with EHRs. Datica is HITRUST CSF Certified, and services all who handle PHI in the cloud, from startups to the Fortune 100. For more information, go to <a href="https://datica.com/">Datica.com</a>.</p>
]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Datica Premiers New Book Complete Cloud Compliance at 2018 HITRUST Annual Conference</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/press/datica-premiers-new-book-complete-cloud-compliance-at-2018-hitrust"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/press/datica-premiers-new-book-complete-cloud-compliance-at-2018-hitrust</id>
    <published>2018-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Laleh Hassibi</name>
    </author>
    <summary>Breakthrough new book navigates the way through managed services and microservice-based architectures so today’s healthcare companies can achieve total compliance on the cloud.</summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[
<p>Seattle, WA — Datica today announced the release of its new book titled <em>Complete Cloud Compliance: How regulated companies de-risk the cloud and kickstart transformation</em>. The book, co-authored by CEO Travis Good, MD, and CMO Kris Gosser, shares new insights pioneered by Datica’s expertise at the intersection of healthcare and cloud computing. Dr. Good announced the book and detailed key concepts while speaking about the topic of cloud compliance at the 2018 HITRUST Annual Conference held in Grapevine, TX.</p>

<h2 id="dynamic-compliance-for-a-dynamic-cloud">Dynamic compliance for a dynamic cloud</h2>

<p>Central to the book’s premise is that the cloud is no longer other people’s computers. Instead, we are in a post-cloud era full of cloud-native microservices and managed services, which creates new challenges for both technology teams and compliance departments. In order to avoid obsolescences, all companies must keep pace with the rapid changes on the cloud; for companies in regulated industries, compliance makes this more challenging. As cloud services are delivered in more discrete, abstracted layers to improve developer experience (a good thing), more control is being taken away from the user thus making compliance attestation harder (a bad thing). The improved developer experience allows for faster development on the cloud (also a good thing), but greater developer freedom circumvents traditional security and compliance procedures (also a bad thing).</p>

<p><a href="https://www.completecloudcompliance.com">Complete Cloud Compliance</a> details the problem facing developers and organizations, and gives a path forward in the form of a novel compliance management program geared towards adapting to the dynamic nature of the cloud.</p>

<p>After a brief introduction stating the business need for a new approach to compliance management, the book details the history of compliance by breaking down the complex details into digestible parts. The goal is to educate technologists on compliance fundamentals. The next chapter takes the same approach but with cloud technology, breaking down complicated technical concepts in a way to help compliance officers understand where the cloud is headed. From there, the key concept of “complete cloud compliance” is detailed followed by best practice recommendations.</p>

<p>“The cloud is fundamentally changing how technology is developed and scaled, making it cheaper and faster for every organization to innovate and transform itself with digital technology,” said Dr. Good. “But, this ease of use, especially for developers, has opened up an entirely new set of challenges to ensure the security and compliance of digital assets. We’re excited to share the lessons we’ve learned and applied over our five years of managing compliant workloads on the cloud for the most risk-averse industry in the world, healthcare.”</p>

<h2 id="conference-goers-can-receive-a-free-preview-copy">Conference goers can receive a free preview copy</h2>

<p>The <em>Complete Cloud Compliance</em> book is due in Fall 2018, and will be available for general purchase online. In the meantime, free copies will be available at the 2018 HITRUST Annual Conference held Sept. 11-13, Microsoft Ignite Conference held Sept. 24-28, and AWS re:Invent conference held Nov. 26-30. Stop by the Datica booth or schedule a meeting to receive a copy. Visit <a href="https://www.completecloudcompliance.com/">completecloudcompliance.com</a> for more details.</p>

<h2 id="about-datica">About Datica</h2>

<p>Datica de-risks the cloud for digital health with software that manages all ongoing compliance and security burdens not covered by cloud service providers. Through its suite of products, customers deploy cloud-native applications and integrate with EHRs. Datica is HITRUST CSF Certified, and services all who handle PHI in the cloud, from startups to the Fortune 100. For more information, go to Datica.com.</p>
]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Datica Joins the Cloud Native Computing Foundation</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/press/datica-joins-the-cloud-native-computing-foundation"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/press/datica-joins-the-cloud-native-computing-foundation</id>
    <published>2018-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Laleh Hassibi</name>
    </author>
    <summary>Datica announced today that they have joined the Cloud Native Computing Foundation (CNCF) as a silver member. Datica has always been a huge proponent of the open source community, with more than 500 stars on the company’s open source policies, and joining the CNCF demonstrates...</summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[
<p>Madison, WI, and Seattle, WA</p>

<p>Datica™ announced today that they have joined the Cloud Native Computing Foundation (CNCF) as a silver member. Datica has always been a huge proponent of the open source community, with more than 500 stars on the company’s open source policies, and joining the CNCF demonstrates its commitment to contributing to the Kubernetes® ecosystem.</p>

<p>Datica recently <a href="https://datica.com/press-release/datica-launches-kubernetes-enabled-platform/">migrated it’s security and compliance platform to Kubernetes</a>, a CNCF project, to offer a complete cloud-native solution for regulated industries such as healthcare.  Datica enables organizations to manage the compliant state of their entire enterprises in one actionable view — across multiple clouds and within multiple industries.  In addition to being cross-cloud compatible and open source, the CNCF Kubernetes community and project have grown at a tremendous pace. In fact, the <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/the-cloud-native-computing-foundation-reaches-236-members-including-54-end-users-300671019.html">CNCF announced Datica as one of it’s 19 newest members</a> this week, bringing the membership level to 236 companies. What really makes Kubernetes a viable option is not the core project itself, but the community of tools and add-ons that surround it.</p>

<p>“The intent of open source is to provide community-vetted projects for the benefit of others, who then freely build upon them to solve other complex and pressing problems,” explains Travis Good, MD, CEO and chief privacy officer. “Datica is a big believer of the value and spirit of open source and, with our open source policies, has already taken the concept beyond bits and bytes to words and legalese that can often bog down a digital health enterprise hoping to bring swift change to the marketplace.” Good continues, “We’re extending that commitment to the open source community by joining the CNCF to collaborate with other Kubernetes developers who are trying to build secure and compliant products.”</p>

<p>“We’re thrilled to have Datica as one of our newest silver members,” says Dan Kohn, executive director of the <a href="http://www.cncf.io/">CNCF</a>. “Other members of the cloud native ecosystem who are also developing products for highly-regulated industries such as healthcare will benefit from resources and contributions from Datica.”</p>

<h3 id="about-datica">About Datica</h3>

<p>Datica helps highly regulated industries manage sensitive information in the cloud. The Datica Platform complies with HIPAA, HITRUST, GDPR, GxP and more by providing a secure, compliant Kubernetes managed service that integrates with additional cloud services. Datica’s customers include mid-to-late stage startups to Fortune 100 companies. For more information, visit <a href="https://datica.com">Datica.com</a>.</p>
]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Datica Celebrates 5th Anniversary as a Compliance and Security Leader for the Cloud</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/press/datica-celebrates-5th-anniversary-as-a-cloud-compliance-and-security-leader"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/press/datica-celebrates-5th-anniversary-as-a-cloud-compliance-and-security-leader</id>
    <published>2018-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Datica Editorial Team</name>
    </author>
    <summary>Company recalls milestones, talks of international expansion, and looks to future innovations.</summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>MADISON, WISC. AND SEATTLE (PRWEB) MAY 31, 2018</p>

<p><a href="https://datica.com" title="Datica">Datica</a>™ announced today that this month marks the company’s 5th anniversary since carving out a niche market in 2013 when it first addressed compliance and security in the cloud. Today, Datica’s Platform for healthcare continues its evolution in one of the most highly regulated industries in the U.S. and has become an enabler for cloud-based strategies.</p>

<p>Last year, the company launched its first international pod and will be adding more in 2018. Getting in front of the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) has been a driving force for Datica over the past year and a half. In 2017, the company began a GDPR audit process of its Platform, a move that soon makes the Platform compliant with the regulations of HIPAA, HITRUST, GDPR and GxP.</p>

<p>Other milestones Datica (originally founded under the name Catalyze) has had since its May 2013 launch include:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Raised $12.5 Million in funding since inception
First to make the <a href="https://datica.com/platform/" title="Kubernetes technology">Kubernetes technology</a> for deploying containerized workloads HITRUST CSF Certified</li>
  <li>Selected as a premier healthcare speaker at AWS re:Invent 2017, and featured in the main keynote at the 2018 Microsoft Build conference</li>
  <li>Pioneered the <a href="https://datica.com/dhsf/" title="Digital Health Success Framework">Digital Health Success Framework</a>, leading to industry-wide acclaim, including presenting at Health 2.0 and SXSW</li>
  <li>Embraced a virtual workforce in 2013, tapping top healthcare technology talent across the nation</li>
</ul>

<p>“Since 2013, we’ve put an emphasis on supporting customers by controlling growth, and in the first half of 2018 we’ve continued that company focus by spending all available resources on engineering and servicing customers, “ said Travis Good, MD, CEO and chief privacy officer. “When I think back to the start of the company, it’s humbling to see how our customer base has expanded from early-stage startups, then to mature healthcare vendors, and finally to the Fortune 500 mix of enterprise customers. It’s the compliance and security aspects that bring these customers to Datica; it’s core to our mission, so we ensure the Platform remains first and foremost secure.”</p>

<p>As Datica celebrates the past five years, it’s also a time to look to the future. Though healthcare has, up until now, been a core focus of the company, Datica’s newly introduced Cloud Compliance Management System will open a host of new opportunities for organizations to manage the compliant state of their entire enterprises in one actionable view — across multiple clouds and within multiple industries. “As we expand our partnerships with Microsoft Azure and AWS, and on to Google Cloud, Datica will explore offering end-to-end compliance beyond healthcare,” said Good.</p>
]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Datica Reveals Findings from Hospital CIO Cloud Perspectives Survey</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/press/datica-reveals-findings-from-hospital-cio-cloud-perspectives-survey"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/press/datica-reveals-findings-from-hospital-cio-cloud-perspectives-survey</id>
    <published>2018-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Datica Health, Inc.</name>
    </author>
    <summary>Chief Information Officers from healthcare organizations look to the cloud, but with wary eyes around security and compliance.</summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><a href="https://datica.com" title="Datica">Datica</a>™ today released its 2018 CIO Cloud Perspective Survey titled “Healthcare Cloud Take-off: Waiting for the Fog to Clear.” The survey report has uncovered why chief information officers mark cloud migration as a pressing priority but also includes new details on why shifts to the cloud are happening slowly. From the survey, 17.7 percent of the respondents say they work with healthcare organizations that have more than 50 percent of the existing software infrastructure remotely hosted or in the cloud. Nearly 15 percent of those who took the survey say 25-50 percent of their infrastructure is cloud-based.</p>

<p>Healthcare systems that have taken an on-ramp to the cloud are still in the minority, but the respondents of this survey who have made the cloud shift a reality are learning what works and what doesn’t. In 2015, and prior to cloud hosting becoming a mainstream topic in the medical industry, a paper from the <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4434058/" title="Journal of Healthcare Informatics">Journal of Healthcare Informatics Research</a> concluded that hospitals of all sizes would use cloud-based Healthcare Software-as-a-Service (SaaS) Platforms to deliver healthcare information services with low cost, high clinical value, and high usability. Now, three years later, roughly 20 percent of hospitals have adopted those cloud-based infrastructures.</p>

<p>Compliance, security, and privacy key to cloud adoption</p>

<p>Another finding: <a href="https://datica.com/platform/compliance/" title="Compliance">Compliance</a>, security, and privacy are the three primary concerns for those hospital CIOs who have considered implementing digital health technology from outside vendors. The survey questions drilled down deeper to uncover the following:</p>

<ul>
  <li>More than half of the respondents have concerns (52.57%)</li>
  <li>Slightly less than half say they are comfortable assessing compliance of vendors (44%)</li>
  <li>A mere 3.43 percent stated no concern for cloud-hosted applications because they weren’t allowed</li>
</ul>

<p>“These survey findings mirror what we’ve been hearing in high-level conversations at Datica,” said Travis Good, MD, CEO and Chief Privacy Officer for the company. “Although <a href="https://datica.com/hipaa-compliant-hosting/" title="cloud hosting for healthcare">cloud hosting for healthcare</a> has become mainstream, the understanding of and confidence in the cloud to meet the exacting standards of the highly regulated industry is still a major concern for healthcare systems.”</p>

<p>Even though new tools and changes in the regulatory environment have made cloud a safe option for storing sensitive information, including Protected Health Information (PHI), the survey shows the majority of survey respondents do not have a strategy for moving their data centers to the cloud. Although nearly 60 percent of those who took the survey place cloud hosting in their organizations’ Top 10 priorities, only about 30 percent have a strategy in place.</p>

<p>Download the Datica 2018 Hospital <a href="https://datica.com/innovation/healthcare-cloud-take-off-waiting-for-fog-clear/" title="CIO Survey Report here">CIO Survey Report here</a>.</p>

<p>About Datica’s Hospital CIO Survey 
Conducted around the 2018 Healthcare Information and Management Systems Society (HIMSS) annual conference in Las Vegas, and with the College of Healthcare Information Management Executives (CHIME) CIO members, the research sought to provide an in-depth look at the current state of the cloud from the seat of the chief information officer of leading hospital organizations. An executive of Datica outlined the survey in person at the CHIME CIO forum at HIMSS18. Using an online survey, CIO leaders from 175 leading healthcare organizations participated in this research and final results were tabulated in April. Datica segmented survey responses and provided analysis to reveal five key findings for the report.</p>

<p>About Datica 
The Datica Platform is designed for those who store, manage and share protected health information (PHI) in the cloud; it manages all ongoing compliance and security burdens found within the exacting standards of HIPAA, HITRUST, GDPR, and GxP. Customers can license and deploy cloud-native applications on their own cloud account, or tap Datica’s cloud account for compliance, security and electronic health record integration expertise when launching and managing applications. Customers of the Kubernetes-enabled Datica Platform include mid-to-late stage startups to Fortune 100 companies across the healthcare spectrum: solution providers, hospital organizations, pharmaceutical giants and nationwide health insurance payers. For more information, go to Datica.com.</p>
]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Access HealthNet Selects the Datica Platform to Accelerate Interoperability and Security for Medical Reimbursements</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/press/access-healthnet-selects-the-datica-platform-to-accelerate-interoperability"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/press/access-healthnet-selects-the-datica-platform-to-accelerate-interoperability</id>
    <published>2018-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Datica Health, Inc.</name>
    </author>
    <summary>Wisconsin-based companies form a working alliance to streamline healthcare data exchange for hospital and medical billing.</summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[
<p>MILWAUKEE AND MADISON, WIS. (PRWEB) MAY 10, 2018</p>

<p>Madison-based <a href="https://datica.com" title="Datica">Datica™</a> and Milwaukee tech startup <a href="https://accesshealthnet.com/" title="Access HealthNet">Access HealthNet</a> (AHN) today announced a strategic partnership to deliver EMR interoperability and security through AHN’s <a href="https://accesshealthnet.com/the-super-option/" title="healthcare bundling platform">healthcare bundling platform</a>. The companies will collaborate to ensure compliance requirements are met to the standards of HIPAA and HITRUST CSF Certification and streamline operations for AHN’s customers.</p>

<p>Together the two companies will greatly expand their ability to assist providers and employers in streamlining the medical reimbursement process that has plagued modern healthcare and fueled its skyrocketing costs.</p>

<p>Founded in 2014, AHN has become a leader in direct contracting with its cloud-based bundling platform, offering more than 350,000 episodes of care throughout the country at more than 5,000 facility locations to self-insured employers, unions, and Medi-Share programs.</p>

<p>“Partnering with Datica will propel our platform forward exponentially,” said AHN’s Chairman and CEO, Eric Haberichter. “Our vision of being fully interoperable with all major hospital and medical billing systems will become a reality much more rapidly with this partnership.”</p>

<p>Datica has been serving an array of high-profile medical facilities across the country and has become the Midwest’s premier HITRUST CSF Certified, <a href="https://accesshealthnet.com/the-super-option/" title="HIPAA compliant digital health platform">HIPAA compliant digital health platform</a>. Founded in 2013, Datica now powers the next era of healthcare technology with its interoperable Kubernetes-enabled cloud infrastructure.</p>

<p>“We recognize the health tech surge happening in both Madison and Milwaukee today. That’s only one reason why Datica is delighted to partner with Access HealthNet in providing the compliance and security layers that hospital and medical systems seek,” said Datica CEO and Chief Privacy Officer Travis Good, MD. “With its bundled payments solution, Access HealthNet is providing a much-needed cost transparency for healthcare; seeing these innovations arise from two Wisconsin cities is a boasting point for the state of Wisconsin.”</p>

<p>About Datica 
The Datica Platform is designed for those who store, manage and share protected health information (PHI) in the cloud and manages all ongoing compliance and security burdens found within the exacting standards of HIPAA, HITRUST, GDPR, and GxP. Customers can license and deploy cloud-native applications on their own cloud account, or tap Datica’s cloud account to receive compliance, security and electronic health record (EHR) integration expertise to launch and manage applications. Datica’s Kubernetes-enabled platform customers include mid-to-late stage startups to Fortune 100 companies across the healthcare spectrum: solution providers, hospital organizations, pharmaceutical giants and nationwide health insurance payers. For more information, go to Datica.com.</p>

<p>About Access HealthNet 
Access HealthNet (AHN) increases access and affordability in healthcare through an e-commerce healthcare marketplace called The Super Option that connects value-based providers offering flat-rates and bundles to self-funded employers. AHN’s proprietary platform has several iterations to serve healthcare’s vast stakeholders, including a direct-to-consumer offering called The Super Option Direct, and a workers’ compensation solution called WC Bundled Payments. To learn more, visit accesshealthnet.com.</p>
]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Datica’s HITRUST CSF Certified, GDPR and HIPAA Compliant Platform Featured at Microsoft Build 2018</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/press/datica's-hitrust-csf-certified-gdpr-and-hipaa-compliant-platform-featured"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/press/datica's-hitrust-csf-certified-gdpr-and-hipaa-compliant-platform-featured</id>
    <published>2018-05-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-05-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Datica Health, Inc.</name>
    </author>
    <summary>The platform, created by Datica™ and built for healthcare developers, had its cloud-based healthcare solution showcased, and general availability on Microsoft Azure was announced.</summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>SEATTLE AND MADISON, WIS. (PRWEB) MAY 08, 2018</p>

<p>Datica, a Microsoft solution provider, was featured at this year’s <a href="https://developer.microsoft.com/en-us/events/build/content" title="Microsoft Build 2018 Developer Conference">Microsoft Build 2018 Developer Conference</a>, May 7-9. Engineers and executives leading the way in the cloud heard how Datica’s platform, which is HIPAA, HITRUST, GDPR and GxP compliant, works in concert with Microsoft Azure to help break-through real-world workflows within clinical settings. During Build 2018, Datica’s compliant cloud technology was highlighted for its success in connecting Microsoft 365 Business tools with Electronic Health Records (EHRs). The new integration tooling that bridges Microsoft Teams with EHRs will work within the bot framework of Teams. An announcement of the tooling’s general availability in the Azure Marketplace was also made in Seattle during Microsoft Build 2018.</p>

<p>Travis Good, MD, CEO and chief privacy officer of Datica, said “Announcing this new tooling on top of our new Kubernetes-based platform as being generally available for enterprise customers in Microsoft’s ecosystem while simultaneously being featured at Microsoft Build 2018, is a huge honor.”</p>

<p>In the healthcare IT field, Datica’s technology is recognized for its compliance with HIPAA and HITRUST, as well as its security-focused approach. Datica engineers made <a href="https://datica.com/platform/compliance/" title="healthcare compliance">healthcare compliance</a> a non-issue for application developers when they built the HITRUST CSF Certified platform to assume all liabilities in the cloud associated with HIPAA, <a href="https://datica.com/discover/gdpr/" title="GDPR">GDPR</a>, and GxP. The new integration tooling that works to connect Microsoft further with healthcare and yet in a compliant way is good for the healthcare field.</p>

<p>“We are pleased to see Datica build technologies that help solve healthcare’s technology challenges,” said Kristina Behr, General Manager, Office for Healthcare, Microsoft Corp. “By bringing Electronic Health Record data into Microsoft Teams for secure collaboration, Datica is meeting the challenging workflow demands of the healthcare enterprise.”</p>

<p>Following Microsoft Build 2018, customers will also be able to license Datica’s platform, putting it on their own Azure account, or for additional security and compliance oversight, have it managed within Datica’s Cloud on Azure.</p>

<p>About Datica 
The Datica Platform manages all ongoing compliance and security burdens found within the exacting standards of HIPAA, HITRUST, GDPR, and GxP. Customers can license and deploy cloud-native healthcare applications on their own cloud account, or tap Datica’s compliance and security expertise to launch and manage applications on Datica’s cloud account, as well as receive integration guidance for connecting to electronic health records (EHRs). Datica built the HITRUST CSF Certified Platform for those who collect, store, manage and share protected health information (PHI) in the cloud. Datica’s customers range from mid-to-late stage startups to Fortune 100 companies across the healthcare spectrum: solution providers, hospital organizations, pharmaceutical giants and nationwide health insurance payers. For more information, go to Datica.com.</p>
]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Datica Launches Kubernetes-enabled Platform to Extend AWS and Cloud Accounts for Customers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/press/datica-launches-kubernetes-enabled-platform"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/press/datica-launches-kubernetes-enabled-platform</id>
    <published>2018-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Datica Health, Inc.</name>
    </author>
    <summary>The next evolution of the company’s licensed Platform grants compliance coverage for HITRUST, GxP, GDPR, SOC 2 and HIPAA.</summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><a href="https://datica.com" title="Datica">Datica</a>, the leading cloud platform for digital health since 2013, today announced its next-generation platform to manage HIPAA compliance on top of AWS and Microsoft Azure. The evolved version of the Datica Platform extends security and compliance expertise in three critical ways to better serve healthcare organizations:</p>

<ol>
  <li>The <a href="https://datica.com/platform" title="Platform">Platform</a> now uses Kubernetes as its underlying container orchestration, granting customers greater technical flexibility.</li>
  <li>The move will also allow customers to install the Platform on their own AWS or Azure cloud accounts.</li>
  <li>Compliance coverage is extended to include GxP, GDPR, and SOC 2.</li>
</ol>

<p>Kubernetes is now the fundamental technical management layer for the platform. Since 2015, Kubernetes has become the industry standard for container management, lending the best tools for workload deployment on public clouds.</p>

<p>“Making Kubernetes the central workhorse for the next version of the Datica Platform left no debate,” said Travis Good, MD, CEO. “Kubernetes helps healthcare teams adopt modern technology while bridging to existing architectures. Basing the new Datica Platform on Kubernetes will provide stronger support for Windows architectures, better service extensibility, and more self-serve tooling,” Good said.</p>

<p>The move to Kubernetes opens up the ability for customers to deploy a licensed version of the Datica Platform on top of their own AWS or Azure cloud accounts. Previously customers deployed their workloads onto Datica’s hosted cloud. Now, the new Kubernetes-enabled Platform allows customers to gain the same security and compliance assurances, but in their own cloud accounts. There, they can retain maximum flexibility and control.</p>

<p><a href="https://datica.com/platform/compliance" title="Compliance">Compliance</a> postures have also been strengthened. The new platform version extends support beyond HIPAA and HITRUST. To date, Datica has obtained three HITRUST CSF Certifications while its hosted customers have passed more than 1,000 audits and risk assessments while on the platform. The new platform will also be GxP and GDPR compliant, making it a strong option for Life Science technology teams, or healthcare teams who do business in Europe.</p>

<p>Available April 2018, the new Kubernetes-enabled platform offers a license starting at $40,000 per year. Contact Datica at datica.com or visit HIMSS18 booth #5077 to obtain more details for your organization.</p>

<h4 id="about-datica">About Datica</h4>
<p>The Datica Platform manages all ongoing compliance and security burdens not covered by AWS and Microsoft Azure. Through the Platform, customers deploy cloud-native applications and integrate with EHRs. Datica is HITRUST CSF Certified, and services all who handle PHI in the cloud, from startups to the Fortune 100. For more information, go to Datica.com.</p>
]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Datica Welcomes Former HealthGrades Executive as New Chief Technology and Security Officer</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/press/datica-welcomes-christopher-gerg-healthgrades-executive-as-new-cto-and-cso"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/press/datica-welcomes-christopher-gerg-healthgrades-executive-as-new-cto-and-cso</id>
    <published>2018-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marcia Noyes</name>
    </author>
    <summary>Industry veteran Christopher Gerg joins Datica to evolve the security and compliance posture for the cloud.</summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><em>Madison, WI - (February 20, 2018)</em> Datica™, creator of the HIPAA compliant and HITRUST CSF Certified Platform trusted by those who deploy cloud-native applications and integrate with EHRs, today welcomed <a href="/about/christopher-gerg">Christopher Gerg</a> as its Chief Technology and Security Officer. Gerg will lead the engineering and security team to help Datica address the exploding adoption of the cloud by healthcare’s trillion dollar industry.</p>

<p>Cloud is an important paradigm for all industries today, and healthcare has yet to adopt it in numbers seen in other market segments. “The blockers for healthcare are compliance and security. Datica has the best platform to address those industry hurdles,” said Travis Good, MD, CEO of Datica. “We are honored to have Christopher Gerg guide Datica’s Platform toward relieving the many burdens for healthcare’s adoption of the cloud.”</p>

<p>As CTO and CSO, Gerg will leverage his most recent experience as an industry consultant and also his experience gained as Chief Information Security Officer and VP of Infrastructure &amp; Engineering for HealthGrades. Gerg’s deep industry knowledge has been well documented, including his authorship of an important O’Reilly Media book,  “Managing Security with Snort &amp; IDS Tools: Intrusion Detection with Open Source Tools.” Today, the book is still being used as a training tool for its primer on TCP/IP networking and attack methodology.</p>

<p>Even though firmly entrenched in his own consulting company, Gerg said he jumped at the chance to join the Datica team. Knowing that organizations often look for a magic plug-in product for their networks to address security concerns, Gerg understands that secure networks are based on the foundational piece first.  “Tools are just components used to meet foundational needs; if you don’t address the foundation, tools hold zero value,” said Gerg. With Datica’s platform and services, customers can deploy their technology in a reliable security environment, with the side benefit of compliance, as well as having a platform that meets the stringent requirements of the healthcare industry.</p>

<p>“Working with a talented team developing a technology that allows an organization to deliver on their core competency while meeting compliance and regulatory obligations is an exciting prospect,” said Gerg.</p>

<h3 id="about-datica">About Datica</h3>
<p>Datica is the platform for digital health success. We solve the problem of HIPAA compliance in the cloud, and enable secure data exchange between digital health and EHRs. Customers and partners across healthcare trust Datica to ensure the barriers for digital health are removed so innovation can happen faster. For more information please visit <a href="https://datica.com">Datica.com</a>.</p>
]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Datica and Methodist Le Bonheur Healthcare Co-present at AWS re:Invent 2017 about Standardizing Compliance on the Cloud</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/press/datica-methodist-lebonheur-healthcare-copresent-aws-re-invent-2017"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/press/datica-methodist-lebonheur-healthcare-copresent-aws-re-invent-2017</id>
    <published>2017-11-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-11-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Laleh Hassibi</name>
    </author>
    <summary>Healthcare breakout session will provide insight into how hospital adoption of a standard compliance layer quickly led to innovative applications and stronger data integration with Electronic Health Records.</summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Datica, the cloud platform for digital health applications, today announced the selection of Adam Leko, the company’s chief technology officer and David Deas, Methodist Le Bonheur Healthcare’s (MLH) corporate director, innovation &amp; knowledge analytics, for a joint healthcare presentation on how to eliminate <a href="https://datica.com/guide/application-hipaa-compliance/">HIPAA compliance</a> as a barrier to speed-to-market hospital development goals at this year’s AWS re:Invent conference.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>In 2017, Datica has enabled several hospital systems to more effectively reduce capital and operational costs by safely and securely moving to the cloud in a compliant manner. This presentation will show how MLH uses the compliant Datica platform to ensure that the configuration and orchestration of Amazon Web Services (AWS) HIPAA-eligible services meet the controls set by the healthcare’s most stringent accreditation body, HITRUST, with every workload deployment. - Adam Leko, Datica</p>
</blockquote>

<p>While demand for on-premises infrastructure has diminished in healthcare, the adoption of cloud-based solutions has grown exponentially. Cloud computing is proving that it expands accessibility to healthcare data and Datica’s platform is helping those health systems interested in deploying digital health applications in the cloud to meet the rigorous security and <a href="https://datica.com/guide/total-cost-of-ownership-of-cloud-compliance/">regulatory compliance standards</a> of the industry.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>By removing security concerns as a barrier to using cloud-based systems, Datica has opened up a new world of possibilities that we would otherwise have been too cautious to undertake. Leveraging the ease and expandability of the compliant Datica platform running on AWS we have greatly accelerated our Innovation team’s capabilities, which allows us to play out ‘what if’ scenarios without large capital commitments or burdensome ROI proofs. All of this has expanded the number of projects we can tackle and lead to a remarkable transformation in how we approach healthcare innovation. - David Deas, MLH</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The Datica/MLH 60-minute live presentation, How Methodist Le Bonheur Healthcare’s Focus on Standardizing Compliant Ops Led to Breakthrough Apps will take place on Monday, November 27 at the Venetian, Level 2, Venetian F in Las Vegas at 12:15 Pacific Time.</p>

<p>For more information about Datica, visit booth #519 and get more details about AWS re:Invent 2017, at: <a href="https://reinvent.awsevents.com">https://reinvent.awsevents.com</a>.</p>

<h2 id="about-datica">About Datica</h2>

<p>Datica is the platform for digital health success. We solve the problem of HIPAA compliance in the cloud, and enable secure data exchange between digital health and EHRs. Customers and partners across healthcare trust Datica to ensure the barriers for digital health are removed so innovation can happen faster. For more information please visit <a href="https://datica.com">https://datica.com</a>.</p>

<h2 id="about-methodist-le-bonheur-healthcare">About Methodist Le Bonheur Healthcare</h2>

<p>Methodist Le Bonheur Healthcare (MLH) is an integrated healthcare delivery system based in Memphis, Tenn. Founded in 1918 by The United Methodist Church to help meet the growing needs for quality health care in the Mid-South, Methodist has grown from one hospital into a six-hospital system that includes Le Bonheur Children’s Hospital, a national US News and World Report Best Children’s Hospital. MLH also offers a home health agency, ambulatory surgery centers, outpatient facilities, hospice residence and physician practices serving all corners of the Memphis and Mid-South community. Consistent with its innovative approach to leveraging technology to make it easier for patients and providers to interact, MLH was named to the 2017 Health Care’s Most Wired list. For seven consecutive years, Methodist has been named the best hospital in Memphis by U.S. News and World Report Great Place to Work® and Fortune ranked Methodist Le Bonheur Healthcare on its 2017 100 Best Companies to Work For, #11 for 2017 Best Workplaces for Women, #21 for 2016 Best Workplaces for Diversity, and #1 on the 2016 list of Best Workplaces for African Americans. With more than 12,000 associates and 1,650 licensed beds, MLH provides care for over 400,000 Emergency Room visits and more than 60,000 inpatient admissions annually. For more information, <a href="http://www.methodisthealth.org">visit http://www.methodisthealth.org</a>.</p>
]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
